<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Observations upon the Prophecies of Daniel, and the Apocalypse of St. John</title>
                <author>Isaac Newton</author>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Produced by</resp>
                    <name>Greg Alethoup, Robert Shimmin, Keith Edkins, and the Online Distributed Proofreading Team</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2005-10-15">Release date: October 15, 2005</date>
                    <date when="2020-12-12" type="revision">Most recently updated: December 12, 2020</date>
                    <ref target="https://www.pgdp.net">Online Distributed Proofreading Team at https://www.pgdp.net</ref>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Project Gutenberg</publisher>
                <availability>
                    <licence>
                        <p>This ebook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the United States and most other parts of the world at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this ebook or online at www.gutenberg.org.</p>
                        <p>If you are not located in the United States, you will have to check the laws of the country where you are located before using this eBook.</p>
                    </licence>
                    <ref target="http://www.gutenberg.org">Project Gutenberg License online at www.gutenberg.org</ref>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblStruct>
                    <monogr>
                        <title type="main"> OBSERVATIONS UPON THE PROPHECIES OF _DANIEL_, AND THE APOCALYPSE OF St. _JOHN_</title>
                        <edition>In Two PARTS.</edition>
                        <author>Sir _ISAAC NEWTON_</author>
                        <imprint>
                            <publisher>
                                <p>
                                    <placeName>
                                        <hi rend="italic">LONDON</hi>,
                                    </placeName>
                                Printed by J. DARBY and T. BROWNE in <hi rend="italic">Bartholomew-Close</hi>.
                                </p>
                                <p>And Sold by J. ROBERTS in <hi rend="italic">Warwick-lane</hi>, J. TONSON in the
                                    <hi rend="italic">Strand</hi>, W. INNYS and R. MANBY at the West End of St.
                                    <hi rend="italic">Paul's Church-Yard</hi>, J. OSBORN and T. LONGMAN in <hi rend="italic">Pater-Noster-Row</hi>,
                                J. NOON near <hi rend="italic">Mercers Chapel</hi> in <hi rend="italic">Cheapside</hi>,
                                T. HATCHETT at the <hi rend="italic">Royal Exchange</hi>, S. HARDING in St.
                                    <hi rend="italic">Martin's lane</hi>, J. STAGG in <hi rend="italic">Westminster-Hall</hi>, J. PARKER in
                                    <hi rend="italic">Pall-mall</hi>, and J. BRINDLEY in <hi rend="italic">New Bond-Street</hi>.
                                </p>
                            </publisher>

                            <date when="1733">M.DCC.XXXIII</date>
                        </imprint>
                    </monogr>
                    <div type="dedication">
                        <p>To the Right Honourable</p>
                        <p>
                            <hi rend="italic">P E T E R</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Lord <hi rend="italic">K I N G</hi>,
                        </p>
                        <p>Baron of <hi rend="italic">Ockham</hi>, Lord High Chancellor of <hi rend="italic">Great-Britain</hi>.
                        </p>
                        <p>My Lord,</p>
                        <p>I shall make no Apology for addressing the following Sheets to Your
                    Lordship, who lived in a long Intercourse of Friendship with the Author;
                    and, like him, amidst occupations of a different nature, made Religion your
                    voluntary Study; and in all your Enquiries and Actions, have shewn the same
                    inflexible Adherence to Truth and Virtue.</p>
                        <p>I shall always reckon it one of the Advantages of my Relation to Sir
                    Isaac Newton, that it affords me an opportunity of making this public
                    acknowledgment of the unfeigned Respect of,</p>
                        <p>My Lord,</p>
                        <p>Your Lordship's most obedient, and most humble Servant,</p>
                        <p>Benj. Smith.</p>
                    </div>
                </biblStruct>
                <listBibl>
                    <head>Table of Contents</head>
                    <list>
                        <item>Part I. Observations upon the Prophecies of Daniel
                            <list>
                                <item>CHAP. I. Introduction concerning, the Compilers of the Books of the Old Testament.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter01.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. II. Of the Prophetic Language.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter02.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. III. Of the vision of the Image composed of four Metals.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter03.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. IV. Of the vision of the four Beasts.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter04.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. V. Of the Kingdoms represented by the feet of the Image composed of iron and clay.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter05.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. VI. Of the ten Kingdoms represented by the ten horns of the fourth Beast.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter06.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. VII. Of the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter07.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. VIII. Of the power of the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast, to change times and laws.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter08.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. IX. Of the Kingdoms represented in _Daniel_ by the Ram and He-Goat.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter09.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. X. Of the Prophecy of the Seventy Weeks.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter10.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. XI. Of the Times of the Birth and Passion of Christ.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter11.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. XII. Of the Prophecy of the Scripture of Truth.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter12.xml" />
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. XIII. Of the King who did according to his will, and magnified himself above every God, and honoured Mahuzzims, and regarded not the desire of women.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter13.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. XIV. Of the Mahuzzims, honoured by the King who doth according to his will.
                                    <ptr target="Part1Chapter14.xml"/>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </item>
                        <item>Part II. Observations upon the Apocalypse of St. John
                            <list>
                                <item>CHAP. I. Introduction, concerning the time when the Apocalypse was written.
                                    <ptr target="Part2Chapter01.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. II. Of the relation which the Apocalypse of John hath to the Book of the Law of Moses, and to the worship of God in the Temple.
                                    <ptr target="Part2Chapter02.xml"/>
                                </item>
                                <item>CHAP. III. Of the relation which the Prophecy of John hath to those of Daniel; and of the Subject of the Prophecy.
                                    <ptr target="Part2Chapter03.xml"/>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </listBibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
      <div n="p.1" type="part">
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter01.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter02.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter03.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter04.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter05.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter06.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter07.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter08.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter09.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter10.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter11.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter12.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter13.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part1Chapter14.xml"/>
        </div>
        <div n="p.2" type="part">
            <xi:include href="Part2Chapter01.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part2Chapter02.xml"/>
            <xi:include href="Part2Chapter03.xml"/>
        </div>
        </body>
<back>
      <div n="a.1" type="appendix">
        <div type="preamble">
          <head>Advertisement.</head> _The last pages of these Observations having been differently
          drawn up by the Author in another copy of his Work; they are here inserted as they follow
          in that copy, after the 22d line of the 261st page foregoing._ </div>
        <p>
          _And none was found worthy to open the book_ till the Lamb of God appeared;
          the great High-Priest represented by a lamb slain at the foot of the Altar
          in the morning-sacrifice. _And he came, and took the book out of the hand
          of him that sat upon the throne._ For the High-Priest, in the feast of the
          seventh month, went into the most holy place, and took the book of the law
          out of the right side of the Ark, to read it to the people: and in order to
          read it well, he studied it seven days, that is, upon the fourth, fifth,
          sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth and tenth days, being attended by some of the
          priests to hear him perform. These seven days are alluded to, by the Lamb's
          opening the seven seals successively.
        </p>
        <p>
          Upon the tenth day of the month, a young bullock was offered for a
          sin-offering for the High-Priest, and a goat for a sin-offering for the
          people: and lots were cast upon two goats to determine which of them should
          be God's lot for the sin-offering; and the other goat was called _Azazel_,
          the scape-goat. The High-Priest in his linen garments, took a censer full
          of burning coals of fire from the Altar, his hand being full of sweet
          incense beaten small; and went into the most holy place within the veil,
          and put the incense upon the fire, and sprinkled the blood of the bullock
          with his finger upon the mercy-seat and before the mercy-seat seven times;
          and then he killed the goat which fell to God's lot, for a sin-offering for
          the people, and brought his blood within the veil, and sprinkled it also
          seven times upon the mercy-seat and before the mercy-seat. Then he went out
          to the Altar, and sprinkled it also seven times with the blood of the
          bullock, and as often with the blood of the goat. After this _he laid both
          his hands upon the head of the live goat; and confessed over him all the
          iniquities of the children of _Israel_, and all their transgressions in all
          their sins, putting them upon the head of the goat; and sent him away into
          the wilderness by the hands of a fit man: and the goat bore upon him all
          their iniquities into a land not inhabited_, Levit. chap. iv. &amp; chap. xvi.
          While the High-Priest was doing these things in the most holy place and at
          the Altar, the people continued at their devotion quietly and in silence.
          Then the High-Priest went into the holy place, put off his linen garments,
          and put on other garments; then came out, and sent the bullock and the goat
          of the sin-offering to be burnt without the camp, with fire taken in a
          censer from the Altar: and as the people returned home from the Temple,
          they said to one another, _God seal you to a good new year_.
        </p>
        <p>
          In allusion to all this, _when he had opened the seventh seal, there was
          silence in heaven about the space of half an hour. And an Angel stood at
          the Altar having a golden Censer, and there was given unto him much
          incense, that he should offer it with the prayers of all Saints, upon the
          golden Altar which was before the throne. And the smoke of the incense with
          the prayers of the Saints ascended up before God out of the Angel's hand.
          And the Angel took the Censer, and filled it with fire of the Altar, and
          cast it to the earth_, suppose without the camp, for sacrificing the goat
          which fell to God's lot. For the High-Priest being _Christ_ himself, the
          bullock is omitted. At this sacrifice _there were voices and thundrings_,
          of the musick of the Temple, _and lightnings_ of the sacred fire, _and an
          earthquake_: and synchronal to these things was the sealing of _the 144000
          out of all the twelve tribes of the children of _Israel_ with the seal of
          God in their foreheads_, while the rest of the twelve tribes received the
          mark of the Beast, and the Woman fled from the Temple into the wilderness
          to her place upon this Beast. For this sealing and marking was represented
          by casting lots upon the two goats, sacrificing God's lot on mount _Sion_,
          and sending the scape-goat into the wilderness loaden with the sins of the
          people.
        </p>
        <p>
          Upon the fifteenth day of the month, and the six following days, there were
          very great sacrifices. And in allusion to the sounding of trumpets, and
          singing with thundring voices, and pouring out drink-offerings at those
          sacrifices, _seven trumpets are sounded_, and _seven thunders utter their
          voices_, and _seven vials of wrath are poured out_. Wherefore the sounding
          of the _seven trumpets_, the voices of the _seven thunders_, and the
          pouring out of the _seven vials of wrath_, are synchronal, and relate to
          one and the same division of the time of the seventh seal following the
          silence, into seven successive parts. The seven days of this feast were
          called the feast of Tabernacles; and during these seven days the children
          of _Israel_ dwelt in booths, and rejoiced with palm-branches in their
          hands. To this alludes _the multitude with palms in their hands_, which
          appeared after the sealing of the 144000, and _came out of the great
          tribulation_ with triumph at the battle of the great day, to which the
          seventh trumpet sounds. The visions therefore of the 144000, and of the
          palm-bearing multitude, extend to the sounding of the seventh trumpet, and
          therefore are synchronal to the times of the seventh seal.
        </p>
        <p>
          When the 144000 _are sealed out of all the twelve tribes of _Israel__, and
          the rest receive _the mark of the Beast_, and thereby the first temple is
          destroyed; _John_ is bidden to _measure the temple and altar_, that is,
          their courts, _and them that worship therein_, that is, the 144000 standing
          on mount _Sion_ and on the sea of glass: _but the court that is without the
          temple_, that is, the peoples court, to _leave out and measure it not,
          because it is given to the_ Gentiles, those who receive the mark of the
          Beast; _and the holy city they shall tread under foot forty and two
          months_, that is, all the time that the Beast acts under the woman
          _Babylon_: and _the two witnesses prophesy 1260 days_, that is, all the
          same time, _clothed in sackcloth. These have power_, like _Elijah, to shut
          heaven that it rain not_, at the sounding of the first trumpet; and, like
          _Moses, to turn the waters into blood_ at the sounding of the second; _and
          to smite the earth with all plagues_, those of the trumpets, _as often as
          they will_. These prophesy at the building of the second temple, like
          _Haggai_ and _Zechary_. These are _the two Olive-trees_, or Churches, which
          _supplied the lamps with oil_, _Zech._ iv. These are _the two
          candlesticks_, or Churches, _standing before the God of the earth_. Five of
          the seven Churches of _Asia_, those in prosperity, are found fault with,
          and exhorted to repent, and threatned to be _removed out of their places_,
          or _spewed out of _Christ's_ mouth_, or _punished with the sword of
          _Christ's_ mouth, except they repent_: the other two, the Churches of
          _Smyrna_ and _Philadelphia_, which were under persecution, remain in a
          state of persecution, to illuminate the second temple. When the primitive
          Church catholick, represented by _the woman in heaven_, apostatized, and
          became divided into two corrupt Churches, represented by the _whore of
          _Babylon__ and the _two-horned Beast_, the 144000 _who were sealed out of
          all the twelve tribes_, became the _two Witnesses_, in opposition to those
          two false Churches: and the name of _two Witnesses_ once imposed, remains
          to the true Church of God in all times and places to the end of the
          Prophecy.
        </p>
        <p>
          In the interpretation of this Prophecy, _the woman in heaven clothed with
          the sun_, before she flies into the wilderness, represents the primitive
          Church catholick, illuminated with the _seven lamps_ in the _seven golden
          candlesticks_, which are the _seven Churches_ of _Asia_. The Dragon
          signifies the same Empire with _Daniel_'s He-goat in the reign of his last
          horn, that is, the whole _Roman_ Empire, until it became divided into the
          _Greek_ and _Latin_ Empires; and all the time of that division it signifies
          the _Greek_ Empire alone: and the Beast is _Daniel_'s fourth Beast, that
          is, the Empire of the _Latins_. Before the division of the _Roman_ Empire
          into the _Greek_ and _Latin_ Empires, the Beast is included in the body of
          the Dragon; and from the time of that division, the Beast is the _Latin_
          Empire only. Hence the Dragon and Beast have the same heads and horns; but
          the heads are crowned upon the Dragon, and the horns upon the Beast. The
          horns are ten kingdoms, into which the Beast becomes divided presently
          after his separation from the Dragon, as hath been described above. The
          heads are seven successive dynasties, or parts, into which the _Roman_
          Empire becomes divided by the opening of the seven seals. Before the woman
          fled into the wilderness, _she being with child_ of a Christian Empire,
          _cried travelling_, viz. in the ten years persecution of _Dioclesian_, _and
          pained to be delivered: and the Dragon_, the heathen _Roman_ Empire, _stood
          before her, to devour her child as soon as it was born. And she brought
          forth a man child, who_ at length _was to rule all nations with a rod of
          iron. And her child was caught up unto God, and to his throne_ in the
          Temple, by the victory of _Constantine_ the great over _Maxentius_: _and
          the woman fled_ from the Temple _into the wilderness_ of _Arabia_ to
          _Babylon_, _where she hath a place_ of riches and honour and dominion, upon
          the back of the Beast, _prepared of God, that they should feed her there
          1260 days. And there was war in heaven_, between the heathens under
          _Maximinus_ and the new Christian Empire; _and the great Dragon was cast
          out, that old serpent, which deceiveth the whole world_, the spirit of
          heathen idolatry; _he was cast out_ of the throne _into the earth. And they
          overcame him by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony;
          and they loved not their lives unto the death_.
        </p>
        <p>
          _And when the Dragon saw that he was cast unto the earth, he persecuted the
          woman which brought forth the man child_, stirring up a new persecution
          against her in the reign of _Licinius_. _And to the woman_, by the building
          of _Constantinople_ and equalling it to _Rome_, _were given two wings of a
          great eagle, that she might flee into the wilderness into her place_ upon
          the back of her Beast, _where she is nourished for a time, and times, and
          half a time, from the face of the serpent. And the serpent_, upon the death
          of _Constantine_ the great, _cast out of his mouth water as a flood_, viz.
          the _Western_ Empire under _Constantine junior_ and _Constans_, _after the
          woman: that he might cause her to be carried away of the flood. And the
          earth_, the nations of _Asia_ now under _Constantinople_, _helped the
          woman_; and by conquering the _Western_ Empire, now under _Magnentius_,
          _swallowed up the flood which the Dragon cast out of his mouth. And the
          Dragon was wroth with the woman, and went to make war with the remnant of
          her seed, which keep the commandments of God, and have the testimony of
          _Jesus Christ_, which_ in that war _were sealed out of all the twelve
          tribes of _Israel__, and remained upon mount _Sion_ with the Lamb, being in
          number 144000, and having their father's name written in their foreheads.
        </p>
        <p>
          When the earth had swallowed up the flood, and the Dragon was gone to make
          war with the remnant of the woman's seed, _John stood upon the sand of the
          sea, and saw a Beast rise out of the sea, having seven heads and ten horns.
          And the Beast was like unto a Leopard, and his feet were as the feet of a
          Bear, and his mouth as the mouth of a Lion._ _John_ here names _Daniel_'s
          four Beasts in order, putting his Beast in the room of _Daniel_'s fourth
          Beast, to shew that they are the same. _And the Dragon gave_ this Beast
          _his power and his seat and great authority_, by relinquishing the
          _Western_ Empire to him. _And one of his heads_, the sixth, was _as it were
          wounded to death_, viz. by the sword of the earth, which swallowed up the
          waters cast out of the mouth of the Dragon; _and his deadly wound was
          healed_, by a new division of the Empire between _Valentinian_ and
          _Valens_, _An._ 364. _John_ saw the Beast rise out of the sea, at the
          division thereof between _Gratian_ and _Theodosius_, _An._ 379. The Dragon
          gave the Beast his power, and his seat and great authority, at the death of
          _Theodosius_, when _Theodosius_ gave the _Western_ Empire to his son
          _Honorius_. After which the two Empires were no more united: but the
          _Western_ Empire became presently divided into ten kingdoms, as above; and
          these kingdoms at length united in religion under the woman, and reign with
          her _forty and two months_.
        </p>
        <p>
          _And I beheld_, saith _John_, _another Beast coming up out of the earth._
          When the woman fled from the Dragon into the kingdom of the Beast, and
          became his Church, this other Beast rose up out of the earth, to represent
          the Church of the Dragon. For _he had two horns like the Lamb_, such as
          were the bishopricks of _Alexandria_ and _Antioch_: _and he spake as the
          Dragon_ in matters of religion: _and he causeth the earth_, or nations of
          the Dragon's kingdom, _to worship the first Beast, whose deadly wound was
          healed_, that is, to be of his religion. _And he doth great wonders, so
          that he maketh fire come down from heaven on the earth in the sight of
          men_; that is, he excommunicateth those who differ from him in point of
          religion: for in pronouncing their excommunications, they used to swing
          down a lighted torch from above. _And he said to them that dwell on the
          earth, that they should make an image to the Beast, which had the wound by
          a sword, and did live_; that is, that they should call a Council of men of
          the religion of this Beast. _And he had power to give life unto the image
          of the Beast, that the image of the Beast should both speak, and cause that
          as many as would not worship the image of the Beast should be killed_, viz.
          mystically, by dissolving their Churches. _And he causeth all both small
          and great, rich and poor, free and bond, to receive a mark in their right
          band or in their foreheads, and that no man might buy or sell, save he that
          had the mark, or the name of the Beast, or the number of his name_; that
          is, the mark [Cross], or the name [Greek: LATEINOS], or the number thereof
          [Greek: chxs], 666. All others were excommunicated.
        </p>
        <p>
          When the seven Angels had poured out the seven vials of wrath, and _John_
          had described them all in the present time, he is called up from the time
          of the seventh vial to the time of the sixth seal, to take a view of the
          woman and her Beast, who were to reign in the times of the seventh seal. In
          respect of the latter part of time of the sixth seal, then considered as
          present, the Angel tells _John_: _The Beast that thou sawest, was and is
          not, and shall ascend out of the abyss, and go into perdition_; that is, he
          was in the reign of _Constans_ and _Magnentius_, until _Constantius_
          conquered _Magnentius_, and re-united the _Western_ Empire to the
          _Eastern_. He is not during the reunion, and he shall ascend out of the
          abyss or sea at a following division of the Empire. The Angel tells him
          further: _Here is the mind which hath wisdom: the seven heads are seven
          mountains, on which the woman sitteth_; _Rome_ being built upon seven
          hills, and thence called the seven-hilled city. _Also there are seven
          Kings: five are fallen, and one is, and the other is not yet come; and when
          he cometh, he must continue a short space: and the Beast that was and is
          not, even he is the eighth, and is of the seven, and goeth into perdition_.
          Five are fallen, the times of the five first seals being past; and one is,
          the time of the sixth seal being considered as present; and another is not
          yet come, and when he cometh, which will be at the opening of the seventh
          seal, he must continue a short space: and the Beast that was and is not,
          even he is the eighth, by means of the division of the _Roman_ Empire into
          two collateral Empires; and is of the seven, being one half of the seventh,
          and shall go into perdition. The words, _five are fallen, and one is, and
          the other is not yet come_, are usually referred by interpreters to the
          time of _John_ the Apostle, when the Prophecy was given: but it is to be
          considered, that in this Prophecy many things are spoken of as present,
          which were not present when the Prophecy was given, but which would be
          present with respect to some future time, considered as present in the
          visions. Thus where it is said upon pouring out the seventh vial of wrath,
          that _great _Babylon_ came in remembrance before God, to give unto her the
          cup of the wine of the fierceness of his wrath_; this relates not to the
          time of _John_ the Apostle, but to the time of pouring out the seventh vial
          of wrath. So where it is said, _Babylon is fallen, is fallen_; and _thrust
          in thy sickle and reap, for the time is come for thee to reap_; and _the
          time of the dead is come, that they should be judged_; and again, _I saw
          the dead small and great stand before God_: these sayings relate not to the
          days of _John_ the Apostle, but to the latter times considered as present
          in the visions. In like manner the words, _five are fallen, and one is, and
          the other is not yet come_, and _the Beast that was and is not, he is the
          eighth_, are not to be referred to the age of _John_ the Apostle, but
          relate to the time when the Beast was to be wounded to death with a sword,
          and shew that this wound was to be given him in his sixth head: and without
          this reference we are not told in what head the Beast was wounded. _And the
          ten horns which thou sawest, are ten Kings, which have received no kingdom
          as yet, but receive power as Kings one hour with the Beast. These have one
          mind_, being all of the whore's religion, _and shall give their power and
          strength unto the Beast. These shall make war with the Lamb_, at the
          sounding of the seventh trumpet; _and the Lamb shall overcome them: for he
          is Lord of Lords and King of Kings; and they that are with him are called
          and chosen and faithful. And he saith unto me, the waters which thou sawest
          where the whore sitteth, are peoples and multitudes and nations and
          tongues_, composing her Beast. _And the ten horns which thou sawest upon
          the Beast, these shall hate the whore, and shall make her desolate and
          naked, and shall eat her flesh, and burn her with fire_, at the end of the
          1260 days. _For God hath put in their hearts to fulfil his will, and to
          agree and give their kingdom unto the Beast, until the words of God shall
          be fulfilled. And the woman which thou sawest, is that great city which
          reigneth over the Kings of the earth_, or the great city of the _Latins_,
          which reigneth over the ten Kings till the end of those days.
        </p>
        <milestone unit="appendix" n="a.1" rend="italic">
          FINIS.
        </milestone>
        <milestone unit="appendix" n="a.1" rend="bold">
          *** END OF THE PROJECT GUTENBERG EBOOK OBSERVATIONS UPON THE PROPHECIES OF DANIEL, AND THE
          APOCALYPSE OF ST. JOHN ***
        </milestone>
      </div>

      <div type="colophon">
        <p>Updated editions will replace the
          previous one—the old editions will be renamed.</p>
        <p>Creating the works from print editions not
          protected by U.S. copyright law means that no one owns a United States copyright in these
          works,
          so the Foundation (and you!) can copy and distribute it in the United States without
          permission
          and without paying copyright royalties. Special rules, set forth in the General Terms of
          Use
          part of this license, apply to copying and distributing Project Gutenberg™ electronic
          works to
          protect the PROJECT GUTENBERG™ concept and trademark. Project Gutenberg is a registered
          trademark, and may not be used if you charge for an eBook, except by following the terms
          of the
          trademark license, including paying royalties for use of the Project Gutenberg trademark.
          If you
          do not charge anything for copies of this eBook, complying with the trademark license is
          very
          easy. You may use this eBook for nearly any purpose such as creation of derivative works,
          reports, performances and research. Project Gutenberg eBooks may be modified and printed
          and
          given away—you may do practically ANYTHING in the United States with eBooks not protected
          by
          U.S. copyright law. Redistribution is subject to the trademark license, especially
          commercial
          redistribution. </p>
      </div>
      <div type="license">
        <head> START: FULL LICENSE </head>
        <head>THE FULL PROJECT GUTENBERG LICENSE </head>
        <head>PLEASE READ THIS BEFORE YOU DISTRIBUTE OR USE THIS WORK </head>
        <p>To protect the Project Gutenberg™ mission of promoting the free
          distribution of electronic works, by using or distributing this work (or any other work
          associated
          in any way with the phrase “Project Gutenberg”), you agree to comply with all the terms of
          the
          Full Project Gutenberg™ License available with this file or online at
          www.gutenberg.org/license.</p>
        <p>Section 1. General Terms of Use and Redistributing Project Gutenberg™ electronic works.</p>
        <p>1.A.
          By reading or using any part of this Project Gutenberg™ electronic work, you indicate that
          you
          have read, understand, agree to and accept all the terms of this license and intellectual
          property
          (trademark/copyright) agreement. If you do not agree to abide by all the terms of this
          agreement,
          you must cease using and return or destroy all copies of Project Gutenberg™ electronic
          works
          in
          your possession. If you paid a fee for obtaining a copy of or access to a Project
          Gutenberg™
          electronic work and you do not agree to be bound by the terms of this agreement, you may
          obtain a
          refund from the person or entity to whom you paid the fee as set forth in paragraph 1.E.8.</p>
        <p>
          1.B. “Project Gutenberg” is a registered trademark. It may only be used on or associated
          in
          any
          way with an electronic work by people who agree to be bound by the terms of this
          agreement.
          There
          are a few things that you can do with most Project Gutenberg™ electronic works even
          without
          complying with the full terms of this agreement. See paragraph 1.C below. There are a lot
          of
          things you can do with Project Gutenberg™ electronic works if you follow the terms of this
          agreement and help preserve free future access to Project Gutenberg™ electronic works. See
          paragraph 1.E below.</p>
        <p>1.C. The Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation (“the
          Foundation” or PGLAF), owns a compilation copyright in the collection of Project
          Gutenberg™
          electronic works. Nearly all the individual works in the collection are in the public
          domain
          in
          the United States. If an individual work is unprotected by copyright law in the United
          States
          and
          you are located in the United States, we do not claim a right to prevent you from copying,
          distributing, performing, displaying or creating derivative works based on the work as
          long as
          all
          references to Project Gutenberg are removed. Of course, we hope that you will support the
          Project
          Gutenberg™ mission of promoting free access to electronic works by freely sharing Project
          Gutenberg™ works in compliance with the terms of this agreement for keeping the Project
          Gutenberg™
          name associated with the work. You can easily comply with the terms of this agreement by
          keeping
          this work in the same format with its attached full Project Gutenberg™ License when you
          share
          it
          without charge with others.</p>
        <p> 1.D. The copyright laws of the place where you are located also
          govern what you can do with this work. Copyright laws in most countries are in a constant
          state of
          change. If you are outside the United States, check the laws of your country in addition
          to
          the
          terms of this agreement before downloading, copying, displaying, performing, distributing
          or
          creating derivative works based on this work or any other Project Gutenberg™ work. The
          Foundation
          makes no representations concerning the copyright status of any work in any country other
          than
          the
          United States. </p>
        <p>1.E. Unless you have removed all references to Project Gutenberg:
        </p>
        <p> 1.E.1. The following sentence, with active links to, or other immediate access to, the
          full Project Gutenberg™ License must appear prominently whenever any copy of a Project
          Gutenberg™ work (any work on which the phrase “Project Gutenberg” appears, or with which
          the phrase “Project Gutenberg” is associated) is accessed, displayed, performed, viewed,
          copied or distributed: <q>
            This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the United States and most
            other parts of the world at no cost and with almost no restrictions
            whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms
            of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online
            at www.gutenberg.org. If you
            are not located in the United States, you will have to check the laws
            of the country where you are located before using this eBook.</q>
        </p>
        <p> 1.E.2. If an
          individual Project Gutenberg™ electronic work is derived from texts not protected by U.S.
          copyright law (does not contain a notice indicating that it is posted with permission of
          the
          copyright holder), the work can be copied and distributed to anyone in the United States
          without
          paying any fees or charges. If you are redistributing or providing access to a work with
          the
          phrase “Project Gutenberg” associated with or appearing on the work, you must comply
          either
          with
          the requirements of paragraphs 1.E.1 through 1.E.7 or obtain permission for the use of the
          work
          and the Project Gutenberg™ trademark as set forth in paragraphs 1.E.8 or 1.E.9.</p>
        <p>1.E.3. If
          an individual Project Gutenberg™ electronic work is posted with the permission of the
          copyright
          holder, your use and distribution must comply with both paragraphs 1.E.1 through 1.E.7 and
          any
          additional terms imposed by the copyright holder. Additional terms will be linked to the
          Project
          Gutenberg™ License for all works posted with the permission of the copyright holder found
          at
          the
          beginning of this work. </p>
        <p>1.E.4. Do not unlink or detach or remove the full Project
          Gutenberg™ License terms from this work, or any files containing a part of this work or
          any
          other
          work associated with Project Gutenberg™. </p>
        <p>1.E.5. Do not copy, display, perform, distribute
          or redistribute this electronic work, or any part of this electronic work, without
          prominently
          displaying the sentence set forth in paragraph 1.E.1 with active links or immediate access
          to
          the
          full terms of the Project Gutenberg™ License.</p>
        <p>1.E.6. You may convert to and distribute this
          work in any binary, compressed, marked up, nonproprietary or proprietary form, including
          any
          word
          processing or hypertext form. However, if you provide access to or distribute copies of a
          Project
          Gutenberg™ work in a format other than “Plain Vanilla ASCII” or other format used in the
          official
          version posted on the official Project Gutenberg™ website (www.gutenberg.org), you must,
          at no
          additional cost, fee or expense to the user, provide a copy, a means of exporting a copy,
          or a
          means of obtaining a copy upon request, of the work in its original “Plain Vanilla ASCII”
          or
          other
          form. Any alternate format must include the full Project Gutenberg™ License as specified
          in
          paragraph 1.E.1. </p>
        <p> 1.E.7. Do not charge a fee for access to, viewing, displaying, performing,
          copying or distributing any Project Gutenberg™ works unless you comply with paragraph
          1.E.8 or
          1.E.9. </p>
        <p> 1.E.8. You may charge a reasonable fee for copies of or providing access to or
          distributing Project Gutenberg™ electronic works provided that: <list>
            <item>You pay a royalty fee of 20% of the gross profits you derive from
              the use of Project Gutenberg™ works calculated using the method
              you already use to calculate your applicable taxes. The fee is owed
              to the owner of the Project Gutenberg™ trademark, but he has
              agreed to donate royalties under this paragraph to the Project
              Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation. Royalty payments must be paid
              within 60 days following each date on which you prepare (or are
              legally required to prepare) your periodic tax returns. Royalty
              payments should be clearly marked as such and sent to the Project
              Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation at the address specified in
              Section 4, “Information about donations to the Project Gutenberg
              Literary Archive Foundation.”</item>

            <item>You provide a full refund of any money paid by a
              user who notifies
              you in writing (or by e-mail) within 30 days of receipt that s/he
              does not agree to the terms of the full Project Gutenberg™
              License. You must require such a user to return or destroy all
              copies of the works possessed in a physical medium and discontinue
              all use of and all access to other copies of Project Gutenberg™
              works.</item>

            <item>You provide, in accordance with paragraph 1.F.3, a full refund of
              any money paid for a work or a replacement copy, if a defect in the
              electronic work is discovered and reported to you within 90 days of
              receipt of the work.</item>

            <item>You comply with all other terms of this agreement for free
              distribution of Project Gutenberg™ works.</item>
          </list>
        </p>
        <p> 1.E.9. If you wish to
          charge a fee or distribute a Project Gutenberg™ electronic work or group of works on
          different
          terms than are set forth in this agreement, you must obtain permission in writing from the
          Project
          Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation, the manager of the Project Gutenberg™ trademark.
          Contact
          the Foundation as set forth in Section 3 below. </p>
        <p> 1.F. <br /> 1.F.1. Project Gutenberg volunteers and employees expend considerable effort
          to identify, do copyright research on, transcribe and proofread works not protected by
          U.S. copyright law in creating the Project Gutenberg™ collection. Despite these efforts,
          Project Gutenberg™ electronic works, and the medium on which they may be stored, may
          contain “Defects,” such as, but not limited to, incomplete, inaccurate or corrupt data,
          transcription errors, a copyright or other intellectual property infringement, a defective
          or damaged disk or other medium, a computer virus, or computer codes that damage or cannot
          be read by your equipment. </p>
        <p> 1.F.2. LIMITED WARRANTY, DISCLAIMER OF
          DAMAGES - Except for the “Right of Replacement or Refund” described in paragraph 1.F.3,
          the
          Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation, the owner of the Project Gutenberg™
          trademark,
          and
          any other party distributing a Project Gutenberg™ electronic work under this agreement,
          disclaim
          all liability to you for damages, costs and expenses, including legal fees. YOU AGREE THAT
          YOU
          HAVE NO REMEDIES FOR NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY, BREACH OF WARRANTY OR BREACH OF
          CONTRACT
          EXCEPT
          THOSE PROVIDED IN PARAGRAPH 1.F.3. YOU AGREE THAT THE FOUNDATION, THE TRADEMARK OWNER, AND
          ANY
          DISTRIBUTOR UNDER THIS AGREEMENT WILL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ACTUAL, DIRECT, INDIRECT,
          CONSEQUENTIAL, PUNITIVE OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES EVEN IF YOU GIVE NOTICE OF THE POSSIBILITY
          OF
          SUCH
          DAMAGE. </p>
        <p> 1.F.3. LIMITED RIGHT OF REPLACEMENT OR REFUND - If you discover a defect in this
          electronic work within 90 days of receiving it, you can receive a refund of the money (if
          any)
          you
          paid for it by sending a written explanation to the person you received the work from. If
          you
          received the work on a physical medium, you must return the medium with your written
          explanation.
          The person or entity that provided you with the defective work may elect to provide a
          replacement
          copy in lieu of a refund. If you received the work electronically, the person or entity
          providing
          it to you may choose to give you a second opportunity to receive the work electronically
          in
          lieu
          of a refund. If the second copy is also defective, you may demand a refund in writing
          without
          further opportunities to fix the problem. </p>
        <p> 1.F.4. Except for the limited right of
          replacement or refund set forth in paragraph 1.F.3, this work is provided to you ‘AS-IS’,
          WITH
          NO
          OTHER WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO WARRANTIES
          OF
          MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PURPOSE. </p>
        <p> 1.F.5. Some states do not allow disclaimers of
          certain implied warranties or the exclusion or limitation of certain types of damages. If
          any
          disclaimer or limitation set forth in this agreement violates the law of the state
          applicable
          to
          this agreement, the agreement shall be interpreted to make the maximum disclaimer or
          limitation
          permitted by the applicable state law. The invalidity or unenforceability of any provision
          of
          this
          agreement shall not void the remaining provisions. </p>
        <p> 1.F.6. INDEMNITY - You agree to
          indemnify and hold the Foundation, the trademark owner, any agent or employee of the
          Foundation,
          anyone providing copies of Project Gutenberg™ electronic works in accordance with this
          agreement,
          and any volunteers associated with the production, promotion and distribution of Project
          Gutenberg™ electronic works, harmless from all liability, costs and expenses, including
          legal
          fees, that arise directly or indirectly from any of the following which you do or cause to
          occur:
          (a) distribution of this or any Project Gutenberg™ work, (b) alteration, modification, or
          additions or deletions to any Project Gutenberg™ work, and (c) any Defect you cause. </p>
        <p>
          Section 2. Information about the Mission of Project Gutenberg™ </p>
        <p> Project Gutenberg™ is
          synonymous with the free distribution of electronic works in formats readable by the
          widest
          variety of computers including obsolete, old, middle-aged and new computers. It exists
          because
          of
          the efforts of hundreds of volunteers and donations from people in all walks of life. </p>
        <p>
          Volunteers and financial support to provide volunteers with the assistance they need are
          critical
          to reaching Project Gutenberg™’s goals and ensuring that the Project Gutenberg™ collection
          will
          remain freely available for generations to come. In 2001, the Project Gutenberg Literary
          Archive
          Foundation was created to provide a secure and permanent future for Project Gutenberg™ and
          future
          generations. To learn more about the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation and how
          your
          efforts and donations can help, see Sections 3 and 4 and the Foundation information page
          at
          www.gutenberg.org. </p>
        <p> Section 3. Information about the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive
          Foundation </p>
        <p> The Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation is a non-profit 501(c)(3)
          educational corporation organized under the laws of the state of Mississippi and granted
          tax
          exempt status by the Internal Revenue Service. The Foundation’s EIN or federal tax
          identification
          number is 64-6221541. Contributions to the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation
          are
          tax
          deductible to the full extent permitted by U.S. federal laws and your state’s laws. </p>
        <p> The
          Foundation’s business office is located at 809 North 1500 West, Salt Lake City, UT 84116,
          (801)
          596-1887. Email contact links and up to date contact information can be found at the
          Foundation’s
          website and official page at www.gutenberg.org/contact </p>
        <p> Section 4. Information about
          Donations to the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation </p>
        <p> Project Gutenberg™ depends
          upon and cannot survive without widespread public support and donations to carry out its
          mission
          of increasing the number of public domain and licensed works that can be freely
          distributed in
          machine-readable form accessible by the widest array of equipment including outdated
          equipment.
          Many small donations ($1 to $5,000) are particularly important to maintaining tax exempt
          status
          with the IRS. </p>
        <p> The Foundation is committed to complying with the laws regulating charities
          and charitable donations in all 50 states of the United States. Compliance requirements
          are
          not
          uniform and it takes a considerable effort, much paperwork and many fees to meet and keep
          up
          with
          these requirements. We do not solicit donations in locations where we have not received
          written
          confirmation of compliance. To SEND DONATIONS or determine the status of compliance for
          any
          particular state visit www.gutenberg.org/donate. </p>
        <p> While we cannot and do not solicit
          contributions from states where we have not met the solicitation requirements, we know of
          no
          prohibition against accepting unsolicited donations from donors in such states who
          approach us
          with offers to donate. </p>
        <p> International donations are gratefully accepted, but we cannot make
          any statements concerning tax treatment of donations received from outside the United
          States.
          U.S.
          laws alone swamp our small staff. </p>
        <p> Please check the Project Gutenberg web pages for current
          donation methods and addresses. Donations are accepted in a number of other ways including
          checks,
          online payments and credit card donations. To donate, please visit:
          www.gutenberg.org/donate. </p>
        <p>
          Section 5. General Information About Project Gutenberg™ electronic works </p>
        <p> Professor Michael
          S. Hart was the originator of the Project Gutenberg™ concept of a library of electronic
          works
          that
          could be freely shared with anyone. For forty years, he produced and distributed Project
          Gutenberg™ eBooks with only a loose network of volunteer support. </p>
        <p> Project Gutenberg™ eBooks
          are often created from several printed editions, all of which are confirmed as not
          protected
          by
          copyright in the U.S. unless a copyright notice is included. Thus, we do not necessarily
          keep
          eBooks in compliance with any particular paper edition. </p>
        <p> Most people start at our website
          which has the main PG search facility: www.gutenberg.org. </p>
        <p> This website includes information
          about Project Gutenberg™, including how to make donations to the Project Gutenberg
          Literary
          Archive Foundation, how to help produce our new eBooks, and how to subscribe to our email
          newsletter to hear about new eBooks.</p>
      </div>

    </back>
    </text>
</TEI>