<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<text xmlns="http://example.com/SemanticScripture"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" title="1 Chronicles" id="13"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.com/SemanticScripture ../../Schema/SemanticScripture.xsd">
<ante>
    <publisher>
        The Project Gutenberg eBook of Observations upon the Prophecies of Daniel, and the
        Apocalypse of
        St. John

        This ebook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the United States and
        most other parts of the world at no cost and with almost no restrictions
        whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms
        of the Project Gutenberg License included with this ebook or online
        at www.gutenberg.org. If you are not located in the United States,
        you will have to check the laws of the country where you are located
        before using this eBook.

        Title: Observations upon the Prophecies of Daniel, and the Apocalypse of St. John

        Author: Isaac Newton

        Release date: October 15, 2005 [eBook #16878]
        Most recently updated: December 12, 2020

        Language: English

        Credits: Produced by Greg Alethoup, Robert Shimmin, Keith Edkins
        and the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at
        https://www.pgdp.net
    </publisher>
    <producer>
        Produced by Greg Alethoup, Robert Shimmin, Keith Edkins
        and the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at
        https://www.pgdp.net
    </producer>
    <title>
        OBSERVATIONS
        UPON THE
        PROPHECIES
        OF
        _DANIEL_,
        AND THE
        APOCALYPSE
        OF
        St. _JOHN_.

        * * * * *

        In Two PARTS.

        * * * * *

        By Sir _ISAAC NEWTON_.

    </title>
    <copyright>
        _LONDON,_

        Printed by J. DARBY and T. BROWNE in _Bartholomew-Close._

        And Sold by J. ROBERTS in _Warwick-lane_, J. TONSON in the
        _Strand_, W. INNYS and R. MANBY at the West End of St.
        _Paul's Church-Yard_, J. OSBORN and T. LONGMAN in _Pater-Noster-Row_,
        J. NOON near _Mercers Chapel_ in _Cheapside_,
        T. HATCHETT at the _Royal Exchange_, S. HARDING in St.
        _Martin's lane_, J. STAGG in _Westminster-Hall_, J. PARKER in
        _Pall-mall_, and J. BRINDLEY in _New Bond-Street_.

        M.DCC.XXXIII.
    </copyright>
    <forward>
        To the Right Honourable

        _P E T E R_

        Lord _K I N G_,

        Baron of _Ockham_, Lord High Chancellor of _Great-Britain._

        My Lord,

        _I shall make no Apology for addressing the following Sheets to Your
        Lordship, who lived in a long Intercourse of Friendship with the Author;
        and, like him, amidst occupations of a different nature, made Religion your
        voluntary Study; and in all your Enquiries and Actions, have shewn the same
        inflexible Adherence to Truth and Virtue._

        _I shall always reckon it one of the Advantages of my Relation to Sir
        _Isaac Newton_, that it affords me an opportunity of making this publick
        acknowledgment of the unfeigned Respect of_,

        My Lord,
        Your Lordship's
        most obedient, and
        most humble Servant,
        Benj. Smith.
    </forward>
    <toc>
        <part n="1" caption="Observations upon the Prophecies of _Daniel_.">
            <entries>
                <entry section="98001">CHAP. I. Introduction concerning, the Compilers of the Books of
                    the Old
                    Testament. </entry>
                <entry section="98002">CHAP. II. Of the Prophetic Language. </entry>
                <entry section="98003">CHAP. III. Of the vision of the Image composed of four Metals. </entry>
                <entry section="98004">CHAP. IV. Of the vision of the four Beasts. </entry>
                <entry section="98005">CHAP. V. Of the Kingdoms represented by the feet of the Image
                    composed
                    of iron and clay.</entry>
                <entry section="98006">CHAP. VI. Of the ten Kingdoms represented by the ten horns of the
                    fourth Beast. </entry>
                <entry section="98007">CHAP. VII. Of the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast. </entry>
                <entry section="98008">CHAP. VIII. Of the power of the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s
                    fourth
                    Beast, to change times and laws.</entry>
                <entry section="98009">CHAP. IX. Of the Kingdoms represented in _Daniel_ by the Ram and
                    He-Goat. </entry>
                <entry section="98010">CHAP. X. Of the Prophecy of the Seventy Weeks. </entry>
                <entry section="98011">CHAP. XI. Of the Times of the Birth and Passion of Christ. </entry>
                <entry section="98012">CHAP. XII. Of the Prophecy of the Scripture of Truth. </entry>
                <entry section="98013">CHAP. XIII. Of the King who did according to his will, and
                    magnified
                    himself above every God, and honoured _Mahuzzims_,
                    and regarded not the desire of women.</entry>
                <entry section="98014">CHAP. XIV. Of the _Mahuzzims_, honoured by
                    the King who doth according to his will.</entry>
            </entries>
        </part>
        <part n="2" caption="Observations upon the _Apocalypse_ of St. _John_.  ">
            <entries>
                <entry section="98015">CHAP. I. Introduction, concerning the time when the _Apocalypse_ was written.</entry>
                <entry section="98016">CHAP. II. Of the relation which the _Apocalypse_ of _John_ hath
                    to the Book of the Law of _Moses_, and to the worship of God in the Temple.</entry>
                <entry section="98017">CHAP. III. Of the relation which the Prophecy of _John_ hath to
                    those
                    of _Daniel_; and of the Subject of the Prophecy.</entry>
            </entries>
        </part>
    </toc>
</ante>
<sections>
    <section kind="ch" id="98001">
        <fragments>
            <fragment id="98001001"></fragment>
        </fragments>
    </section>
 </sections>
</text>