<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.1" id="98001" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. I</head>
          <head>Introduction concerning the Compilers of the books of the Old Testament.</head>
          <p id="98001002">
            When _Manasses_ [1] set up a carved image in the house of the Lord, and
            built altars in the two courts of the house, to all the host of Heaven, and
            us'd inchantments and witchcraft, and familiar spirits, and for his great
            wickedness was invaded by the army of _Asserhadon_ King of _Assyria_, and
            carried captive to _Babylon_; the book of the Law was lost till the
            eighteenth year of his grandson _Josiah_. Then [2] _Hilkiah_ the High
            Priest, upon repairing the Temple, found it there: and the King lamented
            that their fathers had not done after the words of the book, and commanded
            that it should be read to the people, and caused the people to renew the
            holy covenant with God. This is the book of the Law now extant.
          </p>
          <p id="98001003">
            When [3] _Shishak_ came out of _Egypt_ and spoil'd the temple, and brought
            _Judah_ into subjection to the monarchy of _Egypt_, (which was in the fifth
            year of _Rehoboam_) the _Jews_ continued under great troubles for about
            twenty years; being _without the true God, and without a teaching Priest,
            and without Law: and in those times there was no peace to him that went
            out, nor to him that came in, but great vexations were upon all the
            inhabitants of the countries, and nation was destroyed of nation, and city
            of city, for God did vex them with all adversity_. But [4] when _Shishak_
            was dead, and _Egypt_ fell into troubles, _Judah_ had quiet ten years; and
            in that time _Asa_ built fenced cities in _Judah_, and got up an army of
            580000 men, with which, in the 15th year of his reign, he met and overcame
            _Zerah_ the _Ethiopian_, who had conquered _Egypt_ and _Lybia_, and
            _Troglodytica_, and came out with an army of 1000000 _Lybians_ and
            _Ethiopians_, to recover the countries conquered by _Sesac_. And after this
            victory [5] _Asa_ dethroned his mother for idolatry, and he renewed the
            Altar, and brought new vessels of gold and silver into the Temple; and he
            and the people entered into a new covenant to seek the Lord God of their
            fathers, upon pain of death to those who worshiped other Gods; and his son
            _Jehosaphat_ took away the high places, and in the third year of his reign
            sent some of his Princes, and of the Priests and Levites, to teach in the
            cities of _Judah_: and they had the book of the Law with them, and went
            about throughout all the cities of _Judah_, and taught the people. This is
            that book of the Law which was afterwards lost in the reign of _Manasses_,
            and found again in the reign of _Josiah_, and therefore it was written
            before the third year of _Jehosaphat_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001004">
            The same book of the Law was preserved and handed down to posterity by the
            _Samaritans_, and therefore was received by the ten Tribes before their
            captivity. For [6] when the ten Tribes were captivated, a Priest or the
            captivity was sent back to _Bethel_, by order of the King of _Assyria_, to
            instruct the new inhabitants of _Samaria_, in _the manner of the God of the
            land_; and the _Samaritans_ had the _Pentateuch_ from this Priest, as
            containing the law or _manner of the God of the land_, which he was to
            teach them. For [7] they persevered in the religion which he taught them,
            joining with it the worship of their own Gods; and by persevering in what
            they had been taught, they preserved this book of their Law in the original
            character of the _Hebrews_, while the two Tribes, after their return from
            _Babylon_, changed the character to that of the _Chaldees_, which they had
            learned at _Babylon_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001005">
            And since the _Pentateuch_ was received as the book of the Law, both by the
            two Tribes and by the ten Tribes, it follows that they received it before
            they became divided into two Kingdoms. For after the division, they
            received not laws from one another, but continued at variance. _Judah_
            could not reclaim _Israel_ from the sin of _Jeroboam_, and _Israel_ could
            not bring _Judah_ to it. The _Pentateuch_ therefore was the book of the Law
            in the days of _David_ and _Solomon_. The affairs of the Tabernacle and
            Temple were ordered by _David_ and _Solomon_, according to the Law of this
            book; and _David_ in the 78th Psalm, admonishing the people to give ear to
            the Law of God, means the Law of this book. For in describing how their
            forefathers kept it not, he quotes many historical things out of the books
            of _Exodus_ and _Numbers_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001006">
            The race of the Kings of _Edom_, before there reigned any King over
            _Israel_, is set down in the book of [8] _Genesis_; and therefore that book
            was not written entirely in the form now extant, before the reign of
            _Saul_. The writer set down the race of those Kings till his own time, and
            therefore wrote before _David_ conquered _Edom_. The _Pentateuch_ is
            composed of the Law and the history of God's people together; and the
            history hath been collected from several books, such as were the history of
            the Creation composed by _Moses_, _Gen_. ii. 4. the book of the generations
            of _Adam_, _Gen._ v. i. and the book of the wars of the Lord, _Num._ xxi.
            14. This book of wars contained what was done at the Red-sea, and in the
            journeying of _Israel_ thro' the Wilderness, and therefore was begun by
            _Moses_. And _Joshua_ might carry it on to the conquest of _Canaan_. For
            _Joshua_ wrote some things in the book of the Law of God, _Josh._ xxiv. 26
            and therefore might write his own wars in the book of wars, those being the
            principal wars of God. These were publick books, and therefore not written
            without the authority of _Moses_ and _Joshua_. And _Samuel_ had leisure in
            the reign of _Saul_, to put them into the form of the books of _Moses_ and
            _Joshua_ now extant, inserting into the book of _Genesis_, the race of the
            Kings of _Edom_, until there reigned a King in _Israel_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001007">
            The book of the _Judges_ is a continued history of the _Judges_ down to the
            death of _Sampson_, and therefore was compiled after his death, out of the
            Acts of the _Judges_. Several things in this book are said to be done _when
            there was no King in _Israel__, _Judg._ xvii. 6. xviii. 1. xix. 1. xxi. 25.
            and therefore this book was written after the beginning of the reign of
            _Saul_. When it was written, the _Jebusites_ dwelt in _Jerusalem_, _Jud._
            i. 21 and therefore it was written before the eighth year of _David_, 2
            _Sam._ v. 8. and 1 _Chron._ xi. 6. The books of _Moses_, _Joshua_, and
            _Judges_, contain one continued history, down from the Creation to the
            death of _Sampson_. Where the _Pentateuch_ ends, the book of _Joshua_
            begins; and where the book of _Joshua_ ends, the book of _Judges_ begins.
            Therefore all these books have been composed out of the writings of
            _Moses_, _Joshua_, and other records, by one and the same hand, after the
            beginning of the reign of _Saul_, and before the eighth year of _David_.
            And _Samuel_ was a sacred writer, 1 _Sam._ x. 25. acquainted with the
            history of _Moses_ and the _Judges_, 1 _Sam._ xii. 8, 9, 10, 11, 12. and
            had leisure in the reign of _Saul_, and sufficient authority to compose
            these books. He was a Prophet, and judged _Israel_ all the days of his
            life, and was in the greatest esteem with the people; and the Law by which
            he was to judge the people was not to be published by less authority than
            his own, the Law-maker being not inferior to the judge. And the book of
            _Jasher_, which is quoted in the book of _Joshua_, _Josh._ x. 13. was in
            being at the death of _Saul_, 2 _Sam._ i. 18.
          </p>
          <p id="98001008">
            At the dedication of the Temple of _Solomon_, when the Ark was brought into
            the most holy place, there was nothing in it but the two tables, 1 _Kings_
            viii. 9. and therefore when the _Philistines_ took the Ark, they took out
            of it the book of the Law, and the golden pot of Manna, and _Aaron_'s Rod.
            And this and other losses in the desolation of _Israel_, by the conquering
            _Philistines_, might give occasion to _Samuel_, after some respite from
            those enemies, to recollect the scattered writings of _Moses_ and _Joshua_,
            and the records of the Patriarchs and Judges, and compose them in the form
            now extant.
          </p>
          <p id="98001009">
            The book of _Ruth_ is a history of things done in the days of the _Judges_,
            and may be looked upon as an addition to the book of the _Judges_, written
            by the same author, and at the same time. For it was written after the
            birth of _David_, _Ruth_ iv. 17, 22. and not long after, because the
            history of _Boaz_ and _Ruth_, the great grandfather and great grandmother
            of _David_, and that of their contemporaries, could not well be remembered
            above two or three generations. And since this book derives the genealogy
            of _David_ from _Boaz_ and _Ruth_, and omits _David_'s elder brothers and
            his sons; it was written in honour of _David_, after he was anointed King
            by _Samuel_, and before he had children in _Hebron_, and by consequence in
            the reign of _Saul_. It proceeds not to the history of _David_, and
            therefore seems to have been written presently after he was anointed. They
            judge well therefore who ascribe to _Samuel_ the books of _Joshua_,
            _Judges_, and _Ruth_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001010">
            _Samuel_ is also reputed the author of the first book of _Samuel_, till the
            time of his death. The two books of _Samuel_ cite no authors, and therefore
            seem to be originals. They begin with his genealogy, birth and education,
            and might be written partly in his lifetime by himself or his disciples the
            Prophets at _Naioth_ in _Ramah_, 1 _Sam._ xix. 18, 19, 20. and partly after
            his death by the same disciples.
          </p>
          <p id="98001011">
            The books of the _Kings_ cite other authors, as the book of the Acts of
            _Solomon_, the book of the _Chronicles_ of the Kings of _Israel_, and the
            book of the _Chronicles_ of the Kings of _Judah_. The books of the
            _Chronicles_ cite the book of _Samuel_ the Seer, the book of _Nathan_ the
            Prophet, and the book of _Gad_ the Seer, for the Acts of _David_; the book
            of _Nathan_ the Prophet, the Prophecy of _Ahijah_ the _Shilonite_, and the
            visions of _Iddo_ the Seer, for the Acts of _Solomon_; the book of
            _Shemajah_ the Prophet, and the book of _Iddo_ the Seer concerning
            genealogies, for the Acts of _Rehoboam_ and _Abijah_; the book of the Kings
            of _Judah_ and _Israel_ for the Acts of _Asa_, _Joash_, _Amaziah_,
            _Jotham_, _Ahaz_, _Hezekiah_, _Manasseh_, and _Josiah_; the book of
            _Hanani_ the Seer, for the Acts of _Jehosaphat_; and the visions of
            _Isaiah_ for the Acts of _Uzziah_ and _Hezekiah_. These books were
            therefore collected out of the historical writings of the antient Seers and
            Prophets. And because the books of the _Kings_ and _Chronicles_ quote one
            another, they were written at one and the same time. And this time was
            after the return from the _Babylonian_ captivity, because they bring down
            the history of _Judah_, and the genealogies of the Kings of _Judah_, and of
            the High Priests, to that captivity. The book of _Ezra_ was originally a
            part of the book of the _Chronicles_, and has been divided from it. For it
            begins with the two last verses of the books of _Chronicles_, and the first
            book of _Esdras_ begins with the two last chapters thereof. _Ezra_ was
            therefore the compiler of the books of _Kings_ and _Chronicles_, and
            brought down the history to his own time. He was a ready Scribe in the Law
            of God; and for assisting him in this work _Nehemias_ founded a library,
            and _gathered together the Acts of the Kings and the Prophets, and of
            _David_, and the Epistles of the Kings, concerning the holy gifts_, 2
            _Maccab._ ii. 13. By the Acts of _David_ I understand here the two books of
            _Samuel_, or at least the second book. Out of the Acts of the _Kings_,
            written from time to time by the Prophets, he compos'd the books of the
            Kings of _Judah_ and _Israel_, the _Chronicles_ of the Kings of _Judah_,
            and the _Chronicles_ of the Kings of _Israel_. And in doing this he joined
            those Acts together, in due order of time, copying the very words of the
            authors, as is manifest from hence, that the books of the _Kings_ and
            _Chronicles_ frequently agree with one another in words for many sentences
            together. Where they agree in sense, there they agree in words also.
          </p>
          <p id="98001012">
            So the Prophecies of _Isaiah_, written at several times, he has collected
            into one body. And the like he did for those of _Jeremiah_, and the rest of
            the Prophets, down to the days of the second Temple. The book of _Jonah_ is
            the history of _Jonah_ written by another hand. The book of _Daniel_ is a
            collection of papers written at several times. The six last chapters
            contain Prophecies written at several times by _Daniel_ himself: the six
            first are a collection of historical papers written by others. The fourth
            chapter is a decree of _Nebuchadnezzar_. The first chapter was written
            after _Daniel_'s death: for the author saith, that _Daniel_ continued to
            the first year of _Cyrus_; that is, to his first year over the _Persians_
            and _Medes_, and third year over _Babylon_. And, for the same reason, the
            fifth and sixth chapters were also written after his death. For they end
            with these words: _So this _Daniel_ prospered in the reign of _Darius_ and
            in the reign of _Cyrus_ the_ Persian. Yet these words might be added by the
            collector of the papers, whom I take to be _Ezra_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001013">
            The Psalms composed by _Moses_, _David_, and others, seem to have been also
            collected by _Ezra_ into one volume. I reckon him the collector, because in
            this collection I meet with Psalms as late as the _Babylonian_ captivity,
            but with none later.
          </p>
          <p id="98001014">
            After these things _Antiochus Epiphanes_ spoiled the Temple, commanded the
            _Jews_ to forsake the Law upon pain of death, and caused the sacred books
            to be burnt wherever they could be found: and in these troubles the book of
            the _Chronicles_ of the Kings of _Israel_ was entirely lost. But upon
            recovering from this oppression, _Judas Maccabæus_ gathered together all
            those writings that were to be met with, 2 _Maccab._ ii. 14. and in
            reducing them into order, part of the Prophecies of _Isaiah_, or some other
            Prophet, have been added to the end of the Prophecies of _Zechariah_; and
            the book of _Ezra_ has been separated from the book of _Chronicles_, and
            set together in two different orders; in one order in the book of _Ezra_,
            received into the Canon, and in another order in the first book of
            _Esdras_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001015">
            After the _Roman_ captivity, the _Jews_ for preserving their traditions,
            put them in writing in their _Talmud_, and for preserving their scriptures,
            agreed upon an Edition, and pointed it, and counted the letters of every
            sort in every book: and by preserving only this Edition, the antienter
            various lections, except what can be discovered by means of the
            _Septuagint_ Version, are now lost; and such marginal noteGrp, or other
            corruptions, as by the errors of the transcribers, before this Edition was
            made, had crept into the text, are now scarce to be corrected.
          </p>
          <p id="98001016">
            The _Jews_ before the _Roman_ captivity, distinguished the sacred books
            into the Law, the Prophets, and the _Hagiographa_, or holy writings; and
            read only the Law and the Prophets in their Synagogues. And Christ and his
            Apostles laid the stress of religion upon the Law and the Prophets, _Matt._
            vii. 12. xxii. 4. _Luke_ xvi. 16, 29, 31. xxiv. 44. _Acts_ xxiv. 14. xxvi.
            22. _Rom._ iii. 21. By the _Hagiographa_ they meant the historical books
            called _Joshua_, _Judges_, _Ruth_, _Samuel_, _Kings_, _Chronicles_, _Ezra_,
            _Nehemiah_, and _Esther_, the book of _Job_, the _Psalms_, the books of
            _Solomon_, and the _Lamentations_. The Samaritans read only the
            _Pentateuch_: and when _Jehosaphat_ sent men to teach in the cities, they
            had with them only the book of the Law; for the Prophecies now extant were
            not then written. And upon the return from the _Babylonian_ captivity,
            _Ezra_ read only the book of the Law to the people, from morning to noon on
            the first day of the seventh month; and from day to day in the feast of
            Tabernacles: for he had not yet collected the writings of the Prophets into
            the volume now extant; but instituted the reading of them after the
            collection was made. By reading the Law and the Prophets in the Synagogues,
            those books have been kept freer from corruption than the _Hagiographa_.
          </p>
          <p id="98001017">
            In the infancy of the nation of _Israel_, when God had given them a Law,
            and made a covenant with them to be their God if they would keep his
            commandments, he sent Prophets to reclaim them, as often as they revolted
            to the worship of other Gods: and upon their returning to him, they
            sometimes renewed the covenant which they had broken. These Prophets he
            continued to send, till the days of _Ezra_: but after their Prophecies were
            read in the Synagogues, those Prophecies were thought sufficient. For if
            the people would not hear _Moses_ and the old Prophets, they would hear no
            new ones, no not _tho they should rise from the dead_. At length when a new
            truth was to be preached to the _Gentiles_, namely, _that Jesus was the
            Christ_, God sent new Prophets and Teachers: but after their writings were
            also received and read in the Synagogues of the Christians, Prophecy ceased
            a second time. We have _Moses_, the Prophets, and Apostles, and the words
            of Christ himself; and if we will not hear them, we shall be more
            inexcusable than the _Jews._ For the Prophets and Apostles have foretold,
            that as _Israel_ often revolted and brake the covenant, and upon repentance
            renewed it; so there should be a falling away among the Christians, soon
            after the days of the Apostles; and that in the latter days God would
            destroy the impenitent revolters, and make a new covenant with his people.
            And the giving ear to the Prophets is a fundamental character of the true
            Church. For God has so ordered the Prophecies, that in the latter days _the
            wise may understand, but the wicked shall do wickedly, and none of the
            wicked shall understand_, Dan. xii. 9, 10. The authority of Emperors,
            Kings, and Princes, is human. The authority of Councils, Synods, Bishops,
            and Presbyters, is human. The authority of the Prophets is divine, and
            comprehends the sum of religion, reckoning _Moses_ and the Apostles among
            the Prophets; and _if an Angel from Heaven preach any other gospel_, than
            what they have delivered, _let him be accursed_. Their writings contain the
            covenant between God and his people, with instructions for keeping this
            covenant; instances of God's judgments upon them that break it: and
            predictions of things to come. While the people of God keep the covenant,
            they continue to be his people: when they break it they cease to be his
            people or church, and become _the Synagogue of Satan, who say they are
            _Jews_ and are not._ And no power on earth is authorized to alter this
            covenant.
          </p>
          <p id="98001018">
            The predictions of things to come relate to the state of the Church in all
            ages: and amongst the old Prophets, _Daniel_ is most distinct in order of
            time, and easiest to be understood: and therefore in those things which
            relate to the last times, he must be made the key to the rest.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes on Chap. I.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.1.1">2 Chron. xxxiii. 5, 6, 7.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.2">2 Chron. xxxiv.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.3">2 Chron. xii. 2, 3, 4, 8, 9. &amp; xv. 3, 5, 6.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.4">2 Chron. xiv. 1, 6, 7, 8, 9, 12.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.5">2 Chron. xv. 3, 12, 13, 16, 18.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.6">2 Kings xvii. 27, 28, 32, 33.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.7">2 Kings xvii. 34, 41.</note>
            <note id="n.1.1.8">Gen. xxxvi. 31.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
