<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.3" id="98003" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. III.</head>
          <head>Of the vision of the Image composed of four Metals.</head>
          <p id="98003002">
            The Prophecies of _Daniel_ are all of them related to one another, as if
            they were but several parts of one general Prophecy, given at several
            times. The first is the easiest to be understood, and every following
            Prophecy adds something new to the former. The first was given in a dream
            to _Nebuchadnezzar_, King of _Babylon_, in the second year of his reign;
            but the King forgetting his dream, it was given again to _Daniel_ in a
            dream, and by him revealed to the King. And thereby, _Daniel_ presently
            became famous for wisdom, and revealing of secrets: insomuch that _Ezekiel_
            his contemporary, in the nineteenth year of _Nebuchadnezzar_, spake thus of
            him to the King of _Tyre_: _Behold_, saith he, _thou art wiser than
            _Daniel_, there is no secret that they can hide from thee_, Ezek. xxviii.
            3. And the same _Ezekiel_, in another place, joins _Daniel_ with _Noah_ and
            _Job_, as most high in the favour of God, _Ezek._ xiv. 14, 16, 18, 20. And
            in the last year of _Belshazzar_, the Queen-mother said of him to the King:
            _Behold there is a man in thy kingdom, in whom is the spirit of the holy
            gods; and in the days of thy father, light and understanding and wisdom,
            like the wisdom of the gods, was found in him; whom the king
            _Nebuchadnezzar_ thy father, the king, I say, thy father made master of the
            magicians, astrologers, _Chaldeans_ and soothsayers: forasmuch as an
            excellent spirit, and knowledge, and understanding, interpreting of dreams,
            and shewing of hard sentences, and dissolving of doubts, were found in the
            same _Daniel_, whom the king named _Belteshazzar__, Dan. v. 11, 12.
            _Daniel_ was in the greatest credit amongst the _Jews_, till the reign of
            the _Roman_ Emperor _Hadrian_: and to reject his Prophecies, is to reject
            the Christian religion. For this religion is founded upon his Prophecy
            concerning the _Messiah_.
          </p>
          <p id="98003003">
            Now in this vision of the Image composed of four Metals, the foundation of
            all _Daniel_'s Prophecies is laid. It represents a body of four great
            nations, which should reign over the earth successively, viz. the people of
            _Babylonia_, the _Persians_, the _Greeks_, and the _Romans_. And by a stone
            cut out without hands, which fell upon the feet of the Image, and brake all
            the four Metals to pieces, and _became a great mountain, and filled the
            whole earth_; it further represents that a new kingdom should arise, after
            the four, and conquer all those nations, and grow very great, and last to
            the end of all ages.
          </p>
          <p id="98003004">
            The head of the Image was of gold, and signifies the nations of
            _Babylonia_, who reigned first, as _Daniel_ himself interprets. _Thou art
            this head of gold_, saith he to _Nebuchadnezzar_. These nations reigned
            till _Cyrus_ conquered _Babylon_, and within a few months after that
            conquest revolted to the _Persians_, and set them up above the _Medes_. The
            breast and arms of the Image were of silver, and represent the _Persians_
            who reigned next. The belly and thighs of the Image were of brass, and
            represent the _Greeks_, who, under the dominion of _Alexander_ the great,
            conquered the _Persians_, and reigned next after them. The legs were of
            iron, and represent the _Romans_ who reigned next after the _Greeks_, and
            began to conquer them in the eighth year of _Antiochus Epiphanes_. For in
            that year they conquered _Perseus_ King of _Macedon_, the fundamental
            kingdom of the _Greeks_; and from thence forward grew into a mighty empire,
            and reigned with great power till the days of _Theodosius_ the great. Then
            by the incursion of many northern nations, they brake into many smaller
            kingdoms, which are represented by the feet and toes of the Image, composed
            part of iron, and part of clay. For then, saith _Daniel_, [1] _the kingdom
            shall be divided, and there shall be in it of the strength of iron, but
            they shall not cleave one to another._
          </p>
          <p id="98003005">
            _And in the days of these Kings_, saith _Daniel_, _shall the God of heaven
            set up a kingdom which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not
            be left to other people; but it shall break in pieces, and consume all
            these kingdoms, and it shall stand for ever. Forasmuch as thou sawest that
            the stone was cut out of the mountains without hands, and that it brake in
            pieces the iron, the brass, the clay, the silver and the gold._</p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. III.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.3.1">Chap. ii. 41, &amp;c.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
