<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.9" type="chapter" id="98009">
          <head>CHAP. IX.</head>
          <head>Of the kingdoms represented in _Daniel_ by the Ram and He-Goat_.</head>
          <p id="98009002">
            The second and third Empires, represented by the Bear and Leopard, are
            again represented by the Ram and He-Goat; but with this difference, that
            the Ram represents the kingdoms of the _Medes_ and _Persians_ from the
            beginning of the four Empires, and the Goat represents the kingdom of the
            _Greeks_ to the end of them. By this means, under the type of the Ram and
            He-Goat, the times of all the four Empires are again described: _I lifted
            up mine eyes_, saith [1] _Daniel_, _and saw_, _and behold there stood
            before the river_ [Ulai] _a Ram which had two horns, and the two horns were
            high, but one was higher than the other, and the higher came up last.--And
            the Ram having two horns, are the kings of _Media_ and _Persia__: not two
            persons but two kingdoms, the kingdoms of _Media_ and _Persia_; and the
            kingdom of _Persia_ was the higher horn and came up last. The kingdom of
            _Persia_ rose up, when _Cyrus_ having newly conquered _Babylon_, revolted
            from _Darius_ King of the _Medes_, and beat him at _Pasargadæ_, and set up
            the _Persians_ above the _Medes_. This was the horn which came up last. And
            the horn which came up first was the kingdom of the _Medes_, from the time
            that _Cyaxares_ and _Nebuchadnezzar_ overthrew _Nineveh_, and shared the
            Empire of the _Assyrians_ between them. The Empires of _Media_ and
            _Babylon_ were contemporary, and rose up together by the fall of the
            _Assyrian_ Empire; and the Prophecy of the four Beasts begins with one of
            them, and that of the Ram and He-Goat with the other. As the Ram represents
            the kingdom of _Media_ and _Persia_ from the beginning of the four Empires;
            so the He-Goat represents the Empire of the _Greeks_ to the end of those
            Monarchies. In the reign of his great horn, and of the four horns which
            succeeded it, he represents this Empire during the reign of the Leopard:
            and in the reign of his little horn, which stood up in the latter time of
            the kingdom of the four, and after their fall became mighty but not by his
            own power, he represents it during the reign of the fourth Beast.
          </p>
          <p id="98009003">
            _The rough Goat_, saith _Daniel, is the King of_ Grecia, that is, the
            kingdom; _and the great horn between his eyes is the first King_: not the
            first Monarch, but the first kingdom, that which lasted during the reign of
            _Alexander_ the great, and his brother _Aridæus_ and two young sons,
            _Alexander_ and _Hercules_. [2] _Now that_ [horn] _being broken off,
            whereas four_ [horns] _stood up for it, four kingdoms shall stand up out of
            the nation_ [of the _Greeks_], _but not in his_ [the first horn's] _power_.
            The four horns are therefore four kingdoms; and by consequence, the first
            great horn which they succeeded is the first great kingdom of the _Greeks_,
            that which was founded by _Alexander_ the great, _An. Nabonass._ 414, and
            lasted till the death of his son _Hercules_, _An. Nabonass._ 441. And the
            four are those of _Cassander_, _Lysimachus_, _Antigonus_, and _Ptolemy_, as
            above.
          </p>
          <p id="98009004">
            [3] _And in the latter time of their kingdom, when the transgressors are
            come to the full, a King_ [or new kingdom] _of fierce countenance, and
            understanding dark sentences, shall stand up: and his power shall be
            mighty, but not by his own power_. This King was the last horn of the Goat,
            the little horn which came up out of one of the four horns, and waxed
            exceeding great. The latter time of their kingdom was when the _Romans_
            began to conquer them, that is, when they conquered _Perseus_ King of
            _Macedonia_, the fundamental kingdom of the _Greeks_. And at that time the
            transgressors came to the full: for then the High-priesthood was exposed to
            sale, the Vessels of the Temple were sold to pay for the purchase; and the
            High-priest, with some of the _Jews_, procured a licence from _Antiochus
            Epiphanes_ to do after the ordinances of the heathen, and set up a school
            at _Jerusalem_ for teaching those ordinances. Then _Antiochus_ took
            _Jerusalem_ with an armed force, slew 4000 _Jews_, took as many prisoners
            and sold them, spoiled the Temple, interdicted the worship, commanded the
            Law of _Moses_ to be burnt, and set up the worship of the heathen Gods in
            all _Judea_. In the very same year, _An. Nabonass._ 580, the _Romans_
            conquered _Macedonia_, the chief of the four horns. Hitherto the Goat was
            mighty by its own power, but henceforward began to be under the _Romans_.
            _Daniel_ distinguishes the times, by describing very particularly the
            actions of the Kings of the north and south, those two of the four horns
            which bordered upon _Judea_, until the _Romans_ conquered _Macedonia_; and
            thenceforward only touching upon the main revolutions which happened within
            the compass of the nations represented by the Goat. In this latter period
            of time the little horn was to stand up and grow mighty, but not by his own
            power.
          </p>
          <p id="98009005">
            The three first of _Daniel_'s Beasts had their dominions taken away, each
            of them at the rise of the next Beast; but their lives were prolonged, and
            they are all of them still alive. The third Beast, or Leopard, reigned in
            his four heads, till the rise of the fourth Beast, or Empire of the
            _Latins_; and his life was prolonged under their power. This Leopard
            reigning in his four heads, signifies the same thing with the He-Goat
            reigning in his four horns: and therefore the He-Goat reigned in his four
            horns till the rise of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast, or Empire of the _Latins_:
            then its dominion was taken away by the _Latins_, but its life was
            prolonged under their power. The _Latins_ are not comprehended among the
            nations represented by the He-Goat in this Prophecy: their power over the
            _Greeks_ is only named in it, to distinguish the times in which the He-Goat
            was mighty by his own power, from the times in which he was mighty but not
            by his own power. He was mighty by his own power till his dominion was
            taken away by the _Latins_; after that, his life was prolonged under their
            dominion, and this prolonging of his life was in the days of his last horn:
            for in the days of this horn the Goat became mighty, but not by his own
            power.
          </p>
          <p id="98009006">
            Now because this horn was a horn of the Goat, we are to look for it among
            the nations which composed the body of the Goat. Among those nations he was
            to rise up and grow mighty: he grew mighty [4] _towards the south, and
            towards the east, and towards the pleasant land_; and therefore he was to
            rise up in the north-west parts of those nations, and extend his dominion
            towards _Egypt_, _Syria_ and _Judea_. In the latter time of the kingdom of
            the four horns, it was to rise up out of one of them and subdue the rest,
            but not by its own power. It was to be assisted by a foreign power, a power
            superior to itself, the power which took away the dominion of the third
            Beast, the power of the fourth Beast. And such a little horn was the
            kingdom of _Macedonia_, from the time that it became subject to the
            _Romans_. This kingdom, by the victory of the _Romans_ over _Persius_ King
            of _Macedonia_, _Anno Nabonass._ 580, ceased to be one of the four horns of
            the Goat, and became a dominion of a new sort: not a horn of the fourth
            Beast, for _Macedonia_ belonged to the body of the third; but a horn of the
            third Beast of a new sort, a horn of the Goat which grew mighty but not by
            his own power, a horn which rose up and grew potent under a foreign power,
            the power of the _Romans_.
          </p>
          <p id="98009007">
            The _Romans_, by the legacy of _Attalus_ the last King of _Pergamus_, _An.
            Nabonass._ 615, inherited that kingdom, including all _Asia Minor_ on this
            side mount _Taurus_. _An. Nabonass._ 684 and 685 they conquered _Armenia_,
            _Syria_ and _Judea_; _An. Nabonass._ 718, they subdued _Egypt_. And by
            these conquests the little horn [5] _waxed exceeding great towards the
            south, and towards the east, and towards the pleasant land. And it waxed
            great even to the host of heaven; and cast down some of the host and of the
            stars to the ground, and stamped upon them_, that is, upon the people and
            great men of the _Jews_. [6] _Yea, he magnified himself even to the Prince
            of the Host_, the _Messiah_, the Prince of the _Jews_, whom he put to
            death, _An. Nabonass._ 780. _And by him the daily sacrifice was taken away,
            and the place of his sanctuary was cast down_, viz. in the wars which the
            armies of the _Eastern_ nations under the conduct of the _Romans_ made
            against _Judea_, when _Nero_ and _Vespasian_ were Emperors, _An. Nabonass._
            816, 817, 818. [7] _And an host was given him against the daily sacrifice
            by reason of transgression, and it cast down the truth to the ground, and
            it practised and prospered_. This transgression is in the next words called
            _the transgression of desolation_; and in _Dan._ xi. 31. _the abomination
            which maketh desolate_; and in _Matth._ xxiv. 15. _the abomination of
            desolation, spoken of by _Daniel_ the prophet, standing in the holy place_.
            It may relate chiefly to the worship of _Jupiter Olympius_ in his Temple
            built by the Emperor _Hadrian_, in the place of the Temple of the _Jews_,
            and to the revolt of the _Jews_ under _Barchochab_ occasioned thereby, and
            to the desolation of _Judea_ which followed thereupon; all the _Jews_,
            being thenceforward banished _Judea_ upon pain of death. _Then I heard_,
            saith [8] _Daniel, one saint speaking, and another saint said unto that
            certain saint which spake, How long shall be the vision concerning the
            daily sacrifice, and the transgression of desolation, to give both the
            sanctuary and the host to be trodden under foot? And he said unto me, Unto
            two thousand and three hundred days; then shall the sanctuary be cleansed._
            _Daniel_'s days are years; and these years may perhaps be reckoned either
            from the destruction of the Temple by the _Romans_ in the reign of
            _Vespasian_, or from the pollution of the Sanctuary by the worship of
            _Jupiter Olympius_, or from the desolation of _Judea_ made in the end of
            the _Jewish_ war by the banishment of all the _Jews_ out of their own
            country, or from some other period which time will discover. Henceforward
            the last horn of the Goat continued mighty under the _Romans_, till the
            reign of _Constantine_ the great and his sons: and then by the division of
            the _Roman_ Empire between the _Greek_ and _Latin_ Emperors, it separated
            from the _Latins_, and became the _Greek_ Empire alone, but yet under the
            dominion of a _Roman_ family; and at present it is mighty under the
            dominion of the _Turks_.
          </p>
          <p id="98009008">
            This last horn is by some taken for _Antiochus Epiphanes_, but not very
            judiciously. A horn of a Beast is never taken for a single person: it
            always signifies a new kingdom, and the kingdom of _Antiochus_ was an old
            one. _Antiochus_ reigned over one of the four horns, and the little horn
            was a fifth under its proper kings. This horn was at first a little one,
            and waxed exceeding great, but so did not _Antiochus_. It is described
            great above all the former horns, and so was not _Antiochus_. His kingdom
            on the contrary was weak, and tributary to the _Romans_, and he did not
            enlarge it. The horn was a _King of fierce countenance, and destroyed
            wonderfully, and prospered and practised_; that is, he prospered in his
            practises against the holy people: but _Antiochus_ was frighted out of
            _Egypt_ by a mere message of the _Romans_, and afterwards routed and
            baffled by the _Jews_. The horn was mighty by another's power, _Antiochus_
            acted by his own. The horn stood up against the Prince of the Host of
            heaven, the Prince of Princes; and this is the character not of _Antiochus_
            but of _Antichrist_. The horn cast down the Sanctuary to the ground, and so
            did not _Antiochus_; he left it standing. The Sanctuary and Host were
            trampled under foot 2300 days; and in _Daniel_'s Prophecies days are put
            for years: but the profanation of the Temple in the reign of _Antiochus_
            did not last so many natural days. These were to last till the time of the
            end, till the last end of the indignation against the _Jews_; and this
            indignation is not yet at an end. They were to last till the Sanctuary
            which had been cast down should be cleansed, and the Sanctuary is not yet
            cleansed.
          </p>
          <p id="98009009">
            This Prophecy of the Ram and He-Goat is repeated in the last Prophecy of
            _Daniel_. There the Angel tells _Daniel_, that [9] _he stood up to
            strengthen _Darius_ the _Mede_, and that there should stand up yet three
            kings in _Persia__, [_Cyrus_, _Cambyses_, and _Darius Hystaspis_] _and the
            fourth_ [_Xerxes_] _should be far richer than they all; and by his wealth
            thro' his riches he should stir up all against the realm of _Grecia__. This
            relates to the Ram, whose two horns were the kingdoms of _Media_ and
            _Persia_. Then he goes on to describe the horns of the Goat by the [10]
            _standing up of a mighty king, which should rule with great dominion, and
            do according to his will_; and by the breaking of his kingdom into four
            smaller kingdoms, and not descending to his own posterity. Then he
            describes the actions of two of those kingdoms which bordered on _Judea_,
            _viz_. _Egypt_ and _Syria_, calling them the Kings of the _South_ and
            _North_, that is, in respect of _Judea_; and he carries on the description
            till the latter end of the kingdoms of the four, and till the reign of
            _Antiochus Epiphanes_, when transgressors were come to the full. In the
            eighth year of _Antiochus_, the year in which he profaned the Temple and
            set up the heathen Gods in all _Judea_, and the _Romans_ conquered the
            kingdom of _Macedon_; the prophetic Angel leaves off describing the affairs
            of the kings of the _South_ and _North_, and begins to describe those of
            the _Greeks_ under the dominion of the _Romans_, in these words: [11] _And
            after him Arms_ [the _Romans_] _shall stand up, and they shall pollute the
            sanctuary of strength_. As [Hebrew: MMLK] signifies _after the king_, Dan.
            xi. 8; so here [Hebrew: MMNW] may signify _after him_: and so [Hebrew:
            MN-H'CHT] may signify _after one of them_, Dan. viii. 9. Arms are every
            where in these Prophecies of _Daniel_ put for the military power of a
            kingdom, and they stand up when they conquer and grow powerful. The
            _Romans_ conquered _Illyricum_, _Epirus_ and _Macedonia_, in the year of
            _Nabonassar_ 580; and thirty five years after, by the last will and
            testament of _Attalus_ the last King of _Pergamus_, they inherited that
            rich and flourishing kingdom, that is, all _Asia_ on this side mount
            _Taurus_: and sixty nine years after, they conquered the kingdom of
            _Syria_, and reduced it into a Province: and thirty four years after they
            did the like to _Egypt_. By all these steps the _Roman_ arms stood up over
            the _Greeks_. And after 95 years more, by making war upon the _Jews, they
            polluted the sanctuary of strength, and took away the daily sacrifice,
            and_, in its room soon after, _placed the abomination which made_ the Land
            _desolate_: for this abomination was placed after the days of Christ,
            _Matth._ xxiv. 15. In the 16th year of the Emperor _Hadrian_, A. C. 132,
            they placed this abomination by building a Temple to _Jupiter Capitolinus_,
            where the Temple of God in _Jerusalem_ had stood. Thereupon the _Jews_
            under the conduct of _Barchochab_ rose up in arms against the _Romans_, and
            in that war had 50 cities demolished, 985 of their best towns destroyed,
            and 580000 men slain by the sword: and in the end of the war, A.C. 136,
            they were all banished _Judea_ upon pain or death; and that time the land
            hath remained desolate of its old inhabitants.
          </p>
          <p id="98009010">
            Now that the prophetic Angel passes in this manner from the four kingdoms
            of the _Greeks_ to the _Romans_ reigning over the _Greeks_, is confirmed
            from hence, that in the next place he describes the affairs of the
            _Christians_ unto the time of the end, in these words: [12] _And they that
            understand among the people shall instruct many, yet they shall fall by the
            sword and by flame, by captivity and by spoil many days. Now when they
            shall fall they shall be holpen with a little help_, _viz_. in the reign of
            _Constantine_ the great; _but many shall cleave to them with dissimulation.
            And some of them of understanding there shall fall to try them, and to
            purge_ them from the dissemblers; _and to make them white even to the time
            of the end_. And a little after, the time of the end is said to be _a time,
            times, and half a time_: which is the duration of the reign of the last
            horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast, and of the _Woman_ and her _Beast_ in the
            _Apocalyps_.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. IX.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.9.1">Chap. viii. 3.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.2">Ver. 22.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.3">Ver. 23.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.4">Chap. viii. 9.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.5">Chap. viii. 9, 10.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.6">Ver. 11.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.7">Ver. 12.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.8">Ver. 13, 14.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.9">Dan. xi. 1, 2.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.10">Ver. 3.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.11">Dan xi. 31.</note>
            <note id="n.1.9.12">Chap. xi. 33, &amp;c.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
