<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.13" id="98013" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. XIII.</head>
          <head>Of the King who did according to his will, and magnified himself above every God,
            and
            honoured _Mahuzzims_, and regarded not the desire of women.</head>
          <p id="98013002">
            In the first ages of the Christian religion the Christians of every city
            were governed by a Council of Presbyters, and the President of the Council
            was the Bishop of the city. The Bishop and Presbyters of one city meddled
            not with the affairs of another city, except by admonitory letters or
            messages. Nor did the Bishops of several cities meet together in Council
            before the time of the Emperor _Commodus_: for they could not meet together
            without the leave of the _Roman_ governors of the Provinces. But in the
            days of that Emperor they began to meet in Provincial Councils, by the
            leave of the governors; first in _Asia_, in opposition to the
            _Cataphrygian_ Heresy, and soon after in other places and upon other
            occasions. The Bishop of the chief city, or Metropolis of the _Roman_
            Province, was usually made President of the Council; and hence came the
            authority of Metropolitan Bishops above that of other Bishops within the
            same Province. Hence also it was that the Bishop of _Rome_ in _Cyprian_'s
            days called himself the Bishop of Bishops. As soon as the Empire became
            Christian, the _Roman_ Emperors began to call general Councils out of all
            the Provinces of the Empire; and by prescribing to them what points they
            should consider, and influencing them by their interest and power, they set
            up what party they pleased. Hereby the _Greek_ Empire, upon the division of
            the _Roman_ Empire into the _Greek_ and _Latin_ Empires, became _the King
            who_, in matters of religion, _did according to his will_; _and_, in
            legislature, _exalted and magnified himself above every God_: and at
            length, by the seventh general Council, established the worship of the
            images and souls of dead men, here called _Mahuzzims_.
          </p>
          <p id="98013003"> The same King placed holiness in abstinence from marriage. _Eusebius_ in his
            Ecclesiastical history [1] tells us, that _Musanus_ wrote a tract against those who fell
            away to the heresy of the _Encratites_, which was then newly risen, and had introduced
            pernicious errors; and that _Tatian_, the disciple of _Justin_, was the author thereof;
            and that _Irenæus_ in his first book against heresies teaches this, writing of _Tatian_
            and his heresy in these words: <q lang="lat">_A Saturnino &amp; Marcione profecti qui vocantur
              Continentes, docuerunt non contrahendum esse matrimonium; reprobantes
              scilicet primitivum illud opificium Dei, &amp; tacitè accusantes Deum qui
              masculum &amp; fæminam condidit ad procreationem generis humani. Induxerunt
              etiam abstinentiam ab esu eorum quæ animalia appellant, ingratos se
              exhibentes ergo eum qui universa creavit Deum. Negant etiam primi hominis
              salutem. Atque hoc nuper apud illos excogitatum est, Tatiano quodam omnium
              primo hujus impietatis auctore: qui Justini auditor, quamdiu cum illo
              versatus est, nihil ejusmodi protulit. Post martyrium autem illius, ab
              Ecclesia se abrumpens, doctoris arrogantia elatus ac tumidus, tanquam
              præstantior cæteris, novam quandam formam doctrinæ conflavit: Æonas
              invisibiles commentus perinde ac Valentinus: asserens quoque cum Saturnino
              &amp; Marcione, matrimonium nihil aliud esse quam corruptionem ac stuprum: nova
            præterea argumenta ad subvertendam Adami salutem excogitans. Hæc Irenæus de
              Hæresi quæ tunc viguit Encratitarum._</q> Thus far _Eusebius_. But altho the followers
            of _Tatian_ were at first condemned as hereticks by the name of _Encratites_, or
            _Continentes_; their principles could not be yet quite exploded: for _Montanus_ refined
            upon them, and made only second marriages unlawful; he also introduced frequent
            fastings, and annual, fasting days, the keeping of _Lent_, and feeding upon dried meats.
            The _Apostolici_, about the middle of the third century, condemned marriage, and were a
            branch of the disciples of _Tatian_. The _Hierocitæ_ in _Egypt_, in the latter end of
            the third century, also condemned marriage. _Paul_ the _Eremite_ fled into the
            wilderness from the persecution of _Decius_, and lived there a solitary life till the
            reign of _Constantine_ the great, but made no disciples. _Antony_ did the like in the
            persecution of _Dioclesian_, or a little before, and made disciples; and many others
            soon followed his example. </p>
          <p id="98013004"> Hitherto the principles of the _Encratites_ had been rejected by the Churches; but now
            being refined by the Monks, and imposed not upon all men, but only upon those who would
            voluntarily undertake a monastic life, they began to be admired, and to overflow first
            the _Greek_ Church, and then the _Latin_ also, like a torrent. _Eusebius_ tells us, [2]
            that _Constantine_ the great had those men in the highest veneration, who dedicated
            themselves wholly to the divine philosophy; and that he almost venerated the most holy
            company of Virgins perpetually devoted to God; being certain that the God to whom he had
            consecrated himself did dwell in their minds. In his time and that of his sons, this
            profession of a single life was propagated in _Egypt_ by _Antony_, and in _Syria_ by
            _Hilarion_; and spred so fast, that soon after the time of _Julian_ the Apostate a third
            part of the _Egyptians_ were got into the desarts of _Egypt_. They lived first singly in
            cells, then associated into _coenobia_ or convents; and at length came into towns, and
            filled the Churches with Bishops, Presbyters and Deacons. _Athanasius_ in his younger
            days poured water upon the hands of his master _Antony_; and finding the Monks faithful
            to him, made many of them Bishops and Presbyters in _Egypt_: and these Bishops erected
            new Monasteries, out of which they chose Presbyters of their own cities, and sent
            Bishops to others. The like was done in _Syria_, the superstition being quickly
            propagated thither out of _Egypt_ by _Hilarion_ a disciple of _Antony_. _Spiridion_ and
            _Epiphanius_ of _Cyprus_, _James_ of _Nisibis_, _Cyril_ of _Jerusalem_, _Eustathius_ of
            _Sebastia_ in _Armenia_, _Eusebius_ of _Emisa_, _Titus_ of _Bostra_, _Basilius_ of
            _Ancyra_, _Acacius_ of _Cæsarea_ in _Palestine_, _Elpidius_ of _Laodicea_, _Melitius_
            and _Flavian_ of _Antioch_, _Theodorus_ of _Tyre_, _Protogenes_ of _Carrhæ_, _Acacius_
            of _Berrhæa_, _Theodotus_ of _Hierapolis_, _Eusebius_ of _Chalcedon_, _Amphilochius_ of
            _Iconium_, _Gregory Nazianzen_, _Gregory Nyssen_, and _John Chrysostom_ of
            _Constantinople_, were both Bishops and Monks in the fourth century. _Eustathius_,
            _Gregory Nazianzen_, _Gregory Nyssen_, _Basil_, &amp;c. had Monasteries of Clergymen in
            their cities, out of which Bishops were sent to other cities; who in like manner erected
            Monasteries there, till the Churches were supplied with Bishops out of these
            Monasteries. Hence _Jerome_, in a Letter written about the year 385, [3] saith of the
            Clergy: <q lang="lat">_Quasi &amp; ipsi aliud sint quam Monachi, &amp; non
              quicquid in Monachos dicitur redundet in Clericos qui patres sunt
              Monachorum. Detrimentum pecoris pastoris ignominia est_.</q> And in his book against
            _Vigilantius_: <q lang="lat">_Quid facient Orientis Ecclesiæ? Quæ aut Virgines
              Clericos accipiunt, aut Continentes, aut si uxores habuerint mariti esse
              desistunt_.</q> Not long after even the Emperors commanded the Churches to chuse
            Clergymen out of the Monasteries by this Law. _Impp. Arcad &amp; Honor. AA. Cæsario PF.
            P._ </p>
          <p id="98013005"> [4] <q lang="lat">_Si quos forte Episcopi deesse sibi Clericos arbitrantur, ex
            monachorum
              numero rectius
              ordinabunt: non obnoxios publicis privatisque rationibus cum invidia teneant, sed
            habeant
              jam
              probatos. Dat. _vii._ Kal. Aug. Honorio A. _iv._ &amp; Eutychianio Coss._ A.C. 598. </q>
            The _Greek_ Empire being now in the hands of these _Encratites_, and having them in
            great admiration, _Daniel_ makes it a characteristick of the King who doth according to
            his will, that _he should not regard the desire of Women._ </p>
          <p id="98013006">
            Thus the Sect of the _Encratites_, set on foot by the _Gnosticks_, and
            propagated by _Tatian_ and _Montanus_ near the end of the second century;
            which was condemned by the Churches of that and the third century, and
            refined upon by their followers; overspread the _Eastern_ Churches in the
            fourth century, and before the end of it began to overspread the _Western_.
            Henceforward the Christian Churches having a form of godliness, but denying
            the power thereof, came into the hands of the _Encratites_: and the
            Heathens, who in the fourth century came over in great numbers to the
            Christians, embraced more readily this sort of Christianity, as having a
            greater affinity with their old superstitions, than that of the sincere
            Christians; who by the lamps of the seven Churches of _Asia_, and not by
            the lamps of the Monasteries, had illuminated the Church Catholic during
            the three first centuries.
          </p>
          <p id="98013007"> The _Cataphrygians_ brought in also several other superstitions: such as were the
            doctrine of Ghosts, and of their punishment in Purgatory, with prayers and oblations for
            mitigating that punishment, as _Tertullian_ teaches in his books _De Anima_ and _De
            Monogamia_. They used also the sign of the cross as a charm. So _Tertullian_ in his book
            _de Corona militis_: <q lang="lat">_Ad omnem progressum atque promotum, ad omnem aditum &amp; exitum, ad
            vestitum,
              ad calceatum, ad lavacra, ad mensas, ad lamina, ad cubilia, ad sedilia,
              quacunque nos conversatio exercet, frontem crucis signaculo terimus_.</q> All these
            superstitions the Apostle refers to, where he saith: _Now the Spirit speaketh expresly,
            that in the latter times some shall depart from the faith, giving heed to seducing
            spirits, and doctrines of devils_, the _Dæmons_ and Ghosts worshipped by the heathens,
            _speaking lyes in hypocrisy_, about their apparitions, the miracles done by them, their
            reliques, and the sign of the cross, _having consciences seared with a hot iron_;
            _forbidding to marry, and commanding to abstain from meats_, &amp;c. 1 Tim. iv. 1,2,3.
            From the _Cataphrygians_ these principles and practices were propagated down to
            posterity. _For the mystery of iniquity_ did _already work_ in the _Apostles_ days in
            the _Gnosticks_, continued to work very strongly in their offspring the _Tatianists_ and
            _Cataphrygians_, and was to work _till that man of sin_ should _be revealed_; _whose
            coming is after the working of Satan, with all power and signs, and lying wonders, and
            all deceivableness of unrighteousness_; coloured over with a form of _Christian_
            godliness, but without the power thereof, 2 _Thess_. ii. 7-10. </p>
          <p id="98013008">
            For tho some stop was put to the _Cataphrygian_ Christianity, by Provincial
            Councils, till the fourth century; yet the _Roman_ Emperors then turning
            _Christians_, and great multitudes of heathens coming over in outward
            profession, these found the _Cataphrygian_ Christianity more suitable to
            their old principles, of placing religion in outward forms and ceremonies,
            holy-days, and doctrines of Ghosts, than the religion of the sincere
            _Christians_: wherefore they readily sided with the _Cataphrygian
            Christians_, and established that Christianity before the end of the fourth
            century. By this means those of understanding, after they had been
            persecuted by the heathen Emperors in the three first centuries, and _were
            holpen with a little help_, by the conversion of _Constantine_ the great
            and his sons to the _Christian_ religion, fell under new persecutions, _to
            purge them_ from the dissemblers, _and to make them white, even to the time
            of the end_.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. XIII.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.13.1">Lib. 4. c. 28, 29.</note>
            <note id="n.1.13.2">In vita Constantini, l. 4. c. 28.</note>
            <note id="n.1.13.3">Epist. 10.</note>
            <note id="n.1.13.4">L. 32. de Episcopis.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
