<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.2.2" type="chapter" id="98002">
          <head>CHAP. II.</head>
          <head>Of the relation which the _Apocalypse_ of _John_ hath to the Book of the Law of
            _Moses_,
            and to the worship of God in the Temple_.</head>
          <p id="98002002">
            The _Apocalypse_ of _John_ is written in the same style and language with
            the Prophecies of _Daniel_, and hath the same relation to them which they
            have to one another, so that all of them together make but one complete
            Prophecy; and in like manner it consists of two parts, an introductory
            Prophecy, and an Interpretation thereof.
          </p>
          <p id="98002003">
            The Prophecy is distinguish'd into seven successive parts, by the opening
            of the seven seals of the book which _Daniel_ was commanded to seal up: and
            hence it is called the _Apocalypse_ or _Revelation_ of _Jesus Christ_. The
            time of the seventh seal is sub-divided into eight successive parts by the
            silence in heaven for half an hour, and the sounding of seven trumpets
            successively: and the seventh trumpet sounds to the battle of the great day
            of God Almighty, whereby _the kingdoms of this world become the kingdoms of
            the Lord and of his Christ_, and those are destroyed that destroyed the
            earth.
          </p>
          <p id="98002004">
            The Interpretation begins with the words, _And the temple of God was opened
            in heaven, and there was seen in his temple the Ark of his Testament_: and
            it continues to the end of the Prophecy. The Temple is the scene of the
            visions, and the visions in the Temple relate to the feast of the seventh
            month: for the feasts of the _Jews_ were typical of things to come. The
            Passover related to the first coming of _Christ_, and the feasts of the
            seventh month to his second coming: his first coming being therefore over
            before this Prophecy was given, the feasts of the seventh month are here
            only alluded unto.
          </p>
          <p id="98002005">
            On the first day of that month, in the morning, the High-Priest dressed the
            lamps: and in allusion hereunto, this Prophecy begins with a vision of one
            like _the Son of man_ in the High-Priest's habit, appearing as it were in
            the midst of the seven golden candlesticks, or over against the midst of
            them, dressing the lamps, which appeared like a rod of seven stars in his
            right hand: and this dressing was perform'd by the sending seven Epistles
            to the Angels or Bishops of the seven Churches of _Asia_, which in the
            primitive times illuminated the Temple or Church Catholick. These Epistles
            contain admonitions against the approaching Apostacy, and therefore relate
            to the times when the Apostacy began to work strongly, and before it
            prevailed. It began to work in the Apostles days, and was to continue
            working _till the man of sin should be revealed_. It began to work in the
            disciples of _Simon_, _Menander_, _Carpocrates_, _Cerinthas_, and such
            sorts of men as had imbibed the metaphysical philosophy of the _Gentiles_
            and _Cabalistical Jews_, and were thence called _Gnosticks_. _John_ calls
            them _Antichrists_, saying that in his days there were many _Antichrists_.
            But these being condemned by the Apostles, and their immediate disciples,
            put the Churches in no danger during the opening of the first four seals.
            The visions at the opening of these seals relate only to the civil affairs
            of the heathen _Roman_ Empire. So long the Apostolic traditions prevailed,
            and preserved the Church in its purity: and therefore the affairs of the
            Church do not begin to be considered in this Prophecy before the opening of
            the fifth seal. She began then to decline, and to want admonitions; and
            therefore is admonished by these Epistles, till the Apostacy prevailed and
            took place, which was at the opening of the seventh seal. The admonitions
            therefore in these seven Epistles relate to the state of the Church in the
            times of the fifth and sixth seals. At the opening of the fifth seal, the
            Church is purged from hypocrites by a great persecution. At the opening of
            the sixth, that which letted is taken out of the way, namely the heathen
            _Roman_ Empire. At the opening of the seventh, the man of sin is revealed.
            And to these times the seven Epistles relate.
          </p>
          <p id="98002006">
            The seven Angels, to whom these Epistles were written, answer to the seven
            _Amarc-holim_, who were Priests and chief Officers of the Temple, and had
            jointly the keys of the gates of the Temple, with those of the Treasuries,
            and the direction, appointment and oversight of all things in the Temple.
          </p>
          <p id="98002007">
            After the lamps were dresed, _John_ saw _the door_ of the Temple _opened_;
            and by _the voice as it were of a trumpet_, was called up to the eastern
            gate of the great court, to see the visions: and _behold a throne was set_,
            viz. the mercy-seat upon the Ark of the Testament, which the _Jews_
            respected as _the throne of God between the _Cherubims__, _Exod._ xxv. 2.
            _Psal._ xcix. 1. _And he that sat on it was to look upon like _Jasper_ and
            _Sardine_ stone_, that is, of an olive colour, the people of _Judea_ being
            of that colour. _And_, the Sun being then in the _East, a rainbow was about
            the throne_, the emblem of glory. _And round about the throne were four and
            twenty seats_; answering to the chambers of the four and twenty Princes of
            the Priests, twelve on the south side, and twelve on the north side of the
            Priests Court. _And upon the seats were four and twenty Elders sitting,
            clothed in white rayment, with crowns on their heads_; representing the
            Princes of the four and twenty courses of the Priests clothed in linen.
            _And out of the throne proceeded lightnings and thunderings, and voices_,
            viz. the flashes of the fire upon the Altar at the morning-sacrifice, and
            the thundering voices of those that sounded the trumpets, and sung at the
            Eastern gate of the Priests Court; for these being between _John_ and the
            throne appeared to him as proceeding from the throne. _And there were seven
            lamps of fire burning_, in the Temple, _before the throne, which are the
            seven spirits of God_, or Angels of the seven Churches, represented in the
            beginning of this Prophecy by seven stars. _And before the throne was a sea
            of glass clear as chrystal_; the brazen sea between the porch of the Temple
            and the Altar, filled with clear water. _And in the midst of the throne,
            and round about the throne, were four Beasts full of eyes before and
            behind_: that is, one Beast before the throne and one behind it, appearing
            to _John_ as in the midst of the throne, and one on either side in the
            circle about it, to represent by the multitude of their eyes the people
            standing in the four sides of the peoples court. _And the first Beast was
            like a lion, and the second was like a calf, and the third had the face of
            a man, and the fourth was like a flying eagle_. The people of _Israel_ in
            the wilderness encamped round about the tabernacle, and on the east side
            were three tribes under the standard of _Judah_, on the west were three
            tribes under the standard of _Ephraim_, on the south were three tribes
            under the standard of _Reuben_, and on the north were three tribes under
            the standard of _Dan_, _Numb._ ii. And the standard of _Judah_ was a Lion,
            that of _Ephraim_ an Ox, that of _Reuben_ a Man, and that of _Dan_ an
            Eagle, as the _Jews_ affirm. Whence were framed the hieroglyphicks of
            _Cherubims_ and _Seraphims_, to represent the people of _Israel_. A
            _Cherubim_ had one body with four faces, the faces of a Lion, an Ox, a Man
            and an Eagle, looking to the four winds of heaven, without turning about,
            as in _Ezekiel_'s vision, chap. i. And four _Seraphims_ had the same four
            faces with four bodies, one face to every body. The four Beasts are
            therefore four _Seraphims_ standing in the four sides of the peoples court;
            the first in the eastern side with the head of a Lion, the second in the
            western side with the head of an Ox, the third in the southern side with
            the head of a Man, the fourth in the northern side with the head of an
            Eagle: and all four signify together the twelve tribes of _Israel_, out of
            whom the hundred forty and four thousand were sealed, _Apoc._ vii. 4. _And
            the four Beasts had each of them six wings_, two to a tribe, in all twenty
            and four wings, answering to the twenty and four stations of the people.
            _And they were full of eyes within_, or under their wings. _And they rest
            not day and night_, or at the morning and evening-sacrifices, _saying,
            holy, holy, holy Lord God Almighty, which was, and is, and is to come_.
            These animals are therefore the Seraphims, which appeared to _Isaiah_ [1]
            in a vision like this of the _Apocalypse_. For there also the Lord sat upon
            a throne in the temple; and the Seraphims each with six wings cried, _Holy,
            holy, holy Lord God of hosts. And when those animals give glory and honour
            and thanks to him that sitteth upon the throne, who liveth for ever and
            ever, the four and twenty Elders_ go into the Temple, and there _fall down
            before him that sitteth on the throne, and worship him that liveth for ever
            and ever, and cast their crowns before the throne, saying, Thou art worthy,
            O Lord, to receive glory and honour and power: for thou hast created all
            things, and for thy pleasure they are and were created_. At the morning and
            evening-sacrifices, so soon as the sacrifice was laid upon the Altar, and
            the drink-offering began to be poured out, the trumpets sounded, and the
            _Levites_ sang by course three times; and every time when the trumpets
            sounded, the people fell down and worshiped. Three times therefore did the
            people worship; to express which number, the Beasts cry _Holy, holy, holy_:
            and the song being ended, the people prayed standing, till the solemnity
            was finished. In the mean time the Priests went into the Temple, and there
            fell down before him that sat upon the throne, and worshiped.
          </p>
          <p id="98002008">
            _And _John_ saw, in the right hand of him that sat upon the throne, a book
            written within and on the backside, sealed with seven seals_, viz. the book
            which _Daniel_ was commanded to seal up, and which is here represented by
            the prophetic book of the Law laid up on the right side of the Ark, as it
            were in the right hand of him that sat on the throne: for the festivals and
            ceremonies of the Law prescribed to the people in this book, adumbrated
            those things which were predicted in the book of _Daniel_; and the writing
            within and on the backside of this book, relates to the synchronal
            Prophecies. [2] _And none was found worthy to open the book_ but the Lamb
            of God. _And lo, in the midst of the throne and of the four Beasts, and in
            the midst of the Elders_, that is, at the foot of the Altar, _stood a lamb
            as it had been slain_, the morning-sacrifice; _having seven horns_, which
            are the seven Churches, _and seven eyes, which are the seven spirits of God
            sent forth into all the earth. And he came, and took the book out of the
            right hand of him that sat upon the throne: And when he had taken the book,
            the four Beasts and four and twenty Elders fell down before the Lamb,
            having every one of them harps, and golden vials full of odours, which are
            the prayers of saints. And they sung a new song, saying, Thou art worthy to
            take the book, and to open the seals thereof: for thou wast slain, and hast
            redeemed us to God by thy blood out of every kindred, and tongue, and
            people, and nation; and hast made us, unto our God, Kings and Priests, and
            we shall reign on the earth._ The Beasts and Elders therefore represent the
            primitive _Christians_ of all nations; and the worship of these
            _Christians_ in their Churches is here represented under the form of
            worshiping God and the Lamb in the Temple: God for his benefaction in
            creating all things, and the Lamb for his benefaction in redeeming us with
            his blood: God as sitting upon the throne and living for ever, and the Lamb
            as exalted above all by the merits of his death. _And I heard_, saith
            _John_, _the voice of many Angels round about the throne, and the Beasts
            and the Elders: and the number of them was ten thousand times ten thousand,
            and thousands of thousands; saying with a loud voice, Worthy is the Lamb
            that was slain to receive power, and riches, and wisdom, and strength, and
            honour, and glory, and blessing. And every creature which is in heaven, and
            on the earth, and under the earth, and such as are in the sea, and all that
            are in them, heard I, saying, Blessing, honour, glory, and power, be unto
            him that sitteth upon the throne, and unto the Lamb for ever and ever. And
            the four Beasts said, _Amen_. And the four and twenty Elders fell down and
            worshiped him that liveth for ever and ever._ This was the worship of the
            primitive _Christians_.
          </p>
          <p id="98002009">
            It was the custom for the High-Priest, seven days before the fast of the
            seventh month, to continue constantly in the Temple, and study the book of
            the Law, that he might be perfect in it against the day of expiation;
            wherein the service, which was various and intricate, was wholly to be
            performed by himself; part of which service was reading the Law to the
            people: and to promote his studying it, there were certain Priests
            appointed by the _Sanhedrim_ to be with him those seven days in one of his
            chambers in the Temple, and there to discourse with him about the Law, and
            read it to him, and put him in mind of reading and studying it himself.
            This his opening and reading the Law those seven days, is alluded unto in
            the Lamb's opening the seals. We are to conceive that those seven days
            begin in the evening before each day; for the _Jews_ began their day in the
            evening, and that the solemnity of the fast begins in the morning of the
            seventh day.
          </p>
          <p id="98002010">
            The seventh seal was therefore opened on the day of expiation, and then
            _there was silence in heaven for half an hour. And an Angel_, the
            High-Priest, _stood at the Altar, having a golden Censer; and there was
            given him much incense, that he should offer it with the prayers of all
            Saints, upon the golden Altar which was before the throne_. The custom was
            on other days, for one of the Priests to take fire from the great Altar in
            a silver Censer; but on this day, for the High-Priest to take fire from the
            great Altar in a golden Censer: and when he was come down from the great
            Altar, he took incense from one of the Priests who brought it to him, and
            went with it to the golden Altar: and while he offered the incense, the
            people prayed without in silence, which is the silence in heaven for half
            an hour. When the High-Priest had laid the incense on the Altar, he carried
            a Censer of it burning in his hand, into the most holy place before the
            Ark. _And the smoke of the incense, with the prayers of the Saints,
            ascended up before God out of the Angel's hand._ On other days there was a
            certain measure of incense for the golden Altar: on this day there was a
            greater quantity for both the Altar and the most holy Place, and therefore
            it is called _much incense_. After this _the Angel took the Censer, and
            filled it with fire from the_ great _Altar, and cast it into the earth_;
            that is, by the hands of the Priests who belong to his mystical body, he
            cast it to the earth without the Temple, for burning the Goat which was the
            Lord's lot. _And_ at this and other concomitant sacrifices, until the
            evening-sacrifice was ended, _there were voices, and thundrings, and
            lightnings, and an earthquake_; that is, the voice of the High-Priest
            reading the Law to the people, and other voices and thundrings from the
            trumpets and temple-musick at the sacrifices, and lightnings from the fire
            of the Altar.
          </p>
          <p id="98002011">
            The solemnity of the day of expiation being finished, the seven Angels
            found their trumpets at the great sacrifices of the seven days of the feast
            of tabernacles; and at the same sacrifices, the seven thunders utter their
            voices, which are the musick of the Temple, and singing of the _Levites_,
            intermixed with the soundings of the trumpets: and the seven Angels pour
            out their vials of wrath, which are the drink-offerings of those
            sacrifices.
          </p>
          <p id="98002012">
            When six of the seals were opened, _John_ said: [3] _And after these
            things_, that is, after the visions of the sixth seal, _I saw four Angels
            standing on the four corners of the earth, holding the four winds of the
            earth, that the wind should not blow on the earth, nor on the sea, nor on
            any tree. And I saw another Angel ascending from the _East_, having the
            seal of the living God: and he cried with a loud voice to the four Angels,
            to whom it was given to hurt the earth and the sea, saying, Hurt not the
            earth, nor the sea, nor the trees, till we have sealed the servants of our
            God in their foreheads._ This sealing alludes to a tradition of the _Jews_,
            that upon the day of expiation all the people of _Israel_ are sealed up in
            the books of life and death. For the _Jews_ in their _Talmud_ [4] tell us,
            that in the beginning of every new year, or first day of the month _Tisri_,
            the seventh month of the sacred year, three books are opened in judgment;
            the book of life, in which the names of those are written who are perfectly
            just; the book of death, in which the names of those are written who are
            Atheists or very wicked; and a third book, of those whose judgment is
            suspended till the day of expiation, and whose names are not written in the
            book of life or death before that day. The first ten days of this month
            they call the penitential days; and all these days they fast and pray very
            much, and are very devout, that on the tenth day their sins may be
            remitted, and their names may be written in the book of life; which day is
            therefore called the day of expiation. And upon this tenth day, in
            returning home from the Synagogues, they say to one another, _God the
            creator seal you to a good year_. For they conceive that the books are now
            sealed up, and that the sentence of God remains unchanged henceforward to
            the end of the year. The same thing is signified by the two Goats, upon
            whose foreheads the High-Priest yearly, on the day of expiation, lays the
            two lots inscribed, _For God_ and _For _Azazel__; God's lot signifying the
            people who are sealed with the name of God in their foreheads; and the lot
            _Azazel_, which was sent into the wilderness, representing those who
            receive the mark and name of the Beast, and go into the wilderness with the
            great Whore.
          </p>
          <p id="98002013">
            The servants of God being therefore sealed in the day of expiation, we may
            conceive that this sealing is synchronal to the visions which appear upon
            opening the seventh seal; and that when the Lamb had opened six of the
            seals and seen the visions relating to the inside of the sixth, he looked
            on the backside of the seventh leaf, and then saw _the four Angels holding
            the four winds of heaven, and another Angel ascending from the _East_ with
            the seal of God_. Conceive also, that the Angels which held the four winds
            were the first four of the seven Angels, who upon opening the seventh seal
            were seen standing before God; and that upon their holding the winds,
            _there was silence in heaven for half an hour_; and that while the servants
            of God were sealing, the Angel with the golden Censer offered their prayers
            with incense upon the golden Altar, and read the Law: and that so soon as
            they were sealed, the winds hurt the earth at the sounding of the first
            trumpet, and the sea at the sounding of the second; these winds signifying
            the wars, to which the first four trumpets sounded. For as the first four
            seals are distinguished from the three last by the appearance of four
            horsemen towards the four winds of heaven; so the wars of the first four
            trumpets are distinguished from those of the three last, by representing
            these by _four winds_, and the others by _three great woes_.
          </p>
          <p id="98002014">
            In one of _Ezekiel_'s visions, when the _Babylonian_ captivity was at hand,
            _six men_ appeared _with slaughter-weapons_; _and a seventh_, who [5]
            appeared _among them clothed in white linen and a writer's ink-horn by his
            side_, is commanded to _go thro' the midst of _Jerusalem_, and set a mark
            upon the foreheads of the men that sigh and cry for all the abominations
            done in the midst thereof_: and then the six men, like the Angels of the
            first six trumpets, are commanded to slay those men who are not marked.
            Conceive therefore that the hundred forty and four thousand are sealed, to
            preserve them from the plagues of the first six trumpets; and that at
            length by the preaching of the everlasting gospel, they grow into _a great
            multitude, which no man could number, of all nations, and kindreds, and
            people and tongues_: and at the sounding of the seventh trumpet come out of
            the great tribulation _with Palms in their hands: the kingdoms of this
            world_, by the war to which that trumpet sounds, _becoming the kingdoms of
            God and his _Christ__. For the solemnity of the great _Hosannah_ was kept
            by the _Jews_ upon the seventh or last day of the feast of tabernacles; the
            _Jews_ upon that day carrying Palms in their hands, and crying _Hosannah_.
          </p>
          <p id="98002015">
            After six of the Angels, answering to the six men with slaughter-weapons,
            had sounded their trumpets, the Lamb in the form of _a mighty Angel cane
            down from heaven clothed with a cloud, and a rainbow was upon his head, and
            his face was as it were the Sun, and his feet as pillars of fire_, the
            shape in which _Christ_ appeared in the beginning of this Prophecy; _and he
            had in his hand a little book open_, the book which he had newly opened;
            for he received but one book from him that sitteth upon the throne, and he
            alone was worthy to open and look on this book. _And he set his right foot
            upon the sea and his left foot on the earth, and cried with a loud voice,
            as when a lion roareth_. It was the custom for the High-Priest on the day
            of expiation, to stand in an elevated place in the peoples court, at the
            Eastern gate of the Priests court, and read the Law to the people, while
            the Heifer and the Goat which was the Lord's lot, were burning without the
            Temple. We may therefore suppose him standing in such a manner, that his
            right foot might appear to _John_ as it were standing on the sea of glass,
            and his left foot on the ground of the house; and that he cried with a loud
            voice, in reading the Law on the day of expiation. _And when he had cried,
            seven thunders uttered their voices_. Thunders are the voice of a cloud,
            and a cloud signifies a multitude; and this multitude may be the _Levites_,
            who sang with thundering voices, and played with musical instruments at the
            great sacrifices, on the seven days of the feast of Tabernacles: at which
            times the trumpets also sounded. For the trumpets sounded, and the
            _Levites_ sang alternately, three times at every sacrifice. The Prophecy
            therefore of the seven thunders is nothing else than a repetition of the
            Prophecy of the seven trumpets in another form. _And the Angel which I saw
            stand upon the sea and upon the earth, lifted up his hand to heaven, and
            sware by him that liveth for ever and ever, that_ after the seven thunders
            _there should be time no longer; but in the days of the voice of the
            seventh Angel, when he shall begin to sound, the mystery of God should be
            finished, as he hath declared to his servants the Prophets_. The voices of
            the thunders therefore last to the end of this world, and so do those of
            the trumpets.
          </p>
          <p id="98002016">
            _And the voice which I heard from heaven_, saith _John_, _spake unto me
            again and said, Go and take the little book, &amp;c. And I took the little book
            out of the Angel's hand, and ate it up; and it was in my mouth sweet as
            honey, and as soon as I had eaten it, my belly was bitter. And he said unto
            me, Thou must prophesy again before many peoples, and nations, and tongues,
            and kings_. This is an introduction to a new Prophecy, to a repetition of
            the Prophecy of the whole book; and alludes to _Ezekiel_'s eating a roll or
            book spread open before him, and written within and without, full of
            lamentations and mourning and woe, but sweet in his mouth. Eating and
            drinking signify acquiring and possessing; and eating the book is becoming
            inspired with the Prophecy contained in it. It implies being inspired in a
            vigorous and extraordinary manner with the Prophecy of the whole book, and
            therefore signifies a lively repetition of the whole Prophecy by way of
            interpretation, and begins not till the first Prophecy, that of the seals
            and trumpets, is ended. It was sweet in _John_'s mouth, and therefore
            begins not with the bitter Prophecy of the _Babylonian_ captivity, and the
            _Gentiles_ being in the outward court of the Temple, and treading the holy
            city under foot; and the prophesying of the _two Witnesses_ in sackcloth,
            and their smiting the earth with all plagues, and being killed by the
            Beast; but so soon as the Prophecy of the trumpets is ended, it begins with
            the sweet Prophecy of the glorious _Woman in heaven_, and the victory of
            _Michael_ over the Dragon; and after that, it is bitter in _John_'s belly,
            by a large description of the times of the great Apostacy.
          </p>
          <p id="98002017">
            _And the Angel stood_, upon the earth and sea, _saying, Rise and measure
            the Temple of God and the Altar, and them that worship therein_, that is,
            their courts with the buildings thereon, viz. the square court of the
            Temple called the separate place, and the square court of the Altar called
            the Priests court, and the court of them that worship in the Temple called
            the new court: _but the_ great _court which is without the Temple, leave
            out, and measure it not, for it is given to the _Gentiles_, and the holy
            city shall they tread under foot forty and two months_. This measuring hath
            reference to _Ezekiel_'s measuring the Temple _of Solomon_: there the whole
            Temple, including the outward court, was measured, to signify that it
            should be rebuilt in the latter days. Here the courts of the Temple and
            Altar, and they who worship therein, are only measured, to signify the
            building of a second Temple, for those that are sealed out of all the
            twelve tribes of _Israel_, and worship in the inward court of sincerity and
            truth: but _John_ is commanded to leave out the outward court, or outward
            form of religion and Church-government, because it is given to the
            _Babylonian Gentiles_. For the glorious woman in heaven, the remnant of
            whole seed kept the commandments of God, and had the testimony of _Jesus_,
            continued the same woman in outward form after her flight into the
            wilderness, whereby she quitted her former sincerity and piety, and became
            the great Whore. She lost her chastity, but kept her outward form and
            shape. And while the _Gentiles_ tread the holy city underfoot, and worship
            in the outward court, the two witnesses, represented perhaps by the two
            feet of the Angel standing on the sea and earth, prophesied against them,
            and _had power_, like _Elijah_ and _Moses_, _to consume their enemies with
            fire proceeding out of their mouth, and to shut heaven that it rain not in
            the days of their Prophecy, and to turn the waters into blood, and to smite
            the earth with all plagues as often as they will_, that is, with the
            plagues of the trumpets and vials of wrath; and at length they are slain,
            rise again from the dead, and ascend up to heaven in a cloud; and then the
            seventh trumpet sounds to the day of judgment.
          </p>
          <p id="98002018">
            The Prophecy being finished, _John_ is inspired anew by the eaten book, and
            begins the Interpretation thereof with these words, _And the Temple of God
            was opened in heaven, and there was seen in his Temple the Ark of the
            Testament_. By the Ark, we may know that this was the first Temple; for the
            second Temple had no Ark. _And there were lightnings, and voices, and
            thundrings, and an earthquake, and great hail_. These answer to the wars in
            the _Roman_ Empire, during the reign of the four horsemen, who appeared
            upon opening the first four seals. _And there appeared a great wonder in
            heaven, a woman clothed with the Sun_. In the Prophecy, the affairs of the
            Church begin to be considered at the opening of the fifth seal; and in the
            Interpretation, they begin at the same time with the vision of the Church
            in the form of a woman in heaven: there she is persecuted, and here she is
            pained in travail. The Interpretation proceeds down first to the sealing of
            the servants of God, and marking the rest with the mark of the Beast; and
            then to the day of judgment, represented by a harvest and vintage. Then it
            returns back to the times of opening the seventh seal, and interprets the
            Prophecy of the seven trumpets by the pouring out of seven vials of wrath.
            The Angels who pour them out, come out of the _Temple of the Tabernacle_;
            that is, out of the second Temple, for the Tabernacle had no outward court.
            Then it returns back again to the times of measuring the Temple and Altar,
            and of the _Gentiles_ worshiping in the outward court, and of the Beast
            killing the witnesses in the streets of the great city; and interprets
            these things by the vision of _a woman sitting on the Beast, drunken with
            the blood of the Saints_; and proceeds in the interpretation downwards to
            the fall of the great city and the day of judgment.
          </p>
          <p id="98002019">
            The whole Prophecy of the book, represented by the book of the Law, is
            therefore repeated, and interpreted in the visions which follow those of
            sounding the seventh trumpet, and begin with that of the Temple of God
            opened in heaven. Only the things, which the seven thunders uttered, were
            not written down, and therefore not interpreted.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. II.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.2.1">Isa. vi.</note>
            <note id="n.1.2.2">Apoc. v.</note>
            <note id="n.1.2.3">Apoc. vii</note>
            <note id="n.1.2.4">Buxtorf in Synogoga Judaica, c. 18, 21.</note>
            <note id="n.1.2.5">Ezek. ix.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
