<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.2.3" type="chapter" id="98003">
          <head>CHAP. III.</head>
          <head>Of the relation which the Prophecy of _John_ hath to those of _Daniel_; and of the
            Subject
            of the Prophecy.</head>
          <p id="98003002">
            The whole scene of sacred Prophecy is composed of three principal parts:
            the regions beyond _Euphrates_, represented by the two first Beasts of
            _Daniel_; the Empire of the _Greeks_ on this side of _Euphrates_,
            represented by the Leopard and by the He-Goat; and the Empire of the
            _Latins_ on this side of _Greece_, represented by the Beast with ten horns.
            And to these three parts, the phrases of the _third part of the earth, sea,
            rivers, trees, ships, stars, sun, and moon_, relate. I place the body of
            the fourth Beast on this side of _Greece_, because the three first of the
            four Beasts had their lives prolonged after their dominion was taken away,
            and therefore belong not to the body of the fourth. He only stamped them
            with his feet.
          </p>
          <p id="98003003">
            By the _earth_, the _Jews_ understood the great continent of all _Asia_ and
            _Africa_, to which they had access by land: and by the Isles of the _sea_,
            they understood the places to which they sailed by sea, particularly all
            _Europe_: and hence in this Prophecy, the _earth_ and _sea_ are put for the
            nations of the _Greek_ and _Latin_ Empires.
          </p>
          <p id="98003004">
            The third and fourth Beasts of _Daniel_ are the same with the Dragon and
            ten-horned Beast of _John_, but with this difference: _John_ puts the
            Dragon for the whole _Roman_ Empire while it continued entire, because it
            was entire when that Prophecy was given; and the Beast he considers not
            till the Empire became divided: and then he puts the Dragon for the Empire
            of the _Greeks_, and the Beast for the Empire of the _Latins_. Hence it is
            that the Dragon and Beast have common heads and common horns: but the
            Dragon hath crowns only upon his heads, and the Beast only upon his horns;
            because the Beast and his horns reigned not before they were divided from
            the Dragon: and when the Dragon gave the Beast his throne, the ten horns
            received power as Kings, the same hour with the Beast. The heads are seven
            successive Kings. Four of them were the four horsemen which appeared at the
            opening of the first four seals. In the latter end of the sixth head, or
            seal, considered as present in the visions, it is said, _five_ of the seven
            Kings _are fallen, and one is, and another is not yet come; and the Beast
            that was and is not_, being wounded to death with a sword, _he is the
            eighth, and of the seven_: he was therefore a collateral part of the
            seventh. The horns are the same with those of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast,
            described above.
          </p>
          <p id="98003005">
            The four horsemen which appear at the opening of the first four seals, have
            been well explained by Mr. _Mede_; excepting that I had rather continue the
            third to the end of the reign of the three _Gordians_ and _Philip_ the
            _Arabian_, those being Kings from the _South_, and begin the fourth with
            the reign of _Decius_, and continue it till the reign of _Dioclesian_. For
            the fourth horseman _sat upon a pale_ horse, _and his name was Death; and
            hell followed with him; and power was given them to kill unto the fourth
            part of the earth, with the sword, and with famine, and with the plague,
            and with the Beasts of the earth_, or armies of invaders and rebels: and as
            such were the times during all this interval. Hitherto the _Roman_ Empire
            continued in an undivided monarchical form, except rebellions; and such it
            is represented by the four horsemen. But _Dioclesian_ divided it between
            himself and _Maximianus_, A.C. 285; and it continued in that divided state,
            till the victory of _Constantine_ the great over _Licinius_, A.C. 323,
            which put an end to the heathen persecutions set on foot by _Dioclesian_
            and _Maximianus_, and described at the opening of the fifth seal. But this
            division of the Empire was imperfect, the whole being still under one and
            the same Senate. The same victory of _Constantine_ over _Licinius_ a
            heathen persecutor, began the fall of the heathen Empire, described at the
            opening of the sixth seal: and the visions of this seal continue till after
            the reign of _Julian_ the Apostate, he being a heathen Emperor, and
            reigning over the whole _Roman_ Empire.
          </p>
          <p id="98003006">
            The affairs of the Church begin to be considered at the opening of the
            fifth seal, as was said above. Then she is represented by _a woman_ in the
            Temple of heaven, _clothed with the sun_ of righteousness, _and the moon_
            of _Jewish_ ceremonies _under her feet, and upon her head a crown of twelve
            stars_ relating to the twelve Apostles and to the twelve tribes of
            _Israel_. When she fled from the Temple into the wilderness, she left in
            the Temple a _remnant of her seed, who kept the commandments of God, and
            had the testimony of Jesus Christ_; and therefore before her flight she
            represented the true primitive Church of God, tho afterwards she
            degenerated like _Aholah_ and _Aholibah_. In _Diocesian_'s persecution _she
            cried, travelling in birth, and pained to be delivered_. And in the end of
            that persecution, by the victory of _Constantine_ over _Maxentius_ A.C.
            312, _she brought forth a man-child_, such a child as _was to rule all
            nations with a rod of iron_, a _Christian_ Empire. _And her child_, by the
            victory of _Constantine_ over _Licinius_, A.C. 323, _was caught up unto God
            and to his throne. And the woman_, by the division of the _Roman_ Empire
            into the _Greek_ and _Latin_ Empires, _fled_ from the first Temple _into
            the wilderness_, or spiritually barren Empire of the _Latins_, where she is
            found afterwards sitting upon the Beast and upon the seven mountains; and
            is called _the great city which reigneth over the Kings of the earth_, that
            is, over the ten Kings who give their kingdom to her Beast.
          </p>
          <p id="98003007">
            But before her flight there was war in heaven between _Michael_ and the
            Dragon, the _Christian_ and the heathen religions; and the Dragon, _that
            old serpent, called the Devil and Satan, who deceiveth the whole world, was
            cast out to the earth, and his Angels were cast out with him_. And _John
            heard a voice in heaven, saying, Now is come salvation and strength, and
            the kingdom of our God, and the power of his _Christ_: for the accuser of
            our brethren is cast down. And they overcame him by the blood of the Lamb,
            and by the word of their testimony. And they loved not their lives unto the
            death. Therefore rejoice, ye heavens, and ye that dwell in them. Woe be to
            the inhabiters of the earth and sea_, or people of the _Greek_ and _Latin_
            Empires, _for the devil is come down amongst you, having great wrath,
            because he knoweth that he hath but a short time_.
          </p>
          <p id="98003008">
            _And when the Dragon saw that he was cast down_ from the _Roman_ throne,
            and the man-child caught up thither, he _persecuted the woman which brought
            forth the man-child; and to her_, by the division of the _Roman_ Empire
            between the cities of _Rome_ and _Constantinople_ A.C. 330, _were given two
            wings of a great eagle_, the symbol of the _Roman_ Empire, _that she might
            flee_ from the first Temple _into the wilderness_ of _Arabia, to her place_
            at _Babylon_ mystically so called. _And the serpent_, by the division of
            the same Empire between the sons of _Constantine_ the great, A.C. 337,
            _cast out of his mouth water as a flood_, the _Western_ Empire, _after the
            woman; that he might cause her to be carried away by the flood. And the
            earth_, or _Greek_ Empire, _helped the woman, and the earth opened her
            mouth, and swallowed up the flood_, by the victory of _Constantius_ over
            _Magnentius_, A.C. 353, and thus the Beast was wounded to death with a
            sword. _And the Dragon was wroth with the woman_, in the reign of _Julian_
            the Apostate A.C. 361, _and_, by a new division of the Empire between
            _Valentinian_ and _Valens_, A.C. 364, _went_ from her into the _Eastern_
            Empire _to make war with the remnant of her seed_, which she left behind
            her when she fled: and thus the Beast revived. By the next division of the
            Empire, which was between _Gratian_ and _Theodosius_ A.C. 379, the _Beast_
            with ten horns _rose out of the sea_, and the _Beast_ with two horns _out
            of the earth_: and by the last division thereof, which was between the sons
            of _Theodosius_, A.C. 395, _the Dragon gave the Beast his power and throne,
            and great authority_. And the ten horns _received power as Kings, the same
            hour with the Beast_.
          </p>
          <p id="98003009">
            At length the woman arrived at her place of temporal as well as spiritual
            dominion upon the back of the Beast, where she is nourished _a time, and
            times, and half a time, from the face of the serpent_; not in his kingdom,
            but at a distance from him. She is nourished by _the merchants of the
            earth_, three times or years and an half, or 42 months, or 1260 days: and
            in these Prophecies days are put for years. During all this time the Beast
            acted, and _she sat upon him_, that is, reigned over him, and over the ten
            Kings _who gave their power and strength_, that is, their kingdom _to the
            Beast_; and she was _drunken with the blood of the Saints_. By all these
            circumstances she is the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast, who
            reigned with _a look more stout than his fellows_, and was of a different
            kind from the rest, and had eyes _and a mouth_ like the woman; _and made
            war with the saints, and prevailed against them_, and _wore them out_, and
            _thought to change times and laws_, and had them _given into his hand,
            until a time, and times, and half a time_. These characters of the woman,
            and little horn of the Beast, agree perfectly: in respect of her temporal
            dominion, she was a horn of the Beast; in respect of her spiritual
            dominion, she rode upon him in the form of a woman, and was his Church, and
            committed fornication with the ten Kings.
          </p>
          <p id="98003010">
            The second Beast, which _rose up out of the earth_, was the Church of the
            _Greek_ Empire: for it _had two horns like those of the Lamb_, and
            therefore was a Church; and it _spake as the Dragon_, and therefore was of
            his religion; and it _came up out of the earth_, and by consequence in his
            kingdom. It is called also _the false Prophet_ who wrought miracles before
            the first Beast, by which he deceived them that received his mark, and
            worshiped his image. When the Dragon went from the woman to make war with
            the remnant of her seed, this Beast arising out of the earth assisted in
            that war, and _caused the earth and them which dwell therein to worship_
            the authority of _the first Beast, whose mortal wound was healed_, and to
            _make an Image to him_, that is, to assemble a body of men like him in
            point of religion. He had also _power to give life_ and authority _to the
            Image_, so that it could _both speak, and_ by dictating _cause that all_
            religious bodies of men, _who would not worship_ the authority of _the
            Image, should be_ mystically _killed. And he causeth all men to receive a
            mark in their right hand or in their forehead, and that no man might buy or
            sell save he that had the mark, or the name of the Beast, or the number of
            his name_; all the rest being excommunicated by the Beast with two horns.
            His mark is [Cross] [Cross] [Cross], and his name [Greek: LATEINOS], and
            the number of his name 666.
          </p>
          <p id="98003011">
            Thus the Beast, after he was wounded to death with a sword and revived, was
            deified, as the heathens used to deify their Kings after death, and had an
            Image erected to him; and his worshipers were initiated in this new
            religion, by receiving the mark or name of this new God, or the number of
            his name. By killing all that will not worship him and his Image, the first
            Temple, illuminated by the lamps of the seven Churches, is demolished, and
            a new Temple built for them who will not worship him; and the outward court
            of this new Temple, or outward form of a Church, is given to the
            _Gentiles_, who worship the Beast and his Image: while they who will not
            worship him, are sealed with the name of God in their foreheads, and retire
            into the inward court of this new Temple. These are the 144000 sealed out
            of all the twelve tribes of _Israel_, and called the _two Witnesses_, as
            being derived from the two wings of the woman while she was flying into the
            wilderness, and represented by two of the seven candlesticks. These appear
            to _John_ in the inward court of the second Temple, standing on mount
            _Sion_ with the Lamb, and as it were on the sea of glass. These are _the
            Saints of the most High_, and _the host of heaven_, and _the holy people_
            spoken of by _Daniel_, as worn out and trampled under foot, and destroyed
            in the latter times by the little horns of his fourth Beast and He-Goat.
          </p>
          <p id="98003012">
            While the _Gentiles_ tread the holy city under foot, God _gives power to
            his two Witnesses, and they prophesy a thousand two hundred and threescore
            days clothed in sackcloth_. They are called _the two Olive-trees_, with
            relation to the two Olive-trees, which in _Zechary_'s vision, chap. iv.
            stand on either side of the golden candlestick to supply the lamps with
            oil: and Olive-trees, according to the Apostle _Paul_, represent Churches,
            _Rom._ xi. They supply the lamps with oil, by maintaining teachers. They
            are also called _the two candlesticks_; which in this Prophecy signify
            Churches, the seven Churches of _Asia_ being represented by seven
            candlesticks. Five of these Churches were found faulty, and threatned if
            they did not repent; the other two were without fault, and so their
            candlesticks were fit to be placed in the second Temple. These were the
            Churches in _Smyrna_ and _Philadelphia_. They were in a state of
            tribulation and persecution, and the only two of the seven in such a state:
            and so their candlesticks were fit to represent the Churches in affliction
            in the times of the second Temple, and the only two of the seven that were
            fit. The _two Witnesses_ are not new Churches: they are the posterity of
            the primitive Church, the posterity of the two wings of the woman, and so
            are fitly represented by two of the primitive candlesticks. We may conceive
            therefore, that when the first Temple was destroyed, and a new one built
            for them who worship in the inward court, two of the seven candlesticks
            were placed in this new Temple.
          </p>
          <p id="98003013">
            The affairs of the Church are not considered during the opening of the
            first four seals. They begin to be consider'd at the opening of the fifth
            seal, as was said above; and are further considered at the opening of the
            sixth seal; and the seventh seal contains the times of the great Apostacy.
            And therefore I refer the Epistles to the seven Churches unto the times of
            the fifth and sixth seals: for they relate to the Church when she began to
            decline, and contain admonitions against the great Apostacy then
            approaching.
          </p>
          <p id="98003014"> When _Eusebius_ had brought down his _Ecclesiatical History_ to the reign of
            _Dioclesian_, he thus describes the state of the Church: <q lang="lat">_Qualem
              quantamque gloriam simul ac libertatem doctrina veræ erga supremum Deum
              pietatis à Christo primùm hominibus annunciata, apud omnes Græcos pariter &amp;
            barbaros ante persecutionem nostrâ memoriâ excitatam, consecuta sit, nos
              certè pro merito explicare non possumus. Argumento esse possit Imperatorum
              benignitas erga nostros: quibus regendas etiam provincias committebant,
              omni sacrificandi metu eos liberantes ob singularem, qua in religionem
              nostram affecti erant, benevolentiam._ And a little after: _Jam vero quis
              innumerabilem hominum quotidiè ad fidem Christi confugientium turbam, quis
              numerum ecclesiarum in singulis urbibus, quis illustres populorum concursus
              in ædibus sacris, cumulatè possit describere? Quo factum est, ut priscis
              ædificiis jam non contenti, in singulis urbibus spatiosas ab ipsis
              fundamentis exstruerent ecclesias. Atque hæc progressii temporis
              increscentia, &amp; quotidiè in majus &amp; melius proficiscentia, nec livor ullus
            atterere, nec malignitas dæmonis fascinare, nec hominum insidiæ prohibere
              unquam potuerunt, quamdiu omnipotentis Dei dextra populum suum, utpote tali
              dignum præsidio, texit atque custodiit. Sed cum ex nimia libertate in
              negligentiam ac desidiam prolapsi essemus; cum alter alteri invidere atque
              obtrectare cæpisset; cum inter nos quasi bella intestina gereremus, verbis,
              tanquam armis quibusdam hastisque, nos mutuò vulnerantes; cum Antistites
              adversus Antistites, populi in populos collisi, jurgia ac tumultus
              agitarent; denique cum fraus &amp; simulatio ad summum malitiæ culmen
              adolevisset: tum divina ultio, levi brachio ut solet, integro adhuc
              ecclesiæ statu, &amp; fidelium turbis liberè convenientibus, sensim ac moderatè
              in nos cæpit animadvertere; orsà primùm persecutione ab iis qui militabant.
              Cum verò sensu omni destituti de placando Dei numine ne cogitaremus quidem;
              quin potius instar impiorum quorundam res humanas nullâ providentiâ
              gubernari rati, alia quotidiè crimina aliis adjiceremus: cum Pastores
              nostri spretâ religionis regulâ, mutuis inter se contentionibus
              decertarent, nihil aliud quam jurgia, minas, æmulationem, odia, ac mutuas
              inimicitias amplificare studentes; principatum quasi tyrannidem quandam
              contentissimè sibi vindicantes: tunc demùm juxta dictum Hieremiæ,
              _obscuravit Dominus in ira sua filiam Sion, &amp; dejecit de cælo gloriam
              Israel_,--per Ecclesiarum scilicet subversionem_, &amp;c. </q>This was the state of
            the Church just before the subversion of the Churches in the beginning of _Dioclesian_'s
            persecution: and to this state of the Church agrees the first of the seven Epistles to
            the Angel of the seven Churches, [1] that to the Church in _Ephesus_. _I have something
            against thee_, saith _Christ_ to the Angel of that Church, _because thou hast left thy
            first love. Remember therefore from whence thou art fallen, and repent, and do the first
            works; or else I will come unto thee quickly, and will remove thy candlestick out of its
            place, except thou repent. But this thou hast, that thou hatest the deeds of the
            _Nicolaitans_, which I also hate_. The _Nicolaitans_ are the _Continentes_ above
            described, who placed religion in abstinence from marriage, abandoning their wives if
            they had any. They are here called _Nicolaitans_, from _Nicolas_ one of the seven
            deacons of the primitive Church of _Jerusalem_; who having a beautiful wife, and being
            taxed with uxoriousness, abandoned her, and permitted her to marry whom she pleased,
            saying that we must disuse the flesh; and thenceforward lived a single life in
            continency, as his children also. The _Continentes_ afterwards embraced the doctrine of
            _Æons_ and Ghosts male and female, and were avoided by the Churches till the fourth
            century; and the Church of _Ephesus_ is here commended for hating their deeds. </p>
          <p id="98003015">
            The persecution of _Dioclesian_ began in the year of _Christ_ 302, and
            lasted ten years in the _Eastern_ Empire and two years in the _Western_. To
            this state of the Church the second Epistle, to the Church of _Smyrna_,
            agrees. _I know_, saith [2] _Christ_, _thy works, and tribulation, and
            poverty, but thou art rich; and I know the blasphemy of them, which say
            they are _Jews_ and are not, but are the synagogue of Satan. Fear none of
            those things which thou shalt suffer: Behold, the Devil shall call some of
            you into prison, that ye may be tried; and ye shall have tribulation ten
            days. Be thou faithful unto death, and I will give thee a crown of life._
            The tribulation of ten days can agree to no other persecution than that of
            _Dioclesian_, it being the only persecution which lasted ten years. By _the
            blasphemy of them which say they are _Jews_ and are not, but are the
            synagogue of Satan_, I understand the Idolatry of the _Nicolaitans_, who
            falsly said they were _Christians_.
          </p>
          <p id="98003016">
            The _Nicolaitans_ are complained of also in [3] the third Epistle, as men
            that _held the doctrine of _Balaam_, who taught _Balac_ to cast a
            stumbling-block before the children of _Israel_, to eat things sacrificed
            to Idols, and [4] to commit_ spiritual _fornication_. For _Balaam_ taught
            the _Moabites_ and _Midianites_ to tempt and invite _Israel_ by their women
            to commit fornication, and to feast with them at the sacrifices of their
            Gods. The Dragon therefore began now to come down among the inhabitants of
            the earth and sea.
          </p>
          <p id="98003017">
            The _Nicolaitans_ are also complained of in the fourth Epistle, under the
            name of the _woman _Jezabel_, who calleth herself a Prophetess, to teach
            and to seduce the servants of _Christ_ to commit fornication, and to eat
            things sacrificed to Idols_. The woman therefore began now to fly into the
            wilderness.
          </p>
          <p id="98003018">
            The reign of _Constantine_ the great from the time of his conquering
            _Licinius_, was monarchical over the whole _Roman_ Empire. Then the Empire
            became divided between the sons of _Constantine_: and afterwards it was
            again united under _Constantius_, by his victory over _Magnentius_. To the
            affairs of the Church in these three successive periods of time, the third,
            fourth, and fifth Epistles, that is, those to the Angels of the Churches in
            _Pergamus_, _Thyatira_, and _Sardis_, seem to relate. The next Emperor was
            _Julian_ the Apostate.
          </p>
          <p id="98003019">
            In the sixth Epistle, [5] to the Angel of the Church in _Philadelphia_,
            _Christ_ saith: _Because_ in the reign of the heathen Emperor _Julian_,
            _thou hast kept the word of my patience, I also will keep thee from the
            hour of temptation, which_ by the woman's flying into the wilderness, and
            the Dragon's making war with the remnant of her seed, and the killing of
            all who will not worship the Image of the Beast, _shall come upon all the
            world, to try them that dwell upon the earth_, and to distinguish them by
            sealing the one with the name of God in their foreheads, and marking the
            other with the mark of the Beast. _Him that overcometh, I will make a
            pillar in the Temple of my God; and he shall go no more out_ of it. _And I
            will write upon him the name of my God_ in his forehead. So the
            _Christians_ of the Church of _Philadelphia_, as many of them as overcome,
            are sealed with the seal of God, and placed in the second Temple, and go no
            more out. The same is to be understood of the Church in _Smyrna_, which
            also kept the word of God's patience, and was without fault. These two
            Churches, with their posterity, are therefore the _two Pillars_, and the
            _two Candlesticks_, and the _two Witnesses_ in the second Temple.
          </p>
          <p id="98003020">
            After the reign of the Emperor _Julian,_ and his successor _Jovian_ who
            reigned but five months, the Empire became again divided between
            _Valentinian_ and _Valens_. Then the Church Catholick, in the Epistle to
            the Angel of the Church of _Laodicea_, is reprehended as _lukewarm_, and
            [6] threatned to be _spewed out of _Christ's_ mouth_. She said, that she
            was _rich and increased with goods, and had need of nothing_, being in
            outward prosperity; _and knew not that she was_ inwardly _wretched, and
            miserable, and poor, and blind, and naked_. She is therefore _spewed out of
            _Christ's_ mouth_ at the opening of the seventh seal: and this puts an end
            to the times of the first Temple.
          </p>
          <p id="98003021"> About one half of the _Roman_ Empire turned _Christians_ in the time of _Constantine_
            the great and his sons. After _Julian_ had opened the Temples, and restored the worship
            of the heathens, the Emperors _Valentinian_ and _Valens_ tolerated it all their reign;
            and therefore the Prophecy of the sixth seal was not fully accomplished before the reign
            of their successor _Gratian_. It was the custom of the heathen Priests, in the beginning
            of the reign of every sovereign Emperor, to offer him the dignity and habit of the
            _Pontifex Maximus_. This dignity all Emperors had hitherto accepted: but _Gratian_
            rejected it, threw down the idols, interdicted the sacrifices, and took away their
            revenues with the salaries and authority of the Priests. _Theodosius_ the great followed
            his example; and heathenism afterwards recovered itself no more, but decreased so fast,
            that _Prudentius_, about ten years after the death of _Theodosius_, called the heathens,
            _vix pauca ingenia &amp; pars hominum rarissima_. Whence the affairs of the sixth seal
            ended with the reign of _Valens_, or rather with the beginning of the reign of
            _Theodosius_, when he, like his predecessor _Gratian_, rejected the dignity of _Pontifex
            Maximus_. For the _Romans_ were very much infested by the invasions of foreign nations
            in the reign of _Valentinian_ and _Valens_: <q lang="lat">_Hoc tempore_, saith
            _Ammianus_, _velut per
              universum orbem Romanum bellicum canentibus buccinis, excitæ gentes
              sævissimæ limites sibi proximos persultabant: Gallias Rhætiasque simul
              Alemanni populabantur: Sarmatæ Pannonias &amp; Quadi: Picti, Saxones, &amp; Scoti
            &amp;
              Attacotti Britannos ærumnis vexavere continuis: Austoriani, Mauricæque aliæ
              gentes Africam solito acriùs incursabant: Thracias diripiebant prædatorii
              globi Gotthorum: Persarum Rex manus Armeniis injectabat_.</q> And whilst the Emperors
            were busy in repelling these enemies, the _Hunns_ and _Alans_ and _Goths_ came over the
            _Danube_ in two bodies, overcame and slew _Valens_, and made so great a slaughter of the
            _Roman_ army, that _Ammianus_ saith: _Nec ulla Annalibus præter Cannensem ita ad
            internecionem res legitur gesta_. These wars were not fully stopt on all sides till the
            beginning of the reign of _Theodosius_, A.C. 379 &amp; 380: but thenceforward the Empire
            remained quiet from foreign armies, till his death, A.C. 395. So long the four winds
            were held: and so long there was silence in heaven. And the seventh seal was opened when
            this silence began. </p>
          <p id="98003022">
            Mr. _Mede_ hath explained the Prophecy of the first six trumpets not much
            amiss: but if he had observed, that the Prophecy of pouring out the vials
            of wrath is synchronal to that of sounding the trumpets, his explanation
            would have been yet more complete.
          </p>
          <p id="98003023">
            The name of _Woes_ is given to the wars to which the three last trumpets
            sound, to distinguish them from the wars of the four first. The sacrifices
            on the first four days of the feast of Tabernacles, at which the first four
            trumpets sound, and the first four vials of wrath are poured out, are
            slaughters in four great wars; and these wars are represented by four winds
            from the four corners of the earth. The first was an east wind, the second
            a west wind, the third a south wind, and the fourth a north wind, with
            respect to the city of _Rome_, the metropolis of the old _Roman_ Empire.
            These four plagues fell upon _the third part of the Earth, Sea, Rivers,
            Sun, Moon and Stars_; that is, upon the Earth, Sea, Rivers, Sun, Moon and
            Stars of the third part of the whole scene of these Prophecies of _Daniel_
            and _John_.
          </p>
          <p id="98003024">
            The plague of the eastern wind [7] at the sounding of the first trumpet,
            was to fall upon the _Earth_, that is, upon the nations of the _Greek_
            Empire. Accordingly, after the death of _Theodosius_ the great, the
            _Goths_, _Sarmatians_, _Hunns_, _Isaurians_, and _Austorian_ Moors invaded
            and miserably wasted _Greece_, _Thrace_, _Asia minor_, _Armenia_, _Syria_,
            _Egypt_, _Lybia_, and _Illyricum_, for ten or twelve years together.
          </p>
          <p id="98003025">
            The plague of the western wind at the sounding of the second trumpet, was
            to fall upon the _Sea_, or _Western_ Empire, by means of _a great mountain
            burning with fire_ cast into it, and _turning it to blood_. Accordingly in
            the year 407, that Empire began to be invaded by the _Visigoths_,
            _Vandals_, _Alans_, _Sueves_, _Burgundians_, _Ostrogoths_, _Heruli_,
            _Quadi_, _Gepides_; and by these wars it was broken into ten kingdoms, and
            miserably wasted: and _Rome_ itself, the burning mountain, was besieged and
            taken by the _Ostrogoths_, in the beginning of these miseries.
          </p>
          <p id="98003026">
            The plague of the southern wind at the sounding of the third trumpet, was
            to cause _a great star, burning as it were a lamp, to fall from heaven upon
            the rivers and fountains of waters_, the _Western_ Empire now divided into
            many kingdoms, and to turn them to _wormwood_ and _blood_, and make them
            _bitter_. Accordingly _Genseric_, the King of the _Vandals_ and _Alans_ in
            _Spain_, A.C. 427, enter'd _Africa_ with an army of eighty thousand men;
            where he invaded the _Moors_, and made war upon the _Romans_, both there
            and on the sea-coasts of _Europe_, for fifty years together, almost without
            intermission, taking _Hippo_ A.C. 431, and _Carthage_ the capital of
            _Africa_ A.C. 439. In A.C. 455, with a numerous fleet and an army of three
            hundred thousand _Vandals_ and _Moors_, he invaded _Italy_, took and
            plundered _Rome_, _Naples_, _Capua_, and many other cities; carrying thence
            their wealth with the flower of the people into _Africa_: and the next
            year, A.C. 456, he rent all _Africa_ from the Empire, totally expelling the
            _Romans_. Then the _Vandals_ invaded and took the Islands of the
            _Mediterranean_, _Sicily_, _Sardinia_, _Corsica_, _Ebusus_, _Majorca_,
            _Minorca_, &amp;c. and _Ricimer_ besieged the Emperer _Anthemius_ in _Rome_,
            took the city, and gave his soldiers the plunder, A.C. 472. The _Visigoths_
            about the same time drove the _Romans_ out of _Spain_: and now the
            _Western_ Emperor, the _great star which fell from heaven, burning as it
            were a lamp_, having by all these wars gradually lost almost all his
            dominions, was invaded, and conquered in one year by _Odoacer_ King of the
            _Heruli_, A.C. 476. After this the _Moors_ revolted A.C. 477, and weakned
            the _Vandals_ by several wars, and took _Mauritania_ from them. These wars
            continued till the _Vandals_ were conquered by _Belisarius_, A.C. 534. and
            by all these wars _Africa_ was almost depopulated, according to
            _Procopius_, who reckons that above five millions of men perished in them.
            When the _Vandals_ first invaded _Africa_, that country was very populous,
            consisting of about 700 bishopricks, more than were in all _France_,
            _Spain_ and _Italy_ together: but by the wars between the _Vandals_,
            _Romans_ and _Moors_, it was depopulated to that degree, that _Procopius_
            tells us, it was next to a miracle for a traveller to see a man.
          </p>
          <p id="98003027">
            In pouring out the third vial it is [8] said: _Thou art righteous, O
            Lord,--because thou hast judged thus: for they have shed the blood of thy
            Saints and Prophets, and thou hast given them blood to drink, for they are
            worthy_. How they shed the blood of Saints, may be understood by the
            following Edict of the Emperor _Honorius_, procured by four Bishops sent to
            him by a Council of _African_ Bishops, who met at _Carthage_ 14 _June_,
            A.C. 410.
          </p>
          <q lang="lat">
            <head>_Impp. Honor. &amp;. Theod. AA. Heracliano Com. Afric._</head>
            <p id="98003028"> _Oraculo penitus remoto, quo ad ritus suos hæreticæ superstitionis abrepserant,
              sciant omnes sanctæ legis inimici, plectendos se poena &amp; proscriptionis &amp;
              sanguinis,
              si ultra convenire per publicum, execrandâ sceleris sui temeritate temptaverint. Dat.
              _viii._
              Kal. Sept. Varano V.C. Cons._ A.C. 410.</p>
          </q>
          <p id="98003029">
            Which Edict was five years after fortified by the following.
          </p>
          <q lang="xml">
            <head>_Impp. Honor. &amp; Theod. AA. Heracliano Com. Afric._</head>
            <p id="98003030">
              _Sciant cuncti qui ad ritus suos hæresis superstitionibus obrepserant sacrosanctæ
              legis inimici, plectendos se poenâ &amp; proscriptionis &amp; sanguinis, si ultra
              convenire
              per publicum exercendi sceleris sui temeritate temptaverint: ne quâ vera divinaque
              reverentia
              contagione temeretur. Dat. _viii._ Kal. Sept. Honorio _x._ &amp; Theod. _vi._ AA.
              Coss._
              A.C.
              415.
            </p>
          </q>
          <p id="98003031"> These Edicts being directed to the governor of _Africa_, extended only to the
            _Africans_.
            Before these there were many severe ones against the _Donatists_, but they did not
            extend to
            blood. These two were the first which made their meetings, and the meetings of all
            dissenters,
            capital: for by _hereticks_ in these Edicts are meant all dissenters, as is manifest by
            the
            following against _Euresius_ a _Luciferan_ Bishop.</p>
          <q lang="lat">
            <head>_Impp. Arcad. &amp; Honor.
              AA. Aureliano Proc. Africæ._</head>
            <p id="98003032"> _Hæreticorum vocabulo continentur, &amp; latis adversus eos sanctionibus debent
              succumbere,
              qui vel levi argumento à judicio Catholicæ religionis &amp; tramite detecti fuerint
              deviare:
              ideoque experientia tua Euresium hæreticum esse cognoscat. Dat. _iii._ Non. Sept.
              Constantinop. Olybrio &amp; Probino Coss._ A.C. 395.</p>
          </q>
          <p id="98003033">
            The _Greek_ Emperor _Zeno_ adopted _Theoderic_ King of the _Ostrogoths_ to
            be his son, made him master of the horse and _Patricius_, and Consul of
            _Constantinople_; and recommending to him the _Roman_ people and Senate,
            gave him the _Western_ Empire, and sent him into _Italy_ against _Odoacer_
            King of the _Heruli_. _Theoderic_ thereupon led his nation into _Italy_,
            conquered _Odoacer_, and reigned over _Italy_, _Sicily_, _Rhætia_,
            _Noricum_, _Dalmatia_, _Liburnia_, _Istria_, and part of _Suevia_,
            _Pannonia_ and _Gallia_. Whence _Ennodius_ said, in a Panegyric to
            _Theoderic_: _Ad limitem suum Romana regna remeâsse._ _Theoderic_ reigned
            with great prudence, moderation and felicity; treated the _Romans_ with
            singular benevolence, governed them by their own laws, and restored their
            government under their Senate and Consuls, he himself supplying the place
            of Emperor, without assuming the title. _Ita sibi parentibus præfuit_,
            saith _Procopius_, _ut vere Imperatori conveniens decus nullum ipsi
            abesset: Justitiæ magnus ei cultus, legumque diligens custodia: terras à
            vicinis barbaris servavit intactas_, &amp;c. Whence I do not reckon the reign
            of this King, amongst the plagues of the four winds.
          </p>
          <p id="98003034"> The plague of the northern wind, at the sounding of the fourth trumpet, was to cause
            _the Sun, Moon and Stars_, that is, the King, kingdom and Princes of the _Western_
            Empire, _to be darkned_, and to continue some time in darkness. Accordingly
            _Belisarius_, having conquered the _Vandals_, invaded _Italy_ A.C. 535, and made war
            upon the _Ostrogoths_ in _Dalmatia_, _Liburnia_, _Venetia_, _Lombardy_, _Tuscany_, and
            other regions northward from _Rome_, twenty years together. In this war many cities were
            taken and retaken. In retaking _Millain_ from the _Romans_, the _Ostrogoths_ slew all
            the males young and old, amounting, as _Procopius_ reckons, to three hundred thousand,
            and sent the women captives to their allies the _Burgundians_. _Rome_ itself was taken
            and retaken several times, and thereby the people were thinned; the old government by a
            Senate ceased, the nobles were ruined, and all the glory of the city was extinguish'd:
            and A.C. 552, after a war of seventeen years, the kingdom of the _Ostrogoths_ fell; yet
            the remainder of the _Ostrogoths_, and an army of _Germans_ called in to their
            assistance, continued the war three or four years longer. Then ensued the war of the
            _Heruli_, who, as _Anastasius_ tells us, _perimebant cunctam Italiam_, slew all _Italy_.
            This was followed by the war of the _Lombards_, the fiercest of all the _Barbarians_,
            which began A.C. 568, and lasted for thirty eight years together; _factâ tali clade_,
            saith _Anastasius_, _qualem à sæculo nullus meminit_; ending at last in the Papacy of
            _Sabinian_, A.C. 605, by a peace then made with the _Lombards_. Three years before this
            war ended, _Gregory_ the great, then Bishop of _Rome_, thus speaks of it: <q lang="lat">_Qualiter
            enim
              &amp; quotidianis gladiis &amp; quantis
              Longobardorum incursionibus, ecce jam per triginta quinque annorum
              longitudinem premimur, nullis explere vocibus suggestionis valemus_: and in
              one of his Sermons to the people, he thus expresses the great consumption
              of the _Romans_ by these wars: _Ex illa plebe innumerabili quanti
              remanseritis aspicitis, &amp; tamen adhuc quotidiè flagella urgent, repentini
              casus opprimunt, novæ res &amp; improvisæ clades affligunt_. In another Sermon
              he thus describes the desolations: _Destructæ urbes, eversa sunt castra,
              depopulati agri, in solitudinem terra redacta est. Nullus in agris incola,
              penè nullus in urbibus habitator remansit. Et tamen ipsæ parvæ generis
              humani reliquiæ adhuc quotidiè &amp; sine cessatione feriuntur, &amp; finem non
              habent flagella coelestis justitiæ. Ipsa autem quæ aliquando mundi Domina
              esse videbatur, qualis remansit Roma conspicimus innumeris doloribus
              multipliciter attrita, defolatione civium, impressione hostium, frequentiâ
            ruinarum.--Ecce jam de illa omnes hujus fæculi potentes ablati sunt.--Ecce
              populi defecerunt.--Ubi enim Senatus? Ubi jam populus? Contabuerunt ossa,
              consumptæ sunt carnes. Omnis enim sæcularium dignitatum ordo extinctus est,
              &amp; tamen ipsos vos paucos qui remansimus, adhuc quotidié gladii, adhuc
              quotidié innumeræ tribulationes premunt.--Vacua jam ardet Roma. Quid autem
              ista de hominibus dicimus? Cum ruinis crebrescentibus ipsa quoque destrui
              ædificia videmus. Postquam defecerunt homines etiam parietes cadunt. Jam
              ecce desolata, ecce contrita, ecce gemitibus oppressa est,_ &amp;c.</q>All this was
            spoken by _Gregory_ to the people of _Rome_, who were witnesses of the truth of it. Thus
            by _the plagues of the four winds_, the Empire of the _Greeks_ was shaken, and the
            Empire of the _Latins_ fell; and _Rome_ remained nothing more than the capital of a poor
            dukedom, subordinate to _Ravenna_, the seat of the Exarchs. </p>
          <p id="98003035">
            The fifth trumpet sounded to the wars, which the _King of the_ South, as he
            is called by _Daniel_, made _in the time of the end_, in _pushing at the
            King who did according to his will_. This plague began with the _opening of
            the bottomless pit_, which denoteGrp the letting out of a false religion: the
            _smoke which came out of the pit_, signifying the multitude which embraced
            that religion; and the _locusts which came out of the smoke_, the armies
            which came out of that multitude. This pit was opened, to let out smoke and
            locusts into the regions of the four monarchies, or some of them. _The King
            of these locusts_ was the _Angel of the bottomless pit_, being chief
            governor as well in religious as civil affairs, such as was the Caliph of
            the _Saracens_. Swarms of locusts often arise in _Arabia fælix_, and from
            thence infest the neighbouring nations: and so are a very fit type of the
            numerous armies of _Arabians_ invading the _Romans_. They began to invade
            them A.C. 634, and to reign at _Damascus_ A.C. 637. They built _Bagdad_
            A.C. 766, and reigned over _Persia_, _Syria_, _Arabia_, _Egypt_, _Africa_
            and _Spain_. They afterwards lost _Africa_ to _Mahades_, A.C. 910; _Media_,
            _Hircania_, _Chorasan_, and all _Persia_, to the _Dailamites_, between the
            years 927 and 935; _Mesopotamia_ and _Miafarekin_ to _Nasiruddaulas_, A.C.
            930; _Syria_ and _Egypt_ to _Achsjid_, A.C. 935, and now being in great
            distress, the Caliph of _Bagdad_, A.C. 936, surrendred all the rest of his
            temporal power to _Mahomet_ the son of _Rajici_, King of _Wasit_ in
            _Chaldea_, and made him Emperor of Emperors. But _Mahomet_ within two years
            lost _Bagdad_ to the _Turks_; and thenceforward _Bagdad_ was sometimes in
            the hands of the _Turks_, and sometimes in the hands of the _Saracens_,
            till _Togrul-beig_, called also _Togra_, _Dogrissa_, _Tangrolipix_, and
            _Sadoc_, conquered _Chorasan_ and _Persia_; and A.C. 1055, added _Bagdad_
            to his Empire, making it the seat thereof. His successors _Olub-Arflan_ and
            _Melechschah_, conquered the regions upon _Euphrates_; and these conquests,
            after the death of _Melechschah_, brake into the kingdoms of _Armenia_,
            _Mesopotamia_, _Syria_, and _Cappadocia_. The whole time that the Caliphs
            of the _Saracens_ reigned with a temporal dominion at _Damascus_ and
            _Bagdad_ together, was 300 years, viz. from the year 637 to the year 936
            inclusive. Now locusts live but five months; and therefore, for the decorum
            of the type, these locusts are said to _hurt men five months and five
            months_, as if they had lived about five months at _Damascus_, and again
            about five months at _Bagdad_; in all ten months, or 300 prophetic days,
            which are years.
          </p>
          <p id="98003036">
            The sixth trumpet sounded to the wars, which _Daniel_'s King of the _North_
            made against the King above-mentioned, _who did according to his will_. In
            these wars the King of the _North_, according to _Daniel_, conquered the
            Empire of the _Greeks_, and also _Judea_, _Egypt_, _Lybia_, and _Ethiopia_:
            and by these conquests the Empire of the _Turks_ was set up, as may be
            known by the extent thereof. These wars commenced A.C. 1258, when the four
            kingdoms of the _Turks_ seated upon _Euphrates_, that of _Armenia major_
            seated at _Miyapharekin_, _Megarkin_ or _Martyropolis_, that of
            _Mesopotamia_ seated at _Mosul_, that of all _Syria_ seated at _Aleppo_,
            and that of _Cappadocia_ seated at _Iconium_, were invaded by the _Tartars_
            under _Hulacu_, and driven into the western parts of _Asia minor_, where
            they made war upon the _Greeks_, and began to erect the present Empire of
            the _Turks_. Upon the sounding of the sixth trumpet, [9] _John heard a
            voice from the four horns of the golden Altar which is before God, saying
            to the sixth Angel which had the trumpet, Loose the four Angels which are
            bound at the great river _Euphrates_. And the four Angels were loosed,
            which were prepared for an hour and a day, and a month and a year, for to
            slay the third part of men_. By the four horns of the golden Altar, is
            signified the situation of the head cities of the said four kingdoms,
            _Miyapharekin_, _Mosul_, _Aleppo_, and _Iconium_, which were in a
            quadrangle. They slew the third part of men, when they conquered the
            _Greek_ Empire, and took _Constantinople_, A.C. 1453. and they began to be
            prepared for this purpose, when _Olub-Arslan_ began to conquer the nations
            upon _Euphrates_, A.C. 1063. The interval is called an hour and a day, and
            a month and a year, or 391 prophetic days, which are years. In the first
            thirty years, _Olub-Arslan_ and _Melechschah_ conquered the nations upon
            _Euphrates_, and reigned over the whole. _Melechschah_ died A.C. 1092, and
            was succeeded by a little child; and then this kingdom broke into the four
            kingdoms above-mentioned.
          </p>
          <milestone unit="part" n="2" rend="italic">
            _THE END._
          </milestone>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. III.</desc>
            <note id="n.2.3.1">Apoc. ii. 4, &amp;c.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.2">Apoc. ii. 9, 10.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.3">Ver. 14.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.4">Numb. xxv. 1, 2, 18, &amp; xxi. 16.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.5">Apoc. iii. 10, 12.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.6">Apoc. iii. 16, 17.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.7">Apoc. viii. 7, &amp;c.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.8">Apoc. xvi. 5, 6.</note>
            <note id="n.2.3.9">Apoc. ix. 13, &amp;c.</note>
          </noteGrp>

        </div>
      
