<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.7" id="98007" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. VII.</head>
          <head>Of the eleventh horn of _Daniel_'s fourth Beast.</head>
          <p id="98007002">
            [1]_Now Daniel, considered the horns, and behold there came up among them
            another horn, before whom there were three of the first horns pluckt up by
            the roots; and behold in this horn were eyes like the eyes of a man, and a
            mouth speaking great things,_--and [2] his _look was more stout than his
            fellows,--and the same horn made war with the saints, and prevailed against
            them_: and one who stood by, and made _Daniel_ know the interpretation of
            these things, told him, that [3] _the ten horns were ten kings that should
            arise, and another should arise after them, and be diverse from the first,
            and he should subdue three kings,_ [4] _and speak great words against the
            most High, and wear out the saints, and think to change times and laws: and
            that they should be given into his hands until a time and times and half a
            time_. Kings are put for kingdoms, as above; and therefore the little horn
            is a little kingdom. It was a horn of the fourth Beast, and rooted up three
            of his first horns; and therefore we are to look for it among the nations
            of the _Latin_ Empire, after the rise of the ten horns. But it was a
            kingdom of a different kind from the other ten kingdoms, having a life or
            soul peculiar to itself, with eyes and a mouth. By its eyes it was a Seer;
            and by its mouth speaking great things and changing times and laws, it was
            a Prophet as well as a King. And such a Seer, a Prophet and a King, is the
            Church of _Rome_.
          </p>
          <p id="98007003"> A Seer, [Greek: Episkopos], is a Bishop in the literal sense of the word; and this
            Church
            claims the universal Bishoprick. </p>
          <p id="98007004"> With his mouth he gives laws to kings and nations as an
            Oracle; and pretends to Infallibility, and that his dictates are binding to the whole
            world;
            which
            is to be a Prophet in the highest degree. </p>
          <p id="98007005">
            In the eighth century, by rooting up and subduing the Exarchate of
            _Ravenna_, the kingdom of the _Lombards_, and the Senate and Dukedom of
            _Rome_, he acquired _Peter_'s Patrimony out of their dominions; and thereby
            rose up as a temporal Prince or King, or horn of the fourth Beast.
          </p>
          <p id="98007006">
            In a small book printed at _Paris_ A.C. 1689, entitled, _An historical
            dissertation upon some coins of _Charles_ the great, _Ludovicus Pius_,
            _Lotharius_, and their successors stamped at _Rome__, it is recorded, that
            in the days of Pope _Leo_ X, there was remaining in the _Vatican_, and till
            those days exposed to public view, an inscription in honour of _Pipin_ the
            father of _Charles_ the great, in these words: _Pipinum pium, primum fuisse
            qui amplificandæ Ecclesiæ Romanæ viam aperuerit, Exarchatu Ravennate, &amp;
            plurimis aliis oblatis_; "That _Pipin_ the pious was the first who opened a
            way to the grandeur of the Church of _Rome_, conferring upon her the
            Exarchate of _Ravenna_ and many other oblations." In and before the reign
            of the Emperors _Gratian_ and _Theodosius_, the Bishop of _Rome_ lived
            splendidly; but this was by the oblations of the _Roman_ Ladies, as
            _Ammianus_ describes. After those reigns _Italy_ was invaded by foreign
            nations, and did not get rid of her troubles before the fall of the kingdom
            of _Lombardy_. It was certainly by the victory of the see of _Rome_ over
            the _Greek_ Emperor, the King of _Lombardy_, and the Senate of _Rome_, that
            she acquired _Peter_'s Patrimony, and rose up to her greatness. The
            donation of _Constantine_ the Great is a fiction, and so is the donation of
            the _Alpes Cottiæ_ to the Pope by _Aripert_ King of the _Lombards_: for the
            _Alpes Cottiæ_ were a part of the Exarchate, and in the days of _Aripert_
            belonged to the _Greek_ Emperor.
          </p>
          <p id="98007007">
            The invocation of the dead, and veneration of their images, being gradually
            introduced in the 4th, 5th, 6th and 7th centuries, the _Greek_ Emperor
            _Philippicus_ declared against the latter, A.C. 711 or 712. And [5] the
            Emperor _Leo Isaurus_, to put a stop to it, called a meeting of Counsellors
            and Bishops in his Palace, A.C. 726; and by their advice put out an Edict
            against that worship, and wrote to Pope _Gregory_ II. that a general
            Council might be called. But the Pope thereupon called a Council at _Rome_,
            confirmed the worship of Images, excommunicated the _Greek_ Emperor,
            absolved the people from their allegiance, and forbad them to pay tribute,
            or otherwise be obedient to him. Then the people of _Rome_, _Campania_,
            _Ravenna_ and _Pentapolis_, with the cities under them, revolted and laid
            violent hands upon their magistrates, killing the Exarch _Paul_ at
            _Ravenna_, and laying aside _Peter_ Duke of _Rome_ who was become blind:
            and when _Exhileratus_ Duke of _Campania_ incited the people against the
            Pope, the _Romans_ invaded _Campania_, and slew him with his son _Hadrian_.
            Then a new Exarch, _Eutychius_, coming to _Naples_, sent some secretly to
            take away the lives of the Pope and the Nobles of _Rome_: but the plot
            being discovered, the _Romans_ revolted absolutely from the _Greek_
            Emperor, and took an oath to preserve the life of the Pope, to defend his
            state, and be obedient to his authority in all things. Thus _Rome_ with its
            Duchy, including part of _Tuscany_ and part of _Campania_, revolted in the
            year 726, and became a free state under the government of the Senate of
            this city. The authority of the Senate in civil affairs was henceforward
            absolute, the authority of the Pope extending hitherto no farther than to
            the affairs of the Church only.
          </p>
          <p id="98007008">
            At that time [6] the _Lombards_ also being zealous for the worship of
            images, and pretending to favour the cause of the Pope, invaded the cities
            of the Exarchate: and at length, viz. A.C. 752, took _Ravenna_, and put an
            end to the Exarchate. And this was the first of the three kingdoms which
            fell before the little horn.
          </p>
          <p id="98007009">
            In the year 751 [7] Pope _Zechary_ deposed _Childeric_, a slothful and
            useless King of _France_, and the last of the race of _Merovæus_; and
            absolving his subjects from their oath of allegiance, gave the kingdom to
            _Pipin_ the major of the Palace; and thereby made a new and potent friend.
            His successor [8] Pope _Stephen_ III, knowing better how to deal with the
            _Greek_ Emperor than with the _Lombards_, went the next year to the King of
            the _Lombards_, to persuade him to return the Exarchate to the Emperor. But
            this not succeeding, he went into _France_, and persuaded _Pipin_ to take
            the Exarchate and _Pentapolis_ from the _Lombards_, and give it to St.
            _Peter_. Accordingly _Pipin_ A.C. 754 came with an army into _Italy_, and
            made _Aistulphus_ King of the _Lombards_ promise the surrender: but the
            next year _Aistulphus_, on the contrary, to revenge himself on the Pope,
            besieged the city of _Rome_. Whereupon the Pope sent letters to _Pipin_,
            wherein he told him that if he came not speedily against the _Lombards_,
            _pro data sibi potentia, alienandum fore à regno Dei &amp; vita æterna_, he
            should be excommunicated. _Pipin_ therefore, fearing a revolt of his
            subjects, and being indebted to the Church of _Rome_, came speedily with an
            army into _Italy_, raised the siege, besieged the _Lombards_ in _Pavia_,
            and forced them to surrender the Exarchate and region of _Pentapolis_ to
            the Pope for a perpetual possession. Thus the Pope became Lord of
            _Ravenna_, and the Exarchate, some few cities excepted; and the keys were
            sent to _Rome_, and laid upon the confession of St. _Peter_, that is, upon
            his tomb at the high Altar, _in signum veri perpetuique dominii, sed
            pietate Regis gratuita_, as the inscription of a coin of _Pipin_ hath it.
            This was in the year of Christ 755. And henceforward the Popes being
            temporal Princes, left off in their Epistles and Bulls to note the years of
            the _Greek_ Emperors, as they had hitherto done.
          </p>
          <p id="98007010">
            After this [9] the _Lombards_ invading the Pope's countries, Pope _Adrian_
            sent to _Charles_ the great, the son and successor of _Pipin_, to come to
            his assistance. Accordingly _Charles_ entered _Italy_ with an army, invaded
            the _Lombards_, overthrew their kingdom, became master of their countries,
            and restored to the Pope, not only what they had taken from him, but also
            the rest of the Exarchate which they had promised _Pipin_ to surrender to
            him, but had hitherto detained; and also gave him some cities of the
            _Lombards_, and was in return himself made _Patricius_ by the _Romans_, and
            had the authority of confirming the elections of the Popes conferred upon
            him. These things were done in the years 773 and 774. This kingdom of the
            _Lombards_ was the second kingdom which fell before the little horn. But
            _Rome_, which was to be the seat of his kingdom, was not yet his own.
          </p>
          <p id="98007011"> In the year 796, [10] _Leo_ III being made Pope, notified his election to _Charles_
            the
            great by his Legates, sending to him for a present, the golden keys of the Confession of
            _Peter_,
            and the Banner of the city of _Rome_: the first as an acknowledgment of the Pope's
            holding the
            cities of the Exarchate and _Lombardy_ by the grant of _Charles_; the other as a
            signification
            that _Charles_ should come and subdue the Senate and people of _Rome_, as he had done
            the
            Exarchate and the kingdom of the _Lombards_. For the Pope at the same time desired
            _Charles_
            to
            send some of his Princes to _Rome_, who might subject the _Roman_ people to him, and
            bind them
            by
            oath _in fide &amp; subjectione_, in fealty and subjection, as his words are recited by
            _Sigonius_. An anonymous Poet, publish'd by _Boeclerus_ at _Strasburg_, expresseth it
            thus:</p>
          <q lang="lat">
            <lg>
              <l>_Admonuitque piis precibus, qui mittere vellet_</l>
              <l>_Ex propriis aliquos
                primoribus, ac sibi plebem_</l>
              <l>_Subdere Romanam, servandaque foedera cogens_</l>
              <l>_Hanc fidei
                sacramentis promittere magnis_.</l>
            </lg>
          </q>
          <p id="98007012">
            Hence arose a misunderstanding between the Pope and the city: and the
            _Romans_ about two or three years after, by assistance of some of the
            Clergy, raised such tumults against him, as gave occasion to a new state of
            things in all the _West_. For two of the Clergy accused him of crimes, and
            the _Romans_ with an armed force, seized him, stript him of his sacerdotal
            habit, and imprisoned him in a monastery. But by assistance of his friends
            he made his escape, and fled into _Germany_ to _Charles_ the great, to whom
            he complained of the _Romans_ for acting against him out of a design to
            throw off all authority of the Church, and to recover their antient
            freedom. In his absence his accusers with their forces ravaged the
            possessions of the Church, and sent the accusations to _Charles_; who
            before the end of the year sent the Pope back to _Rome_ with a large
            retinue. The Nobles and Bishops of _France_ who accompanied him, examined
            the chief of his accusers at _Rome_, and sent them into _France_ in
            custody. This was in the year 799. The next year _Charles_ himself went to
            _Rome_, and upon a day appointed presided in a Council of _Italian_ and
            _French_ Bishops to hear both parties. But when the Pope's adversaries
            expected to be heard, the Council declared [11] that he who was the supreme
            judge of all men, was above being judged by any other than himself:
            whereupon he made a solemn declaration of his innocence before all the
            people, and by doing so was looked upon as acquitted.
          </p>
          <p id="98007013"> Soon after, upon _Christmas_-day, the people of _Rome_, who had hitherto elected their
            Bishop, and reckoned that they and their Senate inherited the rights of the antient
            Senate and
            people of _Rome_, voted _Charles_ their Emperor, and subjected themselves to him in such
            manner as
            the old _Roman_ Empire and their Senate were subjected to the old _Roman_ Emperors. The
            Pope
            crowned him, and anointed him with holy oil, and worshipped him on his knees after the
            manner
            of
            adoring the old _Roman_ Emperors; as the aforesaid Poet thus relates:</p>
          <q lang="lat">
            <lg>
              <l> _Post
                laudes igitur dictas &amp; summus eundem_</l>
              <l> _Præsul adoravit, sicut mos debitus olim_</l>
              <l>
                _Principibus fuit antiquis_.</l>
            </lg>
          </q>
          <p id="98007014">
            The Emperor, on the other hand, took the following oath to the Pope: _In
            nomine Christi spondeo atque polliceor, Ego Carolus Imperator coram Deo &amp;
            beato Petro Apostolo, me protectorem ac defensorem fore hujus sanctæ Romanæ
            Ecclesiæ in omnibus utilitatibus, quatenùs divino fultus fuero adjutorio,
            prout sciero poteroque_. The Emperor was also made Consul of _Rome_, and
            his son _Pipin_ crowned King of _Italy_: and henceforward the Emperor
            stiled himself: _Carolus serenissimus, Augustus, à Deo coronatus, magnus,
            pacificus, Romæ gubernans imperium_, or _Imperator Romanorum_; and was
            prayed for in the Churches of _Rome_. His image was henceforward put upon
            the coins of _Rome_: while the enemies of the Pope, to the number of three
            hundred _Romans_ and two or three of the Clergy, were sentenced to death.
            The three hundred _Romans_ were beheaded in one day in the _Lateran_
            fields: but the Clergymen at the intercession of the Pope were pardoned,
            and banished into _France_. And thus the title of _Roman_ Emperor, which
            had hitherto been in the _Greek_ Emperors, was by this act transferred in
            the _West_ to the Kings of _France_.
          </p>
          <p id="98007015">
            After these things [12] _Charles_ gave the City and Duchy of _Rome_ to the
            Pope, subordinately to himself as Emperor of the _Romans_; spent the winter
            in ordering the affairs of _Rome_, and those of the Apostolic see, and of
            all _Italy_, both civil and ecclesiastical, and in making new laws for
            them; and returned the next summer into _France_: leaving the city under
            its Senate, and both under the Pope and himself. But hearing that his new
            laws were not observed by the judges in dictating the law, nor by the
            people in hearing it; and that the great men took servants from free men,
            and from the Churches and Monasteries, to labour in their vineyards,
            fields, pastures and houses, and continued to exact cattle and wine of
            them, and to oppress those that served the Churches: he wrote to his son
            _Pipin_ to remedy these abuses, to take care of the Church, and see his
            laws executed.
          </p>
          <p id="98007016">
            Now the Senate and people and principality of _Rome_ I take to be the third
            King the little horn overcame, and even the chief of the three. For this
            people elected the Pope and the Emperor; and now, by electing the Emperor
            and making him Consul, was acknowledged to retain the authority of the old
            _Roman_ Senate and people. This city was the Metropolis of the old _Roman_
            Empire, represented in _Daniel_ by the fourth Beast; and by subduing the
            Senate and people and Duchy, it became the Metropolis of the little horn of
            that Beast, and completed _Peter_'s Patrimony, which was the kingdom of
            that horn. Besides, this victory was attended with greater consequences
            than those over the other two Kings. For it set up the _Western Empire_,
            which continues to this day. It set up the Pope above the judicature of the
            _Roman_ Senate, and above that of a Council of _Italian_ and _French_
            Bishops, and even above all human judicature; and gave him the supremacy
            over the _Western_ Churches and their Councils in a high degree. It gave
            him _a look more stout than his fellows_; so that when this new religion
            began to be established in the minds of men, he grappled not only with
            Kings, but even with the _Western_ Emperor himself. It is observable also,
            that the custom of kissing the Pope's feet, an honour superior to that of
            Kings and Emperors, began about this time. There are some instances of it
            in the ninth century: _Platina_ tells us, that the feet of Pope _Leo_ IV
            were kissed, according to antient custom, by all who came to him: and some
            say that _Leo_ III began this custom, pretending that his hand was infected
            by the kiss of a woman. The Popes began also about this time to canonize
            saints, and to grant indulgences and pardons: and some represent that _Leo_
            III was the first author of all these things. It is further observable,
            that _Charles_ the great, between the years 775 and 796, conquered all
            _Germany_ from the _Rhine_ and _Danube_ northward to the _Baltic_ sea, and
            eastward to the river _Teis_; extending his conquests also into _Spain_ as
            far as the river _Ebro_: and by these conquests he laid the foundation of
            the new Empire; and at the same time propagated the _Roman_ Catholic
            religion into all his conquests, obliging the _Saxons_ and _Hunns_ who were
            heathens, to receive the _Roman_ faith, and distributing his northern
            conquests into Bishopricks, granting tithes to the Clergy and _Peter-pence_
            to the Pope: by all which the Church of _Rome_ was highly enlarged,
            enriched, exalted, and established.
          </p>
          <p id="98007017"> In the forementioned _dissertation upon some coins of _Charles_ the great, _Ludovicus
            Pius_, _Lotharius_, and their successors, stamped at _Rome__, there is a draught of a
            piece of _Mosaic_ work which Pope _Leo_ III. caused to be made in his Palace near the
            Church of _John Lateran_, in memory of his sending the standard or banner of the city of
            _Rome_ curiously wrought, to _Charles_ the great; and which still remained there at the
            publishing of the said book. In the _Mosaic_ work there appeared _Peter_ with three keys
            in his lap, reaching the _Pallium_ to the Pope with his right hand, and the banner of
            the city to _Charles_ the great with his left. By the Pope was this inscription,
            SCISSIMUS D.N. LEO PP; by the King this, D.N. CARVLO REGI; and under the feet of _Peter_
            this, BEATE PETRE, DONA VITAM LEONI PP, ET BICTORIAM CARVLO REGI DONA. This Monument
            gives the title of King to _Charles_, and therefore was erected before he was Emperor.
            It was erected when _Peter_ was reaching the _Pallium_ to the Pope, and the Pope was
            sending the banner of the city to _Charles_, that is, A.C. 796. The words above, <q lang="lat">_Sanctissimus Dominus noster Leo Papa Domino nostro Carolo Regi_</q>,
            relate to the message; and the words below, _Beate Petre, dona vitam Leoni Papæ &amp;
            victoriam Carolo regi dona_, are a prayer that in this undertaking God would preserve
            the life of the Pope, and give victory to the King over the _Romans_. The three keys in
            the lap of _Peter_ signify the keys of the three parts of his Patrimony, that of _Rome_
            with its Duchy, which the Pope claimed and was conquering, those of _Ravenna_ with the
            Exarchate, and of the territories taken from the _Lombards_; both which he had newly
            conquered. These were the three dominions, whose keys were in the lap of St. _Peter_,
            and whose Crowns are now worn by the Pope, and by the conquest of which he became the
            little horn of the fourth Beast. By _Peter_'s giving the _Pallium_ to the Pope with his
            right hand, and the banner of the city to the King with his left, and by naming the Pope
            before the King in the inscription, may be understood that the Pope was then reckoned
            superior in dignity to the Kings of the earth. </p>
          <p id="98007018">
            After the death of _Charles_ the great, his son and successor _Ludovicus
            Pius_, at the request of the Pope, [13] confirmed the donations of his
            grandfather and father to the see of _Rome_. And in the confirmation he
            names first _Rome_ with its Duchy extending into _Tuscany_ and _Campania_;
            then the Exarchate of _Ravenna_, with _Pentapolis_; and in the third place,
            the territories taken from the _Lombards_. These are his three conquests,
            and he was to hold them of the Emperor for the use of the Church _sub
            integritate_, entirely, without the Emperor's medling therewith, or with
            the jurisdiction or power of the Pope therein, unless called thereto in
            certain cases. This ratification the Emperor _Ludovicus_ made under an
            oath: and as the King of the _Ostrogoths_, for acknowledging that he held
            his kingdom of _Italy_ of the _Greek_ Emperor, stamped the effigies of the
            Emperor on one side of his coins and his own on the reverse; so the Pope
            made the like acknowledgment to the _Western_ Emperor. For the Pope began
            now to coin money, and the coins of _Rome_ are henceforward found with the
            heads of the Emperors, _Charles_, _Ludovicus Pius_, _Lotharius_, and their
            successors, on the one side, and the Pope's inscription on the reverse, for
            many years.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. VII.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.7.1">Chap. vii. 8.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.2">Ver. 20, 21.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.3">Ver. 24.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.4">Ver. 25.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.5">Sigonius de Regno Italiæ, ad Ann. 726.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.6">Sigonius ib. ad Ann. 726, 752.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.7">Sigon. ib. Ann. 750.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.8">Sigon. ib. Ann. 753, 754, 755.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.9">Sigon. ib. Ann. 773.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.10">Sigon. de Regno Ital. ad Ann. 796.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.11">Vide Anastasium.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.12">Sigon. de Regno Ital.</note>
            <note id="n.1.7.13">Confirmationem recitat Sigonius, lib. 4. de Regno Italiæ, ad An.
              817.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
