<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.4" id="98004" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. IV.</head>
          <head>Of the vision of the four Beasts.</head>
          <p id="98004002">
            In the next vision, which is of the four Beasts, the Prophecy of the four
            Empires is repeated, with several new additions; such as are the two wings
            of the Lion, the three ribs in the mouth of the Bear, the four wings and
            four heads of the Leopard, the eleven horns of the fourth Beast, and the
            son of man coming in the clouds of Heaven, to the Antient of Days sitting
            in judgment.
          </p>
          <p id="98004003">
            The first Beast was like a lion, and had eagle's wings, to denote the
            kingdoms of _Babylonia_ and _Media_, which overthrew the _Assyrian_ Empire,
            and divided it between them, and thereby became considerable, and grew into
            great Empires. In the former Prophecy, the Empire of _Babylonia_ was
            represented by the head of gold; in this both Empires are represented
            together by the two wings of the lion. _And I beheld,_ saith [1] _Daniel_,
            _till the wings thereof were pluckt, and it was lifted up from the earth,
            and made to stand upon the feet as a man, and a man's heart was given to
            it_; that is, till it was humbled and subdued, and made to know its human
            state.
          </p>
          <p id="98004004">
            The second Beast was like a bear, and represents the Empire which reigned
            next after the _Babylonians_, that is, the Empire of the _Persians_. _Thy
            kingdom is divided_, or broken, saith _Daniel_ to the last King of
            _Babylon_, _and given to the _Medes_ and _Persians__, _Dan._ v. 28. This
            Beast _raised itself up on one side_; the _Persians_ being under the
            _Medes_ at the fall of _Babylon_, but presently rising up above them. [2]
            _And it had three ribs in the mouth of it, between the teeth of it_, to
            signify the kingdoms of _Sardes_, _Babylon_, and _Egypt_, which were
            conquered by it, but did not belong to its proper body. And it devoured
            much flesh, the riches of those three kingdoms.
          </p>
          <p id="98004005">
            The third Beast was the kingdom which succeeded the _Persian_; and this was
            the empire of the _Greeks_, _Dan._ viii. 6, 7, 20, 21. It was _like a
            Leopard_, to signify its fierceness; and had four heads and four wings, to
            signify that it should become divided into four kingdoms, _Dan._ viii 22.
            for it continued in a monarchical form during the reign of _Alexander_ the
            great, and his brother _Aridæus_, and young sons _Alexander_ and
            _Hercules_; and then brake into four kingdoms, by the governors of
            provinces putting crowns on their own heads, and by mutual consent reigning
            over their provinces. _Cassander_ reigned over _Macedon_, _Greece_, and
            _Epirus_; _Lysimachus_ over _Thrace_ and _Bithynia_; _Ptolemy_ over
            _Egypt_, _Lybia_, _Arabia_, _Coelosyria_, and _Palestine_; and _Seleucus_
            over _Syria_.
          </p>
          <p id="98004006">
            The fourth Beast was the empire which succeeded that of the _Greeks_, and
            this was the _Roman_. This beast was exceeding dreadful and terrible, and
            had great iron teeth, and devoured and brake in pieces, and stamped the
            residue with its feet; and such was the _Roman_ empire. It was larger,
            stronger, and more formidable and lasting than any of the former. It
            conquered the kingdom of _Macedon_, with _Illyricum_ and _Epirus_, in the
            eighth year of _Antiochus Epiphanes_, _Anno Nabonass._. 580; and inherited
            that of _Pergamus_, _Anno Nabonass._ 615; and conquered that of _Syria_,
            _Anno Nabonass._ 679, and that of _Egypt_, _Anno Nabonass._ 718. And by
            these and other conquests it became greater and more terrible than any of
            the three former Beasts. This Empire continued in its greatness till the
            reign of _Theodosius_ the great; and then brake into ten kingdoms,
            represented by the ten horns of this Beast; and continued in a broken form,
            till the Antient of days sat in a throne like fiery flame, and _the
            judgment was set, and the books were opened, and the Beast was slain and
            his body destroyed, and given to the burning flames; and one like the son
            of man came with the clouds of heaven, and came to the Antient of days_
            [3], and received dominion over all nations, and judgment was given to the
            saints of the most high, and the time came that they possessed the kingdom.
          </p>
          <p id="98004007">
            _I beheld,_ saith [4] _Daniel_, _till the Beast was slain, and his body
            destroyed, and given to the burning flames. As concerning the rest of the
            Beasts, they had their dominion taken away: yet their lives were prolonged
            for a season and a time_. And therefore all the four Beasts are still
            alive, tho the dominion of the three first be taken away. The nations of
            _Chaldea_ and _Assyria_ are still the first Beast. Those of _Media_ and
            _Persia_ are still the second Beast. Those of _Macedon_, _Greece_ and
            _Thrace_, _Asia_ minor, _Syria_ and _Egypt_, are still the third. And those
            of _Europe_, on this side _Greece_, are still the fourth. Seeing therefore
            the body of the third Beast is confined to the nations on this side the
            river _Euphrates_, and the body of the fourth Beast is confined to the
            nations on this side _Greece_; we are to look for all the four heads of the
            third Beast, among the nations on this side of the river _Euphrates_; and
            for all the eleven horns of the fourth Beast, among the nations on this
            side of _Greece_. And therefore, at the breaking of the _Greek_ empire into
            four kingdoms of the _Greeks_, we include no part of the _Chaldeans_,
            _Medes_ and _Persians_ in those kingdoms, because they belonged to the
            bodies of the two first Beasts. Nor do we reckon the _Greek_ empire seated
            at _Constantinople_, among the horns of the fourth Beast, because it
            belonged to the body of the third.
          </p>
          <desc>Notes to Chap. IV.</desc>
          <note id="n.1.4.1">Chap. vii. 4.</note>
          <note id="n.1.4.2">Chap. vii. 5.</note>
          <note id="n.1.4.3">Chap. vii. 13.</note>
          <note id="n.1.4.4">Chap. vii. 11, 12.</note>
        </div>
        
