<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.10" type="chapter" id="98010">
          <head>CHAP. X.</head>
          <head>Of the Prophecy of the Seventy Weeks.</head>
          <p id="98010002">
            The Vision of the Image composed of four Metals was given first to
            _Nebuchadnezzar_, and then to _Daniel_ in a dream: and _Daniel_ began then
            to be celebrated for revealing of secrets, _Ezek._ xxviii. 3. The Vision of
            the four Beasts, and of _the Son of man_ coming in the clouds of heaven,
            was also given to _Daniel_ in a dream. That of the Ram and the He-Goat
            appeared to him in the day time, when he was by the bank of the river
            _Ulay_; and was explained to him by the prophetic Angel _Gabriel_. It
            concerns the _Prince of the host_, and the _Prince of Princes_: and now in
            the first year of _Darius_ the _Mede_ over _Babylon_, the same prophetic
            Angel appears to _Daniel_ again, and explains to him what is meant by the
            _Son of man_, by the _Prince of the host_, and the _Prince of Princes_. The
            Prophecy of the _Son of man_ coming in the clouds of heaven relates to the
            second coming of _Christ_; that of the _Prince of the host_ relates to his
            first coming: and this Prophecy of the _Messiah_, in explaining them,
            relates to both comings, and assigns the times thereof.
          </p>
          <p id="98010003">
            This Prophecy, like all the rest of _Daniel_'s, consists of two parts, an
            introductory Prophecy and an explanation thereof; the whole I thus
            translate and interpret.
          </p>
          <p id="98010004">
            [1] '_Seventy weeks are [2] cut out upon thy people, and upon thy holy
            city, to finish transgression, and [3] to make an end of sins, to expiate
            iniquity, and to bring in everlasting righteousness, to consummate the
            Vision and [4] the Prophet, and to anoint the most Holy_.
          </p>
          <p id="98010005">
            '_Know also and understand, that from the going forth of the commandment to
            cause to return and to build _Jerusalem_, unto [5] the Anointed the Prince,
            shall be seven weeks_.
          </p>
          <p id="98010006">
            '_Yet threescore and two weeks shall [6] it return, and the street be built
            and the wall; but in troublesome times: and after the threescore and two
            weeks, the Anointed shall be cut off, and [6] it shall not be his; but the
            people of a Prince to come shall destroy the city and the sanctuary: and
            the end thereof shall be with a flood, and unto the end of the war,
            desolations are determined_.
          </p>
          <p id="98010007">
            '_Yet shall he confirm the covenant with many for one week: and in half a
            week he shall cause the sacrifice and oblation to cease: and upon a wing of
            abominations he shall make it desolate, even until the consummation, and
            that which is determined be poured upon the desolate_.'
          </p>
          <p id="98010008">
            _Seventy weeks are cut out upon thy people, and upon thy holy city, to
            finish transgression_, &amp;c. Here, by putting a week for seven years, are
            reckoned 490 years from the time that the dispersed _Jews_ should be
            re-incorporated into [7] a people and a holy city, until the death and
            resurrection of _Christ_; whereby _transgression should be finished, and
            sins ended, iniquity be expiated, and everlasting righteousness brought in,
            and this Vision be accomplished, and the Prophet consummated_, that Prophet
            whom the _Jews_ expected; and whereby _the most Holy_ should be _anointed_,
            he who is therefore in the next words called the _Anointed_, that is, the
            _Messiah_, or the _Christ_. For by joining the accomplishment of the vision
            with the expiation of sins, the 490 years are ended with the death of
            _Christ_. Now the dispersed _Jews_ became a people and city when they first
            returned into a polity or body politick; and this was in the seventh year
            of _Artaxerxes Longimanus_, when _Ezra_ returned with a body of _Jews_ from
            captivity, and revived the _Jewish_ worship; and by the King's commission
            created Magistrates in all the land, to judge and govern the people
            according to the laws of God and the King, _Ezra_ vii. 25. There were but
            two returns from captivity, _Zerubbabel_'s and _Ezra_'s; in _Zerubbabel_'s
            they had only commission to build the Temple, in _Ezra_'s they first became
            a polity or city by a government of their own. Now the years of this
            _Artaxerxes_ began about two or three months after the summer solstice, and
            his seventh year fell in with the third year of the eightieth _Olympiad_;
            and the latter part thereof, wherein _Ezra_ went up to _Jerusalem_, was in
            the year of the _Julian Period_ 4257. Count the time from thence to the
            death of _Christ_, and you will find it just 490 years. If you count in
            _Judaic_ years commencing in autumn, and date the reckoning from the first
            autumn after _Ezra_'s coming to _Jerusalem_, when he put the King's decree
            in execution; the death of _Christ_ will fall on the year of the _Julian
            Period_ 4747, _Anno Domini_ 34; and the weeks will be _Judaic_ weeks,
            ending with sabbatical years; and this I take to be the truth: but if you
            had rather place the death of _Christ_ in the year before, as is commonly
            done, you may take the year of _Ezra_'s journey into the reckoning.
          </p>
          <p id="98010009">
            _Know also and understand, that from the going forth of the commandment to
            cause to return and to build _Jerusalem_, unto the Anointed the Prince,
            shall be seven weeks_. The former part of the Prophecy related to the first
            coming of _Christ_, being dated to his coming as a Prophet; this being
            dated to his coming to be Prince or King, seems to relate to his second
            coming. There, the Prophet was consummate, and the most holy anointed:
            here, he that was anointed comes to be Prince and to reign. For _Daniel_'s
            Prophecies reach to the end of the world; and there is scarce a Prophecy in
            the Old Testament concerning _Christ_, which doth not in something or other
            relate to his second coming. If divers of the antients, as [8] _Irenæus_,
            [9] _Julius Africanus_, _Hippolytus_ the martyr, and _Apollinaris_ Bishop
            of _Laodicea_, applied the half week to the times of _Antichrist_; why may
            not we, by the same liberty of interpretation, apply the seven weeks to the
            time when _Antichrist_ shall be destroyed by the brightness of _Christ_'s
            coming?
          </p>
          <p id="98010010">
            The _Israelites_ in the days of the antient Prophets, when the ten Tribes
            were led into captivity, expected a double return; and that at the first
            the _Jews_ should build a new Temple inferior to _Solomon_'s, until the
            time of that age should be fulfilled; and afterwards they should return
            from all places of their captivity, and build _Jerusalem_ and the Temple
            gloriously, _Tobit_ xiv. 4, 5, 6: and to express the glory and excellence
            of this city, it is figuratively said to be built of precious stones,
            _Tobit_ xiii. 16, 17, 18. _Isa._ liv. 11, 12. _Rev._ xi. and called the
            _New Jerusalem_, the _Heavenly Jerusalem_, the _Holy City_, the _Lamb's
            Wife_, the _City of the Great King_, the _City into which the Kings of the
            earth do bring their glory and honour_. _Now_ while such a return from
            captivity was the expectation of _Israel_, even before the times of
            _Daniel_, I know not why _Daniel_ should omit it in his Prophecy. This part
            of the Prophecy being therefore not yet fulfilled, I shall not attempt a
            particular interpretation of it, but content myself with observing, that as
            the _seventy_ and the _sixty two weeks_ were _Jewish_ weeks, ending with
            sabbatical years; so the _seven weeks_ are the compass of a _Jubilee_, and
            begin and end with actions proper for a _Jubilee_, and of the highest
            nature for which a _Jubilee_ can be kept: and that since _the commandment
            to return and to build _Jerusalem__, precedes the _Messiah the Prince_ 49
            years; it may perhaps come forth not from the _Jews_ themselves, but from
            some other kingdom friendly to them, and precede their return from
            captivity, and give occasion to it; and lastly, that this rebuilding of
            _Jerusalem_ and the waste places of _Judah_ is predicted in _Micah_ vii.
            11. _Amos_ ix. 11, 14. _Ezek._ xxxvi. 33, 35, 36, 38. _Isa._ liv. 3, 11,
            12. lv. 12. lxi. 4. lxv. 18, 21,22. and _Tobit_ xiv. 5. and that the return
            from captivity and coming of the _Messiah_ and his kingdom are described in
            _Daniel_ vii. _Rev._ xix. _Acts_ i. _Mat._ xxiv. _Joel_ iii. _Ezek._ xxxvi.
            xxxvii. _Isa._ lx. lxii. lxiii. lxv. and lxvi. and many other places of
            scripture. The manner I know not. Let time be the Interpreter.
          </p>
          <p id="98010011">
            _Yet threescore and two weeks shall it return, and the street be built and
            the wall, but in troublesome times: and after the threescore and two weeks
            the _Messiah_ shall be cut off, and it shall not be his; but the people of
            a Prince to come shall destroy the city and the sanctuary_, &amp;c. Having
            foretold both comings of _Christ_, and dated the last from their returning
            and building _Jerusalem_; to prevent the applying that to the building
            _Jerusalem_ by _Nehemiah_, he distinguishes this from that, by saying that
            from this period to the _Anointed_ shall be, not seven weeks, but
            threescore and two weeks, and this not in prosperous but in troublesome
            times; and at the end of these Weeks the _Messiah_ shall not be the Prince
            of the _Jews_, but be cut off; and _Jerusalem_ not be his, but the city and
            sanctuary be destroyed. Now _Nehemiah_ came to _Jerusalem_ in the 20th year
            of this same _Artaxerxes_, while _Ezra_ still continued there, _Nehem._
            xii. 36, and found the city lying waste, and the houses and wall unbuilt,
            _Nehem._ ii. 17. vii. 4, and finished the wall the 25th day of the month
            _Elul_, _Nehem._ vi. 15, in the 28th year of the King, that is, in
            _September_ in the year of the _Julian Period_ 4278. Count now from this
            year threescore and two weeks of years, that is 434 years, and the
            reckoning will end in _September_ in the year of the _Julian Period_ 4712
            which is the year in which _Christ_ was born, according to _Clemens
            Alexandrinus_, _Irenæus_, _Eusebius_, _Epiphanius_, _Jerome_, _Orosius_,
            _Cassiodorus_, and other antients; and this was the general opinion, till
            _Dionysius Exiguus_ invented the vulgar account, in which _Christ_'s birth
            is placed two years later. If with some you reckon that _Christ_ was born
            three or four years before the vulgar account, yet his birth will fall in
            the latter part of the last week, which is enough. How after these weeks
            _Christ_ was cut off and the city and sanctuary destroyed by the _Romans_,
            is well known.
          </p>
          <p id="98010012">
            _Yet shall he confirm the covenant with many for one week._ He kept it,
            notwithstanding his death, till the rejection of the _Jews_, and calling of
            _Cornelius_ and the _Gentiles_ in the seventh year after his passion.
          </p>
          <p id="98010013">
            _And in half a week he shall cause the sacrifice and oblation to cease_;
            that is, by the war of the _Romans_ upon the _Jews_: which war, after some
            commotions, began in the 13th year of _Nero_, A.D. 67, in the spring, when
            _Vespasian_ with an army invaded them; and ended in the second year of
            _Vespasian_, A.D. 70, in autumn, _Sept._ 7, when _Titus_ took the city,
            having burnt the Temple 27 days before: so that it lasted three years and
            an half.
          </p>
          <p id="98010014">
            _And upon a wing of abominations he shall cause desolation, even until the
            consummation, and that which is determined be poured upon the desolate._
            The Prophets, in representing kingdoms by Beasts and Birds, put their wings
            stretcht out over any country for their armies sent out to invade and rule
            over that country. Hence a wing of abominations is an army of false Gods:
            for an abomination is often put in scripture for a false God; as where
            _Chemosh_ is called [10] the abomination of _Moab_, and _Molech_ the
            abomination of _Ammon_. The meaning therefore is, that the people of a
            Prince to come shall destroy the sanctuary, and abolish the daily worship
            of the true God, and overspread the land with an army of false gods; and by
            setting up their dominion and worship, cause desolation to the _Jews_,
            until the times of the _Gentiles_ be fulfilled. For _Christ_ tells us, that
            the abomination of desolation spoken of by _Daniel_ was to be set up in the
            times of the _Roman Empire_, _Matth._ xxiv. 15.
          </p>
          <p id="98010015">
            Thus have we in this short Prophecy, a prediction of all the main periods
            relating to the coming of the _Messiah_; the time of his birth, that of his
            death, that of the rejection of the _Jews_, the duration of the _Jewish_
            war whereby he caused the city and sanctuary to be destroyed, and the time
            of his second coming: and so the interpretation here given is more full and
            complete and adequate to the design, than if we should restrain it to his
            first coming only, as Interpreters usually do. We avoid also the doing
            violence to the language of _Daniel_, by taking the _seven weeks_ and
            _sixty two weeks_ for one number. Had that been _Daniel_'s meaning, he
            would have said _sixty and nine weeks_, and not _seven weeks_ and _sixty
            two weeks_, a way of numbring used by no nation. In our way the years are
            _Jewish Luni-solar years_, [11] as they ought to be; and the _seventy weeks
            of years_ are _Jewish weeks_ ending with _sabbatical years_, which is very
            remarkable. For they end either with the year of the birth of _Christ_, two
            years before the vulgar account, or with the year of his death, or with the
            seventh year after it: all which are _sabbatical years_. Others either
            count by Lunar years, or by weeks not _Judaic_: and, which is worst, they
            ground their interpretations on erroneous Chronology, excepting the opinion
            of _Funccius_ about the _seventy weeks_, which is the same with ours. For
            they place _Ezra_ and _Nehemiah_ in the reign of _Artaxerxes Mnemon_, and
            the building of the Temple in the reign of _Darius Nothus_, and date the
            weeks of _Daniel_ from those two reigns.
          </p>
          <p id="98010016"> The grounds of the Chronology here followed, I will now set down as briefly as I can.</p>
          <p id="98010017"><br/> The _Peloponnesian_ war began in spring _An._ 1 _Olymp._ 87, as _Diodorus_,
            _Eusebius_, and all other authors agree. It began two months before _Pythodorus_ ceased
            to be _Archon_, _Thucyd._ l. 2. that is, in _April_, two months before the end of the
            _Olympic_ year. Now the years of this war are most certainly determined by the 50 years
            distance of its first year from the transit of _Xerxes_ inclusively, _Thucyd._ l. 2. or
            48 years exclusively, _Eratosth. apud Clem. Alex._ by the 69 years distance of its end,
            or 27th year, from the beginning of _Alexander_'s reign in _Greece_; by the acting of
            the _Olympic_ games in its 4th and 12th years, _Thucyd._ l. 5; and by three eclipses of
            the sun, and one of the moon, mentioned by _Thucydides_ and _Xenophon_. Now
            _Thucydides_, an unquestionable witness, tells us, that the news of the death of
            _Artaxerxes Longimanus_ was brought to _Ephesus_, and from thence by some _Athenians_ to
            _Athens_, in the 7th year of this _Peloponnesian_ war, when the winter half year was
            running; and therefore he died _An._ 4 _Olymp._ 88, in the end of _An. J.P._ 4289,
            suppose a month or two before midwinter; for so long the news would be in coming. Now
            _Artaxerxes Longimanus_ reigned 40 years, by the consent of _Diodorus_, _Eusebius_,
            _Jerome_, _Sulpitius_; or 41, according to _Ptol. in can. Clem. Alexand._ l. 1. _Strom.
            Chron. Alexandr_. _Abulpharagius_, _Nicephorus_, including therein the reign of his
            successors _Xerxes_ and _Sogdian_, as _Abulpharagius_ informs us. After _Artaxerxes_
            reigned his son _Xerxes_ two months, and _Sogdian_ seven months; but their reign is not
            reckoned apart in summing up the years of the Kings, but is included in the 40 or 41
            years reign of _Artaxerxes_: omit these nine months, and the precise reign of
            _Artaxerxes_ will be thirty nine years and three months. And therefore since his reign
            ended in the beginning of winter _An. J.P._ 4289, it began between midsummer and autumn,
            _An. J.P._ 4250. </p>
          <p id="98010018">
            The same thing I gather also thus. _Cambyses_ began his reign in spring
            _An. J.P._ 4185, and reigned eight years, including the five months of
            _Smerdes_; and then _Darius Hystaspis_ began in spring _An. J.P._ 4193, and
            reigned thirty six years, by the unanimous consent of all Chronologers. The
            reigns of these two Kings are determined by three eclipses of the moon
            observed at _Babylon_, and recorded by _Ptolemy_; so that it cannot be
            disputed. One was in the seventh year of _Cambyses_, _An. J.P._ 4191,
            _Jul._ 16, at 11 at night; another in the 20th year of _Darius_, _An. J.P._
            4212, _Nov._ 19, at 11h. 45' at night; a third in the 31st year of
            _Darius_, _An. J.P._ 4223, _Apr._ 25, at 11h. 30 at night. By these
            eclipses, and the Prophecies of _Haggai_ and _Zechary_ compared together,
            it is manifest that his years began after the 24th day of the 11th _Jewish_
            month, and before the 25th day of _April_, and by consequence about
            _March_. _Xerxes_ therefore began in spring _An. J.P._ 4229: for _Darius_
            died in the fifth year after the battle at _Marathon_, as _Herodotus_,
            _lib._ 7, and _Plutarch_ mention; and that battle was in _October_ _An.
            J.P._ 4224, ten years before the battle at _Salamis_. _Xerxes_ therefore
            began within less than a year after _October_ _An. J.P._ 4228, suppose in
            the spring following: for he spent his first five years, and something
            more, in preparations for his expedition against the _Greeks_; and this
            expedition was in the time of the _Olympic_ games, _An._ 1 _Olymp._ 75,
            _Calliade Athenis Archonte_, 28 years after the _Regifuge_, and Consulship
            of the first Consul _Junius Brutus_, _Anno Urbis conditæ_ 273, _Fabio &amp;
            Furio Coss._ The passage of _Xerxes_'s army over the _Hellespont_ began in
            the end of the fourth year of the 74th _Olympiad_, that is, in _June_ _An.
            J.P._ 4234, and took up one month: and in autumn, three months after, on
            the full moon, the 16th day of the month _Munychion_, was the battle at
            _Salamis_, and a little after that an eclipse of the sun, which by the
            calculation fell on _Octob._ 2. His sixth year therefore began a little
            before _June_, suppose in spring _An. J.P._ 4234, and his first year
            consequently in spring _An. J.P._ 4229, as above. Now he reigned almost
            twenty one years, by the consent of all writers. Add the 7 months of
            _Artabanus_, and the sum will be 21 years and about four or five months,
            which end between midsummer and autumn _An. J.P._ 4250. At this time
            therefore began the reign of his successor _Artaxerxes_, as was to be
            proved.
          </p>
          <p id="98010019">
            The same thing is also confirmed by _Julius Africanus_, who informs us out
            of former writers, that the 20th year of this _Artaxerxes_ was the 115th
            year from the beginning of the reign of _Cyrus_ in _Persia,_ and fell in
            with _An._ 4 _Olymp._ 83. It began therefore with the _Olympic_ year, soon
            after the summer Solstice, _An. J.P._ 4269. Subduct nineteen years, and his
            first year will begin at the same time of the year _An. J.P._ 4250, as
            above.
          </p>
          <p id="98010020">
            His 7th year therefore began after midsummer _An. J.P._ 4256; and the
            Journey of _Ezra_ to _Jerusalem_ in the spring following fell on the
            beginning of _An. J.P._ 4257, as above.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. X.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.10.1">Chap. ix. 24, 25, 26, 27.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.2">_Cut upon_. A phrase in _Hebrew_, taken from the practise of
              numbring by
              cutting notches.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.3">Heb. _to seal_, i.e. to finish or consummate: a metaphor taken from
              sealing what is finished. So the _Jews_ compute, _ad obsignatum Misna, ad obsignatum
              Talmud_, that
              is, _ad absolutum_.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.4">Heb. _the Prophet_, not the Prophecy.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.5">Heb. _the Messiah_, that is, in _Greek_, _the Christ_; in _English_,
              _the
              Anointed_. I use the _English_ word, that the relation of this clause to the former
              may
              appear.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.6">_Jerusalem_.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.7">See _Isa._ xxiii. 13.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.8">Iren. l. 5. Hær. c. 25.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.9">Apud Hieron. in h. l.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.10">1 Kings xi. 7.</note>
            <note id="n.1.10.11">
              <p id="98010021">The antient solar years of the eastern nations consisted of 12 months,
                and every month of 30 days: and hence came the division of a circle into 360
                degrees. This
                year seems to be used by _Moses_ in his history of the Flood, and by _John_ in the
                _Apocalypse_, where a time, times and half a time, 42 months and 1260 days, are put
                equipollent. But in reckoning by many of these years together, an account is to be
                kept of
                the odd days which were added to the end of these years. For the _Egyptians_ added
                five
                days
                to the end of this year; and so did the _Chaldeans_ long before the times of
                _Daniel_, as
                appears by the _Æra_, of _Nabonassar_: and the _Persian_ Magi used the same year of
                365
                days, till the Empire of the _Arabians_. The antient _Greeks_ also used the same
                solar
                year
                of 12 equal months, or 360 days; but every other year added an intercalary month,
                consisting
                of 10 and 11 days alternately.</p>
              <p id="98010022"><br/> The year of the _Jews_, even from their coming out of _Egypt_, was
                Luni-solar. It was solar, for the harvest always followed the Passover, and the
                fruits of the land were always gathered before the feast of Tabernacles, _Levit._
                xxiii. But the months were lunar, for the people were commanded by _Moses_ in the
                beginning of every month to blow with trumpets, and offer burnt offerings with their
                drink offerings, _Num._ x. 10. xxviii. 11, 14. and this solemnity was kept on the
                new moons, _Psal._ lxxxi. 3,4,5. 1 _Chron._ xxiii. 31. These months were called by
                _Moses_ the first, second, third, fourth month, _&amp;c._ and the first month was
                also called _Abib_, the second _Zif_, the seventh _Ethanim_, the eighth _Bull_,
                _Exod._ xiii. 4. 1 _Kings_ vi. 37, 38. viii. 2. But in the _Babylonian_ captivity
                the _Jews_ used the names of the _Chaldean_ months, and by those names understood
                the months of their own year; so that the _Jewish_ months then lost their old names,
                and are now called by those of the _Chaldeans_.</p>
              <p id="98010023"><br/> The _Jews_ began their civil year from the autumnal Equinox, and their
                sacred year from the vernal: and the first day of the first month was on the visible
                new moon, which was nearest the Equinox.</p>
              <p id="98010024"> Whether _Daniel_ used the _Chaldaick_ or _Jewish_ year, is not
                very material; the difference being but six hours in a year, and 4 months in 480
                years.
                But
                I take his months to be _Jewish_: first, because _Daniel_ was a _Jew_, and the
                _Jews_ even
                by the names of the _Chaldean_ months understood the months of their own year:
                secondly,
                because this Prophecy is grounded on _Jeremiah_'s concerning the 70 years captivity,
                and
                therefore must be understood of the same sort of years with the seventy; and those
                are
                _Jewish_, since that Prophecy was given in _Judea_ before the captivity: and lastly,
                because
                _Daniel_ reckons by weeks of years, which is a way of reckoning peculiar to the
                _Jewish_
                years. For as their days ran by sevens, and the last day of every seven was a
                sabbath; so
                their years ran by sevens, and the last year of every seven was a sabbatical year,
                and
                seven
                such weeks of years made a _Jubilee_.</p>
            </note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
