<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="c.1.11" id="98011" type="chapter">
          <head>CHAP. XI.</head>
          <head>Of the Times of the Birth and Passion of _Christ__.</head>
          <p id="98011002">
            The times of the Birth and Passion of _Christ_, with such like niceties,
            being not material to religion, were little regarded by the _Christians_ of
            the first age. They who began first to celebrate them, placed them in the
            cardinal periods of the year; as the annunciation of the Virgin _Mary_, on
            the 25th of _March_, which when _Julius Cæsar_ corrected the Calendar was
            the vernal Equinox; the feast of _John_ Baptist on the 24th of _June_,
            which was the summer Solstice; the feast of St. _Michael_ on _Sept._ 29,
            which was the autumnal Equinox; and the birth of _Christ_ on the winter
            Solstice, _Decemb._ 25, with the feasts of St. _Stephen_, St. _John_ and
            the _Innocents_, as near it as they could place them. And because the
            Solstice in time removed from the 25th of _December_ to the 24th, the 23d,
            the 22d, and so on backwards, hence some in the following centuries placed
            the birth of _Christ_ on _Decemb._ 23, and at length on _Decemb._ 20: and
            for the same reason they seem to have set the feast of St. _Thomas_ on
            _Decemb._ 21, and that of St. _Matthew_ on _Sept._ 21. So also at the
            entrance of the Sun into all the signs in the _Julian_ Calendar, they
            placed the days of other Saints; as the conversion of _Paul_ on _Jan._ 25,
            when the Sun entred [Aquarius]; St. _Matthias_ on _Feb._ 25, when he entred
            [Pisces]; St. _Mark_ on _Apr._ 25, when he entred [Taurus]; _Corpus
            Christi_ on _May_ 26, when he entred [Gemini]; St. _James_ on _July_ 25,
            when he entred [Cancer]; St. _Bartholomew_ on _Aug._ 24, when he entred
            [Virgo]; _Simon_ and _Jude_ on _Octob._ 28, when he entred [Scorpio]: and
            if there were any other remarkable days in the _Julian_ Calendar, they
            placed the Saints upon them, as St. _Barnabas_ on _June_ 11, where _Ovid_
            seems to place the feast of _Vesta_ and _Fortuna_, and the goddess
            _Matuta_; and St. _Philip_ and _James_ on the first of _May_, a day
            dedicated both to the _Bona Dea_, or _Magna Mater_, and to the goddess
            _Flora_, and still celebrated with her rites. All which shews that these
            days were fixed in the first _Christian_ Calendars by Mathematicians at
            pleasure, without any ground in tradition; and that the _Christians_
            afterwards took up with what they found in the Calendars.
          </p>
          <p id="98011003">
            Neither was there any certain tradition about the years of _Christ_. For
            the _Christians_ who first began to enquire into these things, as _Clemens
            Alexandrinus_, _Origen_, _Tertullian_, _Julius Africanus_, _Lactantius_,
            _Jerome_, St. _Austin_, _Sulpicius Severus_, _Prosper_, and as many as
            place the death of _Christ_ in the 15th or 16th year of _Tiberius_, make
            _Christ_ to have preached but one year, or at most but two. At length
            _Eusebius_ discovered four successive Passovers in the Gospel of _John_,
            and thereupon set on foot an opinion that he preacht three years and an
            half; and so died in the 19th year of _Tiberius_. Others afterwards,
            finding the opinion that he died in the Equinox _Mar._ 25, more consonant
            to the times of the _Jewish_ Passover, in the 17th and 20th years, have
            placed his death in one of those two years. Neither is there any greater
            certainty in the opinions about the time of his birth. The first
            _Christians_ placed his baptism near the beginning of the 15th year of
            _Tiberius_; and thence reckoning thirty years backwards, placed his birth
            in the 43d _Julian_ year, the 42d of _Augustus_ and 28th of the _Actiac_
            victory. This was the opinion which obtained in the first ages, till
            _Dionysius Exiguus_, placing the baptism of _Christ_ in the 16th year of
            _Tiberius_, and misinterpreting the text of _Luke_, iii. 23. as if _Jesus_
            was only beginning to be 30 years old when he was baptized, invented the
            vulgar account, in which his birth is placed two years later than before.
            As therefore relating to these things there is no tradition worth
            considering; let us lay aside all and examine what prejudices can be
            gathered from records of good account.
          </p>
          <p id="98011004">
            The fifteenth year of _Tiberius_ began _Aug._ 28, _An. J.P._ 4727. So soon
            as the winter was over, and the weather became warm enough, we may reckon
            that _John_ began to baptize; and that before next winter his fame went
            abroad, and all the people came to his baptism, and _Jesus_ among the rest.
            Whence the first Passover after his baptism mentioned _John_ ii. 13. was in
            the 16th year of _Tiberius_. After this feast _Jesus_ came into the land of
            _Judea_, and staid there baptizing, whilst _John_ was baptizing in _Ænon_,
            _John_ iii. 22, 23. But when he heard that _John_ was cast into prison, he
            departed into _Galilee_, _Mat._ iii. 12. being afraid, because the
            Pharisees had heard that he baptized more disciples than _John_, _John_ iv.
            1. and in his journey he passed thro' _Samaria_ four months before the
            harvest, _John_ iv. 35. that is, about the time of the winter Solstice. For
            their harvest was between _Easter_ and _Whitsunday_, and began about a
            month after the vernal Equinox. _Say not ye_, saith he, _there are yet four
            months, and then cometh harvest? Behold I say unto you, lift up your eyes,
            and look on the fields, for they are white already to harvest_; meaning,
            that the people in the fields were ready for the Gospel, as his next words
            shew[1]. _John_ therefore was imprisoned about _November_, in the 17th year
            of _Tiberius_; and _Christ_ thereupon went from _Judea_ to _Cana_ of
            _Galilee_ in _December_, and was received there of the _Galileans_, who had
            seen all he did at _Jerusalem_ at the Passover: and when a Nobleman of
            _Capernaum_ heard he was returned into _Galilee_, and went to him and
            desired him to come and cure his son, he went not thither yet, but only
            said, _Go thy way, thy son liveth; and the Nobleman returned and found it
            so, and believed, he and his house_, John iv. This is the beginning of his
            miracles in _Galilee_; and thus far _John_ is full and distinct in relating
            the actions of his first year, omitted by the other Evangelists. The rest
            of his history is from this time related more fully by the other
            Evangelists than by _John_; for what they relate he omits.
          </p>
          <p id="98011005">
            From this time therefore _Jesus_ taught in the Synagogues of _Galilee_ on
            the sabbath-days, being glorified of all: and coming to his own city
            _Nazareth_, and preaching in their Synagogue, they were offended, and
            thrust him out of the city, and led him to the brow of the hill on which
            the city was built to cast him headlong; but he passing thro' the midst of
            them, went his way, and came and dwelt at _Capernaum_, _Luke_ iv. And by
            this time we may reckon the second Passover was either past or at hand.
          </p>
          <p id="98011006">
            All this time _Matthew_ passeth over in few words, and here begins to
            relate the preaching and miracles of _Christ_. _When _Jesus__, saith he,
            _had heard that _John_ was cast into prison, he departed into _Galilee_;
            and leaving _Nazareth_, he came and dwelt at _Capernaum_, and from that
            time began to preach and say, Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at
            hand_, Matth. iv. 12. Afterwards he called his disciples _Peter_, _Andrew_,
            _James_ and _John_; and then _went about all_ Galilee, _teaching in the
            Synagogues,--and healing all manner of sickness:--and his fame went
            thro'out all _Syria_; and they brought unto him all sick people,--and there
            followed him great multitudes of people from _Galilee_, and from
            _Decapolis_, and from _Jerusalem_, and from _Judea_, and from beyond
            _Jordan__, Matth, iv. 18, 25. All this was done before the sermon in the
            mount: and therefore we may certainly reckon that the second Passover was
            past before the preaching of that sermon. The multitudes that followed him
            from _Jerusalem_ and _Judea_, shew that he had lately been there at the
            feast. The sermon in the mount was made when great multitudes came to him
            from all places, and followed him in the open fields; which is an argument
            of the summer-season: and in this sermon he pointed at the lilies of the
            field then in the flower before the eyes of his auditors. _Consider_, saith
            he, _the lilies of the field, how they grow; they toil not, neither do they
            spin; and yet _Solomon_ in all his glory was not arayed like one of these.
            Wherefore if God so clothe the grass of the field, which to day is and to
            morrow is cast into the oven_, &amp;c. _Matth._ vi. 28. So therefore the grass
            of the field was now in the flower, and by consequence the month of _March_
            with the Passover was past.
          </p>
          <p id="98011007">
            Let us see therefore how the rest of the feasts follow in order in
            _Matthew_'s Gospel: for he was an eye-witness of what he relates, and so
            tells all things in due order of time, which _Mark_ and _Luke_ do not.
          </p>
          <p id="98011008">
            Some time after the sermon in the mount, when the time came that he should
            be received, that is, when the time of a feast came that he should be
            received by the _Jews_, he set his face to go to _Jerusalem_: and as he
            went with his disciples in the way, when the _Samaritans_ in his passage
            thro' _Samaria_ had denied him lodgings, and a certain Scribe said unto
            him, _Master, I will follow thee whithersoever thou goest_, Jesus _said
            unto him, The foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests, but
            the Son of man hath not where to lay his head_, Matth. viii. 19. Luke ix.
            51, 57. The Scribe told _Christ_ he would bear him company in his journey,
            and _Christ_ replied that he wanted a lodging. Now this feast I take to be
            the feast of Tabernacles, because soon after I find _Christ_ and his
            Apostles on the sea of _Tiberias_ in a storm so great, that the ship was
            covered with water and in danger of sinking, till _Christ rebuked the winds
            and the sea_, Matth. viii. 23. For this storm shews that winter was now
            come on.
          </p>
          <p id="98011009">
            After this _Christ_ did many miracles, and _went about all the cities and
            villages of _Galilee_, teaching in their Synagogues, and preaching the
            gospel of the kingdom, and healing every sickness, and every disease among
            the people_, Matth. ix. he then sent forth the twelve to do the like,
            _Matth._ x. and at length when he had received a message from _John_, and
            answered it, he said to the multitudes, _From the days of _John_ the
            Baptist until now the kingdom of heaven suffereth violence_; and upbraided
            the cities, _Chorazin_, _Bethsaida_, and _Capernaum_, wherein most of his
            mighty works were done, because they repented not, _Matth._ xi. Which
            several passages shew, that from the imprisonment of _John_ till now there
            had been a considerable length of time: the winter was now past, and the
            next Passover was at hand; for immediately after this, _Matthew_, in chap.
            xii. subjoins, that _Jesus went on the sabbath-day thro' the corn, and his
            disciples were an hungred, and began to pluck the ears of corn and to
            eat,--rubbing them_, saith _Luke_, _in their hands_: the corn therefore was
            not only in the ear, but ripe; and consequently the Passover, in which the
            first-fruits were always offered before the harvest, was now come or past.
            _Luke_ calls this sabbath [Greek: deuteroprôton], the second prime sabbath,
            that is, the second of the two great feasts of the Passover. As we call
            _Easter_ day high _Easter_, and its _octave_ low _Easter_ or _Lowsunday_:
            so _Luke_ calls the feast on the seventh day of the unlevened bread, the
            second of the two prime sabbaths.
          </p>
          <p id="98011010">
            In one of the sabbaths following he went into a Synagogue, and healed a man
            with a withered hand, _Matth._ xii. 9. _Luke_ vi. 6. And when the Pharisees
            took counsel to destroy him, _he withdrew himself from thence, and great
            multitudes followed him; and he healed them all, and charged them that they
            should not make him known_, Matth. xii. 14. Afterwards being in a ship, and
            the multitude standing on the shore, he spake to them three parables
            together, taken from the seeds-men sowing the fields, _Matth._ xiii. by
            which we may know that it was now seed-time, and by consequence that the
            feast of Tabernacles was past. After this he went _into his own country,
            and taught them in their Synagogue_, but _did not many mighty works there
            because of their unbelief_. Then the twelve having been abroad a year,
            returned, and told _Jesus_ all that they had done: and at the same time
            _Herod_ beheaded _John_ in prison, and his disciples came and told _Jesus_;
            and when _Jesus_ heard it, he took the twelve and departed thence privately
            by ship into a desert place belonging to _Bethsaida_: and the people when
            they knew it, followed him on foot out of the cities, the winter being now
            past; and he healed their sick, and in the desert fed them to the number of
            five thousand men, besides women and children, with only five loaves and
            two fishes, _Matth._ xiv. _Luke_ ix. at the doing of which miracle the
            Passover of the _Jews_ was nigh, _John_ vi. 4. But _Jesus_ went not up to
            this feast; but _after these things walked in _Galilee_, because the
            _Jews__ at the Passover before had taken counsel to destroy him, and still
            _sought to kill him_, John vii. i. Henceforward therefore he is found first
            in the coast of _Tyre_ and _Sidon_, then by the sea of _Galilee_,
            afterwards in the coast of _Cæsarea Philippi_; and lastly at _Capernaum_,
            _Matth._ xv. 21, 29. xvi. 13. xvii. 34.
          </p>
          <p id="98011011">
            Afterwards when the feast of Tabernacles was at hand, his brethren
            upbraided him for walking secretly, and urged him to go up to the feast.
            But he went not till they were gone, and then went up privately, _John_
            vii. 2. and when the _Jews_ sought to stone him, he escaped, _John_ viii.
            59. After this he was at the feast of the Dedication in winter, _John_ x.
            22. and when they sought again to take him, he fled beyond _Jordan_, _John_
            x. 39, 40. _Matth_. xix. 1. where he stayed till the death of _Lazarus_,
            and then came to _Bethany_ near _Jerusalem_, and raised him, _John_ xi. 7,
            18. whereupon the _Jews_ took counsel from that time to kill him: and
            _therefore_ he _walked no more openly among the _Jews_, but went thence
            into a country near to the wilderness, into a city called _Ephraim_; and
            there continued with his disciples_ till the last Passover, in which the
            _Jews_ put him to death, _John_ xi. 53, 54.
          </p>
          <p id="98011012">
            Thus have we, in the Gospels of _Matthew_ and _John_ compared together, the
            history of _Christ_'s actions in continual order during five Passovers.
            _John_ is more distinct in the beginning and end; _Matthew_ in the middle:
            what either omits, the other supplies. The first Passover was between the
            baptism of _Christ_ and the imprisonment of _John, John_ ii. 13. the second
            within four months after the imprisonment of _John_, and _Christ_'s
            beginning to preach in _Galilee_, _John_ iv. 35. and therefore it was
            either that feast to which _Jesus_ went up, when the Scribe desired to
            follow him, _Matth._ viii. 19. _Luke_ ix. 51, 57. or the feast before it.
            The third was the next feast after it, when the corn was eared and ripe,
            _Matth_, xii. 1. _Luke_ vi. 1. The fourth was that which was nigh at hand
            when _Christ_ wrought the miracle of the five loaves, _Matth_. xiv. 15.
            _John_ vi. 4, 5. and the fifth was that in which _Christ_ suffered,
            _Matth._ xx. 17. _John_ xii. 1.
          </p>
          <p id="98011013">
            Between the first and second Passover _John_ and _Christ_ baptized
            together, till the imprisonment of _John_, which was four months before the
            second. Then _Christ_ began to preach, and call his disciples; and after he
            had instructed them a year, lent them to preach in the cities of the
            _Jews_: at the same time _John_ hearing of the fame of _Christ_, sent to
            him to know who he was. At the third, the chief Priests began to consult
            about the death of _Christ_. A little before the fourth, the twelve after
            they had preached a year in all the cities, returned to _Christ_; and at
            the same time _Herod_ beheaded _John_ in prison, after he had been in
            prison two years and a quarter: and thereupon _Christ_ fled into the desart
            for fear of _Herod_. The fourth _Christ_ went not up to _Jerusalem_ for
            fear of the _Jews_, who at the Passover before had consulted his death, and
            because his time was not yet come. Thenceforward therefore till the feast
            of Tabernacles he walked in _Galilee_, and that secretly for fear of
            _Herod_: and after the feast of Tabernacles he returned no more into
            _Galilee_, but sometimes was at _Jerusalem_, and sometimes retired beyond
            _Jordan_, or to the city _Ephraim_ by the wilderness, till the Passover in
            which he was betrayed, apprehended, and crucified.
          </p>
          <p id="98011014">
            _John_ therefore baptized two summers, and _Christ_ preached three. The
            first summer _John_ preached to make himself known, in order to give
            testimony to _Christ_. Then, after _Christ_ came to his baptism and was
            made known to him, he baptized another summer, to make _Christ_ known by
            his testimony; and _Christ_ also baptized the same summer, to make himself
            the more known: and by reason of _John_'s testimony there came more to
            _Christ_'s baptism than to _John_'s. The winter following _John_ was
            imprisoned; and now his course being at an end, _Christ_ entered upon his
            proper office of preaching in the cities. In the beginning of his preaching
            he completed the number of the twelve Apostles, and instructed them all the
            first year in order to send them abroad. Before the end of this year, his
            fame by his preaching and miracles was so far spread abroad, that the
            _Jews_ at the Passover following consulted how to kill him. In the second
            year of his preaching, it being no longer safe for him to converse openly
            in _Judea_, he sent the twelve to preach in all their cities: and in the
            end of the year they returned to him, and told him all they had done. All
            the last year the twelve continued with him to be instructed more
            perfectly, in order to their preaching to all nations after his death. And
            upon the news of _John_'s death, being afraid of _Herod_ as well as of the
            _Jews_, he walked this year more secretly than before; frequenting desarts,
            and spending the last half of the year in _Judea_, without the dominions of
            _Herod_.
          </p>
          <p id="98011015">
            Thus have we in the Gospels of _Matthew_ and _John_ all things told in due
            order, from the beginning of _John_'s preaching to the death of _Christ_,
            and the years distinguished from one another by such essential characters
            that they cannot be mistaken. The second Passover is distinguished from the
            first, by the interposition of _John_'s imprisonment. The third is
            distinguished from the second, by a double character: first, by the
            interposition of the feast to which _Christ_ went up, _Mat._ viii. 19.
            _Luke_ ix. 57. and secondly, by the distance of time from the beginning of
            _Christ_'s preaching: for the second was in the beginning of his preaching,
            and the third so long after, that before it came _Christ_ said, _from the
            days of _John_ the Baptist until now_, &amp;c. and upbraided the cities of
            _Galilee_ for their not repenting at his preaching, and mighty works done
            in all that time. The fourth is distinguished from the third, by the
            mission of the twelve from _Christ_ to preach in the cities of _Judea_ in
            all the interval. The fifth is distinguished from all the former by the
            twelve's being returned from preaching, and continuing with _Christ_ during
            all the interval, between the fourth and fifth, and by the passion and
            other infallible characters.
          </p>
          <p id="98011016">
            Now since the first summer of _John_'s baptizing fell in the fifteenth year
            of the Emperor _Tiberius_, and by consequence the first of these five
            Passovers in his sixteenth year; the last of them, in which _Jesus_
            suffered, will fall on the twentieth year of the same Emperor; and by
            consequence in the Consulship of _Fabius_ and _Vitellius_, in the 79th
            _Julian_ year, and year of _Christ_ 34, which was the sabbatical year of
            the _Jews_. And that it did so, I further confirm by these arguments.
          </p>
          <p id="98011017">
            I take it for granted that the passion was on friday the 14th day of the
            month _Nisan_, the great feast of the Passover on saturday the 15th day of
            _Nisan_, and the resurrection on the day following. Now the 14th day of
            _Nisan_ always fell on the full moon next after the vernal Equinox; and the
            month began at the new moon before, not at the true conjunction, but at the
            first appearance of the new moon: for the _Jews_ referred all the time of
            the silent moon, as they phrased it, that is, of the moon's disappearing,
            to the old moon; and because the first appearance might usually be about 18
            hours after the true conjunction, they therefore began their month from the
            sixth hour at evening, that is, at sun set, next after the eighteenth hour
            from the conjunction. And this rule they called [Hebrew: YH] _Jah_,
            designing by the letters [Hebrew: Y] and [Hebrew: H] the number 18.
          </p>
          <p id="98011018">
            I know that _Epiphanius_ tells us, if some interpret his words rightly,
            that the _Jews_ used a vicious cycle, and thereby anticipated the legal new
            moons by two days. But this surely he spake not as a witness, for he
            neither understood _Astronomy_ nor _Rabbinical_ learning, but as arguing
            from his erroneous hypothesis about the time of the passion. For the _Jews_
            did not anticipate, but postpone their months: they thought it lawful to
            begin their months a day later than the first appearance of the new moon,
            because the new moon continued for more days than one; but not a day
            sooner, lest they should celebrate the new moon before there was any. And
            the _Jews_ still keep a tradition in their books, that the _Sanhedrim_ used
            diligently to define the new moons by sight: sending witnesses into
            mountainous places, and examining them about the moon's appearing, and
            translating the new moon from the day they had agreed on to the day before,
            as often as witnesses came from distant regions, who had seen it a day
            sooner than it was seen at _Jerusalem_. Accordingly _Josephus_, one of the
            _Jewish_ Priests who ministred in the temple, tells us [2] that the
            Passover was kept _on the 14th day of_ Nisan, [Greek: kata selênên]
            _according to the moon, when the sun was in _Aries__. This is confirmed
            also by two instances, recorded by him, which totally overthrow the
            hypothesis of the _Jews_ using a vicious cycle. For that year in which
            _Jerusalem_ was taken and destroyed, he saith, the Passover was on the 14th
            day of the month _Xanticus_, which according to _Josephus_ is our _April_;
            and that five years before, it fell on the 8th day of the same month. Which
            two instances agree with the course of the moon.
          </p>
          <p id="98011019">
            Computing therefore the new moons of the first month according to the
            course of the moon and the rule _Jah_, and thence counting 14 days, I find
            that the 14th day of this month in the year of _Christ_ 31, fell on tuesday
            _March_ 27; in the year 32, on sunday _Apr._ 13; in the year 33, on friday
            _Apr._ 3; in the year 34, on wednesday _March_ 24, or rather, for avoiding
            the Equinox which fell on the same day, and for having a fitter time for
            harvest, on thursday _Apr._ 22. also in the year 35, on tuesday _Apr._ 12.
            and in the year 36, on saturday _March_ 31.
          </p>
          <p id="98011020">
            But because the 15th and 21st days of _Nisan_, and a day or two of
            _Pentecost_, and the 10th, 15th, and 22d of _Tisri_, were always sabbatical
            days or days of rest, and it was inconvenient on two sabbaths together to
            be prohibited burying their dead and making ready fresh meat, for in that
            hot region their meat would be apt in two days to corrupt: to avoid these
            and such like inconveniences, the _Jews_ postponed their months a day, as
            often as the first day of the month _Tisri_, or, which is all one, the
            third of the month _Nisan_, was sunday, wednesday or friday: and this rule
            they called [Hebrew: 'DW] _Adu_, by the letters [Hebrew: W , D , ']
            signifying the numbers 1, 4, 6; that is, the 1st, 4th, and 6th days of the
            week; which days we call sunday, wednesday and friday. Postponing therefore
            by this rule the months found above; the 14th day of the month _Nisan_ will
            fall in the year of _Christ_ 31, on wednesday _March_ 28; in the year 32,
            on monday _Apr._ 14; in the year 33, on friday _Apr._ 3; in the year 34, on
            friday _Apr._ 23; in the year 35, on wednesday _Apr._ 13, and in the year
            36, on saturday _March_ 31.
          </p>
          <p id="98011021">
            By this computation therefore the year 32 is absolutely excluded, because
            the Passion cannot fall on friday without making it five days after the
            full moon, or two days before it; whereas it ought to be upon the day of
            the full moon, or the next day. For the same reason the years 31 and 35 are
            excluded, because in them the Passion cannot fall on friday, without making
            it three days after the full moon, or four days before it: errors so
            enormous, that they would be very conspicuous in the heavens to every
            vulgar eye. The year 36 is contended for by few or none, and both this and
            the year 35 may be thus excluded.
          </p>
          <p id="98011022">
            _Tiberius_ in the beginning of his reign made _Valerius Gratus_ President
            of _Judea_; and after 11 years, substituted _Pontius Pilate_, who governed
            10 years. Then _Vitellius_, newly made President of _Syria_, deprived him
            of his honour, substituting _Marcellus_, and at length sent him to _Rome_:
            but, by reason of delays, _Tiberius_ died before _Pilate_ got thither. In
            the mean time _Vitellius_, after he had deposed _Pilate_, came to
            _Jerusalem_ in the time of the Passover, to visit that Province as well as
            others in the beginning of his office; and in the place of _Caiaphas_, then
            High Priest, created _Jonathas_ the son of _Ananus_, or _Annas_ as he is
            called in scripture. Afterwards, when _Vitellius_ was returned to
            _Antioch_, he received letters from _Tiberius_, to make peace with
            _Artabanus_ king of the _Parthians_. At the same time the _Alans_, by the
            sollicitation of _Tiberius_, invaded the kingdom of _Artabanus_; and his
            subjects also, by the procurement of _Vitellius_, soon after rebelled: for
            _Tiberius_ thought that _Artabanus_, thus pressed with difficulties, would
            more readily accept the conditions of peace. _Artabanus_ therefore
            straightway gathering a greater army, opprest the rebels; and then meeting
            _Vitellius_ at _Euphrates_, made a league with the _Romans_. After this
            _Tiberius_ commanded _Vitellius_ to make war upon _Aretas_ King of
            _Arabia_. He therefore leading his army against _Aretas_, went together
            with _Herod_ to _Jerusalem_, to sacrifice at the publick feast which was
            then to be celebrated. Where being received honourably, he stayed three
            days, and in the mean while translated the high Priesthood from _Jonathas_
            to his brother _Theophilus_: and the fourth day, receiving letters of the
            death of _Tiberius_, made the people swear allegiance to _Caius_ the new
            Emperor; and recalling his army, sent them into quarters. All this is
            related by _Josephus_ _Antiq._ _lib._ 18. _c._ 6, 7. Now _Tiberius_ reigned
            22 years and 7 months, and died _March_ 16, in the beginning of the year of
            _Christ_ 37; and the feast of the Passover fell on _April_ 20 following,
            that is, 35 days after the death of _Tiberius_: so that there were about 36
            or 38 days, for the news of his death to come from _Rome_ to _Vitellius_ at
            _Jerusalem_; which being a convenient time for that message, confirms that
            the feast which _Vitellius_ and _Herod_ now went up to was the Passover.
            For had it been the Pentecost, as is usually supposed, _Vitellius_ would
            have continued three months ignorant of the Emperor's death: which is not
            to be supposed. However, the things done between this feast and the
            Passover which _Vitellius_ was at before, namely, the stirring up a
            sedition in _Parthia_, the quieting that sedition, the making a league
            after that with the _Parthians_, the sending news of that league to _Rome_,
            the receiving new orders from thence to go against the _Arabians_, and the
            putting those orders in execution; required much more time than the fifty
            days between the Passover and Pentecost of the same year: and therefore the
            Passover which _Vitellius_ first went up to, was in the year before.
            Therefore _Pilate_ was deposed before the Passover A.C. 36, and by
            consequence the passion of _Christ_ was before that Passover: for he
            suffered not under _Vitellius_, nor under _Vitellius_ and _Pilate_
            together, but under _Pilate_ alone.
          </p>
          <p id="98011023">
            Now it is observable that the high Priesthood was at this time become an
            annual office, and the Passover was the time of making a new high Priest.
            For _Gratus_ the predecessor of _Pilate_, saith _Josephus_, made _Ismael_
            high Priest after _Ananus_; and a while after, suppose a year, deposed him,
            and substituted _Eleazar_, and a year after _Simon_, and after another year
            _Caiaphas_; and then gave way to _Pilate_. So _Vitellius_ at one Passover
            made _Jonathas_ successor to _Caiaphas_, and at the next _Theophilus_ to
            _Jonathas_. Hence _Luke_ tells us, that in the 15th year of _Tiberius_,
            _Annas_ and _Caiaphas_ were high Priests, that is, _Annas_ till the
            Passover, and _Caiaphas_ afterwards. Accordingly _John_ speaks of the high
            Priesthood as an annual office: for he tells us again and again, in the
            last year of _Christ_'s preaching, that _Caiaphas_ was high Priest for that
            year, _John_ xi. 49, 51. xviii. 13. And the next year _Luke_ tells you,
            that _Annas_ was high Priest, _Acts_ iv. 6. _Theophilus_ was therefore made
            high Priest in the first year of _Caius_, _Jonathas_ in the 22d year of
            _Tiberius_, and _Caiaphas_ in the 21st year of the same Emperor: and
            therefore, allotting a year to each, the Passion, when _Annas_ succeeded
            _Caiaphas_, could not be later than the 20th year of _Tiberius_, A.C. 34.
          </p>
          <p id="98011024">
            Thus there remain only the years 33 and 34 to be considered; and the year
            33 I exclude by this argument. In the Passover two years before the
            Passion, when _Christ_ went thro' the corn, and his disciples pluckt the
            ears, and rubbed them with their hands to eat; this ripeness of the corn
            shews that the Passover then fell late: and so did the Passover A.C. 32,
            _April 14_, but the Passover A.C. 31, _March 28th_, fell very early. It was
            not therefore two years after the year 31, but two years after 32 that
            _Christ_ suffered.
          </p>
          <p id="98011025">
            Thus all the characters of the Passion agree to the year 34; and that is
            the only year to which they all agree.
          </p>
          <noteGrp>
            <desc>Notes to Chap. XI.</desc>
            <note id="n.1.11.1">I observe, that _Christ_ and his forerunner _John_ in their
              parabolical
              discourses were wont to allude to things present. The old Prophets, when
              they would describe things emphatically, did not only draw parables from
              things which offered themselves, as from the rent of a garment, 1 _Sam._
              xv. from the sabbatic year, _Isa._ xxxvii. from the vessels of a Potter,
              _Jer._ xviii, &amp;c. but also when such fit objects were wanting, they
              supplied them by their own actions, as by rending a garment, 1 _Kings_ xi.
              by shooting, 2 _Kings_ xiii. by making bare their body, _Isa._ xx. by
              imposing significant names to their sons, _Isa._ viii. _Hos._ i. by hiding
              a girdle in the bank of _Euphrates_, _Jer._ xiii. by breaking a potter's
              vessel, _Jer._ xix. by putting on fetters and yokes, _Jer._ xxvii. by
              binding a book to a stone, and casting them both into _Euphrates_, _Jer._
              li. by besieging a painted city, _Ezek._ iv. by dividing hair into three
              parts, _Ezek._ v. by making a chain, _Ezek._ vii. by carrying out houshold
              stuff like a captive and trembling, _Ezek._ xii, &amp;c. By such kind of types
              the Prophets loved to speak. And _Christ_ being endued with a nobler
              prophetic spirit than the rest, excelled also in this kind of speaking, yet
              so as not to speak by his own actions, that was less grave and decent, but
              to turn into parables such things as offered themselves. On occasion of the
              harvest approaching, he admonishes his disciples once and again of the
              spiritual harvest, _John_ iv. 35. _Matth._ ix. 37. Seeing the lilies of the
              field, he admonishes his disciples about gay clothing, _Matth._ vi. 28. In
              allusion to the present season of fruits, he admonishes his disciples about
              knowing men by their fruits, _Matth._ vii. 16. In the time of the Passover,
              when trees put forth leaves, he bids his disciples _learn a parable from
              the fig tree: when its branch is yet tender and putteth forth leaves, ye
              know that summer is nigh_, &amp;c. _Matth._ xxiv. 32. _Luke_ xxi. 29. The same
              day, alluding both to the season of the year and to his passion, which was
              to be two days after, he formed a parable of the time of fruits
              approaching, and the murdering of the heir, _Matth._ xxi. 33. Alluding at
              the same time, both to the money-changers whom he had newly driven out of
              the Temple, and to his passion at hand; he made a parable of a Noble-man
              going into a far country to receive a kingdom and return, and delivering
              his goods to his servants, and at his return condemning the slothful
              servant because he put not his money to the exchangers, _Matth._ xxv. 14.
              _Luke_ xix. 12. Being near the Temple where sheep were kept in folds to be
              sold for the sacrifices, he spake many things parabolically of sheep, of
              the shepherd, and of the door of the sheepfold; and discovers that he
              alluded to the sheepfolds which were to be hired in the market-place, by
              speaking of such folds as a thief could not enter by the door, nor the
              shepherd himself open, but a porter opened to the shepherd, _John_ x. 1, 3.
              Being in the mount of _Olives_, _Matth._ xxxvi. 30. _John_ xiv. 31. a place
              so fertile that it could not want vines, he spake many things mystically of
              the Husbandman, and of the vine and its branches, _John_ xv. Meeting a
              blind man, he admonished of spiritual blindness, _John_ ix. 39. At the
              sight of little children, he described once and again the innocence of the
              elect, _Matth._ xviii. 2. xix. 13. Knowing that _Lazarus_ was dead and
              should be raised again, he discoursed of the resurrection and life eternal,
              _John_ xi. 25, 26. Hearing of the slaughter of some whom _Pilate_ had
              slain, he admonished of eternal death, _Luke_ xiii. 1. To his fishermen he
              spake of fishers of men, _Matth._ iv. 10. and composed another parable
              about fishes. _Matth._ xiii. 47. Being by the Temple, he spake of the
              Temple of his body, _John_ ii. 19. At supper he spake a parable about the
              mystical supper to come in the kingdom of heaven, _Luke_ xiv. On occasion
              of temporal food, he admonished his disciples of spiritual food, and of
              eating his flesh and drinking his blood mystically, _John_ vi. 27, 53. When
              his disciples wanted bread, he bad them beware of the leven of the
              Pharisees, _Matth._ xvi. 6. Being desired to eat, he answered that he had
              other meat, _John_ iv. 31. In the great day of the feast of Tabernacles,
              when the _Jews_, as their custom was, brought a great quantity of waters
              from the river _Shiloah_ into the Temple, _Christ_ stood and cried, saying,
              _If any man thirst let him come unto me and drink. He that believeth in me,
              out of his belly shall flow rivers of living water_, John vii. 37. The next
              day, in allusion to the servants who by reason of the sabbatical year were
              newly set free, he said, _If ye continue in my word, the truth shall make
              you free_. Which the _Jews_ understanding literally with respect to the
              present manumission of servants, answered, _We be _Abraham_'s seed, and
              were never in bondage to any man: how sayeth thou, ye shall be made free?_
              John viii. They assert their freedom by a double argument: first, because
              they were the seed of _Abraham_, and therefore newly made free, had they
              been ever in bondage; and then, because they never were in bondage. In the
              last Passover, when _Herod_ led his army thro' _Judea_ against _Aretas_
              King of _Arabia_, because _Aretas_ was aggressor and the stronger in
              military forces, as appeared by the event; _Christ_ alluding to that state
              of things, composed the parable of a weaker King leading his army against a
              stronger who made war upon him, _Luke_ xiv. 31. And I doubt not but divers
              other parables were formed upon other occasions, the history of which we
              have not.</note>
            <note id="n.1.11.2">Joseph. Antiq. lib. 3. c. 10.</note>
          </noteGrp>
        </div>
        
